<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>mac on Neil Grogan</title>
    <link>/tags/mac/</link>
    <description>Recent content in mac on Neil Grogan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/mac/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Mac Mini Server</title>
      <link>/macmini/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/macmini/</guid>
      <description>I recently purchased a Mac Mini Server, for this site to run on. It&amp;rsquo;s hosted on my home broadband connection, but it&amp;rsquo;s just really for small time side-projects like this site. Also it&amp;rsquo;s a way to play around with Docker, VirtualBox, Node.js and all those other fun technologies I don&amp;rsquo;t get time for.
I don&amp;rsquo;t really plan to post links, but maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll review things or cover things I&amp;rsquo;ve bought.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s in your dock?</title>
      <link>/whats-in-your-dock/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/whats-in-your-dock/</guid>
      <description>I recently read an article that posed the question &amp;ldquo;Does your dock reflect your priorities?&amp;rdquo; - which is an interesting question. Further breaking that idea down leads to:
 What apps do I need the most? What apps should be next (or be higher priority)?  iPhone dock  Phone app: pretty self explanatory Safari: Still the best mobile browser I think (though if Google ever gets going on a proper Chrome browser for Android that may change) Tweetbot: I like Twitter the most of the social networks and tweetbot is the Swiss army knife if twitter clients Music (aka.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apple Mac OS X: the most popular Desktop Unix?</title>
      <link>/apple-mac-os-x-most-popular-desktop/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Oct 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/apple-mac-os-x-most-popular-desktop/</guid>
      <description>Apple does it again: explosive growth in the computer market, no doubt in part to its Macbook/Macbook Pro line of laptops. As Ars Technica points out:
 As predicted last quarter, however, Apple broke its tie for third place with Gateway by shipping 1.33 million units and growing by a whopping 37.2 percent (double that of any other US vendor) from third quarter 2006 to claim 8.1 percent of the US market for the quarter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leopard - Worth the wait?</title>
      <link>/leopard-worth-wait/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jun 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/leopard-worth-wait/</guid>
      <description>If you haven&amp;rsquo;t heard of Apple&amp;rsquo;s latest Operating system, have a look at Wikipedia Article on Mac OS X Leopard. Here are some of the features:
 Time Machine: an automated backup utility which allows the user to restore files that have been deleted or replaced by another version of a file. Front Row currently only available with the purchase of a new Mac, but will be included with Leopard. It has been reworked to closely resemble the interface used by the Apple TV.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Broken Macbook Update Part II</title>
      <link>/broken-macbook-update-part-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/broken-macbook-update-part-ii/</guid>
      <description>Looks like Mactivate got it wrong, it wasn&amp;rsquo;t the heatsink, as referred to by my earlier post. Looks like I have seen good advice from the Web, never buy a first generation Apple product, until they work out the kinks! I guess Mactivate have been snowed under with heatsink problems, that they never bothered to check other parts of my Macbook, since it is such a common problem.They have ordered me a new &amp;ldquo;logic board&amp;rdquo; (I am guessing the PMU like I thought it was ;-) ).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Macbook Issue Identified</title>
      <link>/macbook-issue-identified/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/macbook-issue-identified/</guid>
      <description>Turns out my prediction wasn&amp;rsquo;t quite correct, it was not the Power Management Unit (PMU), it was the heatsink. Mactivate have informed me they have one on order from Apple, so it will take a bit longer than I anticipated to get my Macbook back. I found this strange as I had not experienced random shutdowns like the ones that have been widely reported across the web. it was like I described in my earlier post, something to do with the battery not being able to charge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Macbook Update, Fonero Haven, Commercial Darknet and College!</title>
      <link>/macbook-update-fonero-haven-commercial/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/macbook-update-fonero-haven-commercial/</guid>
      <description>I have ordered and I am expecting delivery of my brand new Apple MacBook (or BlackBook as some call it)! It will be a Black, 2Ghz Core Duo, 1 GB RAM, 120 GB HDD (5400 RPM) MacBook, complete with a remote, Bluetooth 2 and Wifi functionality. Not mention cool applications such as iSight built in Camera, Front Row ( a media center) and Spotlight search technology. It cost me close to €2.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>