<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>security on Neil Grogan</title><link>/tags/security/</link><description>Recent content in security on Neil Grogan</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/security/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The year of self hosting</title><link>/self-host/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/self-host/</guid><description>Over the last month or so, I’ve come to embrace my home server setup and how powerful it can be. Here I have this small little Intel NUC Server, for which I promised myself I would do lots of cool and interesting things with.
The first thing I’ve hosted is Plex. I’ve used Docker Compose to bring up a Plex Docker container, with:
Filebot (to tag video files) Beets (to tag audio files) Transmission (to download files) Webhook (receives incoming web requests) The way it works is this:</description></item><item><title>Have you got viruses or spyware? Here's my tips!</title><link>/have-you-got-viruses-or-spyware-heres/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/have-you-got-viruses-or-spyware-heres/</guid><description>I come into contact everyday with people asking how to fix their machines due to the inevitable spyware and viruses found on a Windows machine. Lately I have been switching people to Ubuntu, and even getting them to buy machines to install it on (Dell). But I understand and have no zealotry for Linux when it comes to fixing peoples&amp;rsquo; real world problems. I always mention Ubuntu as a matter of course, and also Macs.</description></item><item><title>Wireless, New Design and Web Services</title><link>/wireless-new-design-and-web-services/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/wireless-new-design-and-web-services/</guid><description>Welcome to the new and improved Duey Finsters. As I mentioned before, I hope to receive a Nokia 770 Internet Tablet soon, so I will be checking the free wireless services offered by Eircom in Dublin and at McDonalds restaurants.
You may have noticed the new look and this revamped blog. You may also question where has Duey Finsters Web Services gone? It is still here, but me and Thomas Whelan, who run it, cannot decide on a name.</description></item></channel></rss>