<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Security on Neil Grogan</title>
    <link>/tags/security/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Security on Neil Grogan</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/security/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The year of self hosting</title>
      <link>/self-host/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/self-host/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the last month or so, I’ve come to embrace my home server setup and how powerful it can be. Here I have this small little &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Next_Unit_of_Computing&#34;&gt;Intel NUC Server&lt;/a&gt;, for which I promised myself I would do lots of cool and interesting things with.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The first thing I’ve hosted is &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.plex.tv&#34;&gt;Plex&lt;/a&gt;. I’ve used &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.docker.com/compose/&#34;&gt;Docker Compose&lt;/a&gt; to bring up a Plex Docker container, with:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.filebot.net/&#34;&gt;Filebot&lt;/a&gt; (to tag video files)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://beets.io/&#34;&gt;Beets&lt;/a&gt; (to tag audio files)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://transmissionbt.com/&#34;&gt;Transmission&lt;/a&gt; (to download files)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://hub.docker.com/r/almir/webhook/&#34;&gt;Webhook&lt;/a&gt; (receives incoming web requests)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The way it works is this:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Irish SOPA Law: An Overview</title>
      <link>/irish-sopa-law-an-overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/irish-sopa-law-an-overview/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../files/2012/01/sopa.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Irish SOPA Illustration&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nuke support in UK hits record high</title>
      <link>/nuke-support-in-uk-hits-record-high/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/nuke-support-in-uk-hits-record-high/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If only we had such sense here in Ireland, we can&amp;rsquo;t meet our commitments and it will hurt the economy in the long run not to go nuclear. The ESB has said &amp;ldquo;sometime in the 2030&amp;rsquo;s we will need to look at it&amp;rdquo; - why not look at it now? These projects take 10-15 years at least to implement properly.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reflection on 9-11</title>
      <link>/nerf-war/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/nerf-war/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been 10 years since the anniversary of 9/11 and much of the world has&#xA;changed a lot in that period. We&amp;rsquo;ve had full body scanners at airports,&#xA;marshalls on flights, bombs hidden in toner cartridges and two wars. I&#xA;reflected on this and remembered two really good articles I&amp;rsquo;ll share here&#xA;on the topic. Hopefully we&amp;rsquo;ve changed for the better.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I finally wrote something that&amp;rsquo;s been bothering me for about ten years:&#xA;The fact that Al Qaeda can&amp;rsquo;t be as big and bad as it&amp;rsquo;s made out to be,&#xA;because its whole design violates every rule of guerrilla organisation.&#xA;It&amp;rsquo;s like a counter intelligence officer&amp;rsquo;s dream,&#xA;the Al Qaeda plan to bring guerrillas from all over the world,&#xA;introduce them to each other, and exchange funds, material and ideas.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Have you got viruses or spyware? Here&#39;s my tips!</title>
      <link>/have-you-got-viruses-or-spyware-heres/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/have-you-got-viruses-or-spyware-heres/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I come into contact everyday with people asking how to fix&#xA;their machines due to the inevitable spyware and viruses found on a&#xA;Windows machine. Lately I have been switching people to&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ubuntu.com/&#34;&gt;Ubuntu&lt;/a&gt;, and even getting them to buy machines&#xA;to install it on (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dell.com/open&#34;&gt;Dell&lt;/a&gt;). But I understand&#xA;and have no zealotry for Linux when it comes to fixing peoples&amp;rsquo; real&#xA;world problems. I always mention &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ubuntu.com/&#34;&gt;Ubuntu&lt;/a&gt; as a&#xA;matter of course, and also &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apple.com/mac&#34;&gt;Macs&lt;/a&gt;. I follow up&#xA;peoples Ubuntu installs with friendly emails explaining the free help&#xA;open to them, but also as common (probably moreso) are my emailed tips&#xA;to people guiding them how to fix there Windows XP computer. So I&amp;rsquo;ll&#xA;list the steps here which are generic and should help anyone out their&#xA;with such problems; this is not a miracle cure and I fix these problems&#xA;on a case by case basis, so expect better perfromance, but not a new&#xA;computer!!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tor helps Privacy</title>
      <link>/tor-helps-privacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Mar 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/tor-helps-privacy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://img89.imageshack.us/my.php?image=efftorlogo400x282kw9.jpg&#34; title=&#34;Tor Logo&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://img89.imageshack.us/img89/3386/efftorlogo400x282kw9.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Tor&#xA;Logo&#34; title=&#34;Tor Logo&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Tor,&#xA;(or The Onion Router) is a service which connects people all over the&#xA;world with one aim: privacy. Tor protects from traffic analysis,&#xA;basically where you have been. Benn to you Banks website? Feel like&#xA;buying something off Amazon or Ebay? Your behaviour online is by no&#xA;means private, you hand over your numerical address, browser details,&#xA;country, city, versions of which plugins you use, where you came from,&#xA;just to name a few. You may have seen on sites something to the effect&#xA;of &amp;ldquo;Welcome Google user!&amp;rdquo;, that website knows exactly what you typed to&#xA;get to it. Tor routes your online activity through different computers,&#xA;for example mine went through an educational institution in the US and&#xA;an Internet Service Provider in the Netherlands.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wireless, New Design and Web Services</title>
      <link>/wireless-new-design-and-web-services/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/wireless-new-design-and-web-services/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the new and improved Duey Finsters. As I mentioned before, I hope&#xA;to receive a Nokia 770 Internet Tablet soon, so I will be checking the free&#xA;wireless services offered by Eircom in Dublin and at McDonalds restaurants.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You may have noticed the new look and this revamped blog. You may also&#xA;question where has Duey Finsters Web Services gone? It is still here, but me&#xA;and Thomas Whelan, who run it, cannot decide on a name. Maybe you all could&#xA;help us out? Since well over 97% of all the words in the dictionary are&#xA;registered as dot coms, we have no clue what to call ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
