<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mozilla on Neil Grogan</title>
    <link>/tags/mozilla/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mozilla on Neil Grogan</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/mozilla/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Chrome vs. Internet Explorer Audience</title>
      <link>/chrome-vs-internet-explorer-audience/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/chrome-vs-internet-explorer-audience/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Lately both Google and Microsoft have been advertising their respective browsers&#xA;on British Television (received in Ireland by the vast majority of the&#xA;population). It&amp;rsquo;s interesting the different approach each company is taking.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chrome ad:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&#34;allowfullscreen&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/embed/E0qDrRJT4zE&#34; width=&#34;560&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To me the Chrome ad is very family oriented, stressing the utility of the web&#xA;and the ease of reaching people and staying in touch. No surprise they&#xA;didn&amp;rsquo;t feature Facebook, which is what the vast majority use to keep in&#xA;touch.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Firefox and Opera lead the web video way</title>
      <link>/firefox-and-opera-lead-web-video-way/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/firefox-and-opera-lead-web-video-way/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I downloaded&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mozilla.com/en-US/firefox/all-beta.html&#34;&gt;Firefox 3.1 beta 2&lt;/a&gt; (after&#xA;trialling other development snapshots over the last few months) to see&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ogg_Theora&#34;&gt;Ogg Theora&lt;/a&gt; video support is coming on&#xA;really well. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.opera.com/&#34;&gt;Opera&lt;/a&gt;, as well as&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mozilla.org/&#34;&gt;Mozilla&lt;/a&gt; has committed to including this royalty-free&#xA;video codec for web use. This is really good news;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://dev.opera.com/articles/view/a-call-for-video-on-the-web-opera-vid/&#34;&gt;as one Opera Developer said:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Something however is still not quite there about web video. The video&#xA;solutions mentioned above are proprietary closed solutions that rely on&#xA;plugins to display in a web page - what we need to make video a first-class&#xA;web citizen is an easy, open solution to integrate video into web pages, and&#xA;native support for video in browsers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Profiling Firefox Extensions I have installed</title>
      <link>/profiling-firefox-extensions-i-have/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/profiling-firefox-extensions-i-have/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;My Current Firefox Extensions: A-Z*&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;../../img/08/74.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../img/08/74.png&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/1865&#34;&gt;Adblock Plus&lt;/a&gt;; because&#xA;ads are for people that don&amp;rsquo;t know how to avoid them! Not only do they stop&#xA;your banwidth from being wasted; they make a ton of websites more usuable. It&#xA;takes care of Flash Ads as well as static ones; using a filter that is&#xA;constantly updated. So even if some of the webs more devious and sneaky&#xA;advertisers try to circumvent it; AdBlock can have a fix to everyone online&#xA;within hours. It is definately my favourite extension! I don&amp;rsquo;t block certain&#xA;ads like Google, Yahoo, Microsoft (the ones with decent reputations) as that&#xA;is how the people behind really good websites I frequent make a living. But&#xA;for all the rest trying to do pop-ups and pop-unders; I am sorry your days are&#xA;numbered! (Some people higly recommend&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/433&#34;&gt;flashblock&lt;/a&gt; but I haven&amp;rsquo;t&#xA;had a need to use it with AdBlock Plus yet).&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;../../img/08/943948800.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../img/08/943948800.png&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/743&#34;&gt;CustomizeGoogle&lt;/a&gt; adds neat&#xA;tricks to Google services such as always using a secure connection to Gmail;&#xA;links to other search engines, page histories, Favicons to search and streaming&#xA;results pages. Comes in handy once in a while; but I don&amp;rsquo;t use it daily.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Internet Explorer thanks Firefox, sincerely?</title>
      <link>/internet-explorer-thanks-firefox/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/internet-explorer-thanks-firefox/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Reading my favourite tech news site: Slashdot ( &lt;a href=&#34;http://slashdot.org/articles/06/10/26/1238239.shtml&#34;&gt;/.&lt;/a&gt;), I see the &lt;a href=&#34;http://blogs.msdn.com/ie/&#34;&gt;Internet&#xA;Explorer team&lt;/a&gt; have sent the &lt;a href=&#34;http://getfirefox.com/&#34;&gt;Firefox Team&lt;/a&gt; a nice cake:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://static.flickr.com/118/278562314_14716c0232.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;MS IE Cake for Firefox&#xA;2&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One comment I read said it all really:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Seems even the IE team knows that IE is dead.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As for the ex-lax, bugs, pubes in the cake of course none of that is true.&#xA;Those things would only be possible if someone at Microsoft actually made the&#xA;cake, and that&amp;rsquo;s not how MS does things. They knew they couldn&amp;rsquo;t make a good&#xA;cake so they just went out and bought a cake from someone who already knew how&#xA;to make one and then stuck their logo on it and called it theirs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mozilla&#39;s Millions</title>
      <link>/mozillas-millions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Mar 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/mozillas-millions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Only now is it truly becoming clear, their is [serious money in Open Source][]/&#xA;With &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mozilla.com/&#34; title=&#34;Mozilla Corp&#34;&gt;Mozilla&lt;/a&gt; reported to have made tens of millions of dollars. One blogger&#xA;reported 70m was made by the corporation, with a Mozilla insider confirming&#xA;thats a reasonable ballpark figure. Christopher Blizzard, board member of&#xA;Mozilla, had this to say on his blog:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Blizzard added that an earnings figure of $72m (£41m) quoted on some blogs was&#xA;incorrect. “I won’t comment on the dollar amount except to say that it’s&#xA;[$72m] not correct, though not off by an order of magnitude. I also won’t&#xA;comment on sources of that money, except to say that some of the assertions&#xA;that I’ve seen in the comments are pretty far off, both in terms of numbers&#xA;and sources,&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
