<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>legal on Neil Grogan</title><link>/tags/legal/</link><description>Recent content in legal on Neil Grogan</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/legal/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Irish SOPA Law: An Overview</title><link>/irish-sopa-law-an-overview/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/irish-sopa-law-an-overview/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Eircom Responds...</title><link>/eircom-responds/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/eircom-responds/</guid><description>Dear,
[My Name]
eircom has not agreed to block any Internet sites from being accessed by
end-users. As part of the settlement of the above proceedings, it was
agreed that eircom would not oppose an application by the Plaintiffs to
seek to have eircom block access to the Pirate Bay website. The Music
Industry will still have to establish, in the normal way that there is
an appropriate basis for the relief which they seek from the Court.</description></item><item><title>Love letter to IRMA's Solicitor</title><link>/love-letter-to-irmas-solicitor/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/love-letter-to-irmas-solicitor/</guid><description>This post is a continuation on the previous one. IRMA is the Irish Music Rights Organisation which represents the big four record companies and their bottom line: never the artist. They have recently tried to regulate the Internet and have forced the biggest Irish ISP: Eircom; to use the three strikes rule and boot people off the Internet&amp;hellip; No Judge, no Jury, no evidence of a crime.. Just an IP address and a sanction which you cannot contest.</description></item><item><title>This post is censored by IRMA</title><link>/this-post-is-censored-by-irma/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/this-post-is-censored-by-irma/</guid><description>I always hoped for better for Ireland; but it seems the thieving hand of &amp;ldquo;rights&amp;rdquo; organizations which pretend to represent the artist have struck gold. Being able to cajole and bribe the largest Irish Internet Service Provider (ISP) - Eircom; has worked only too well. Although Eircom has said it will only obey by having a court order - it has agreed never to oppose these - which makes it complicit in the act of censorship.</description></item><item><title>Letter to EU Commissioner on 95 Year Copyright Extension [Updated]</title><link>/year/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Feb 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/year/</guid><description>I recently read a Slashdot article &amp;ldquo;EU Commissioner proposes 95 year copyright&amp;quot;. I am a staunch supporter of the European project; or at least the ideals it is based on to create a peaceful, demcratic union of countries with a common background and share similiar goals. Intrigued by the article I read it only to find out that a local man who used to represent my area was responsible. I had to write to him to ask how he lost his mind&amp;hellip;.</description></item><item><title>Linux and Patents: Just Patently Wrong</title><link>/linux-and-patents-just-patently-wrong/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/linux-and-patents-just-patently-wrong/</guid><description>So I read the news Novell and Red Hat are being sued for patent infringement. This is all about multiple workspaces that can hold various graphical user elements, a Xerox Parc patent which dates to the early 1990&amp;rsquo;s. Xerox Palo Alto Research center invented the graphical user interface in the 1980&amp;rsquo;s, only to been, licensed and used by Steve Jobs in Mac OS Classic. Now IP Innovation, a submarine patent troll, who make no products and bought the patent want their payday.</description></item><item><title>Apple - Play Nice....</title><link>/apple-play-nice/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Sep 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/apple-play-nice/</guid><description>Is the much beloved Apple the new Microsoft? First there was IBM, the big all crushing corporate machine that was humbled by the next big giant in the form of Microsoft, so it seems Apple&amp;rsquo;s turn is long overdue. The next few weeks are crucial to this crossroads in which Apple finds itself: It owes a HUGE amount to the BSD (an open source Unix clone) which is the foundation for not just OS X, but the iPhone and now the iPod Touch.</description></item><item><title>Update on RTE and the Creative Commons</title><link>/update-on-rte-and-creative-commons/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/update-on-rte-and-creative-commons/</guid><description>Unbeknownst to me, with my quick thinking on the positive developments regarding CBS releasing democratic debates under a permissive license in the United States has caused quite a few Irish bloggers to echo my call on RTE&amp;rsquo;s stance on releasing the Irish Election 2007 debates. If you agree we should be allowed to download, remix and share the debates while giving RTE credit for production, please:
Sign the Petition!
UPDATE: Poll is now closed as the leaders debates are now finished.</description></item><item><title>UK Parliamentary debate "Copyright is not a pension fund"</title><link>/uk-parliamentary-debate-is-not-pension/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/uk-parliamentary-debate-is-not-pension/</guid><description>I found this doing a search for Domino Records DRM. I looked up some of my favourite artists to see if they were part of the &amp;ldquo;MAFIAA&amp;rdquo; that is the RIAA (Recording Industry Association of America), not surprisingly some were (70% of sold music worldwide is put out by this cartel). I got rather confused when a Franz Ferdinand album appeared on the list, when their debut album did not. Seems the record label did a deal with Sony for distribution.</description></item><item><title>Get the facts, about "Get the Facts"</title><link>/get-facts-about-get-facts/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/get-facts-about-get-facts/</guid><description>Just a quick blurb about some things Microsoft like to say: Don&amp;rsquo;t believe it, well at least not it all anyway. On the Irish &amp;ldquo;Get the Facts&amp;rdquo; page (on Windows Server vs. Linux), they make critical errors of judgement a person reasonably well versed in computing could deconstruct. First of all, Linux isn&amp;rsquo;t a server, its a kernel, like the Windows kernel. So comparing &amp;ldquo;Windows Server 2003&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;Linux&amp;rdquo; is misleading to say the least, and stupid to say the most.</description></item><item><title>Law and the Interweb</title><link>/law-and-interweb/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/law-and-interweb/</guid><description>I am writing this because, I regret to say, the stupidity of humanity. People nowadays define their own law on the Web and the Internet (don’t know the difference, you should), while disregarding real life. Maybe its a lack of understanding about technology or law, I don’t know. One things for sure, common sense can go a long way. Take for example this website on the Commitments, which prohibits linking from unauthorised sites!</description></item></channel></rss>