<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Legal on Neil Grogan</title>
    <link>/tags/legal/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Legal on Neil Grogan</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/legal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Irish SOPA Law: An Overview</title>
      <link>/irish-sopa-law-an-overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/irish-sopa-law-an-overview/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../files/2012/01/sopa.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Irish SOPA Illustration&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Eircom Responds...</title>
      <link>/eircom-responds/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/eircom-responds/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Dear,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;[My Name]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;eircom has not agreed to block any Internet sites from being accessed by&lt;br&gt;&#xA;end-users. As part of the settlement of the above proceedings, it was&lt;br&gt;&#xA;agreed that eircom would not oppose an application by the Plaintiffs to&lt;br&gt;&#xA;seek to have eircom block access to the Pirate Bay website. The Music&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Industry will still have to establish, in the normal way that there is&lt;br&gt;&#xA;an appropriate basis for the relief which they seek from the Court.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;eircom is not supporting or consenting to the application. The&lt;br&gt;&#xA;settlement makes no provision for any site other than the Pirate Bay&lt;br&gt;&#xA;website.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Love letter to IRMA&#39;s Solicitor</title>
      <link>/love-letter-to-irmas-solicitor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/love-letter-to-irmas-solicitor/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This post is a continuation on the previous one. IRMA is the Irish Music&#xA;Rights Organisation which represents the big four record companies and their&#xA;bottom line: never the artist. They have recently tried to regulate the&#xA;Internet and have forced the biggest Irish ISP: Eircom; to use the three&#xA;strikes rule and boot people off the Internet&amp;hellip; No Judge, no Jury, no&#xA;evidence of a crime.. Just an IP address and a sanction which you cannot&#xA;contest.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This post is censored by IRMA</title>
      <link>/this-post-is-censored-by-irma/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/this-post-is-censored-by-irma/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I always hoped for better for Ireland; but it seems the thieving hand of&#xA;&amp;ldquo;rights&amp;rdquo; organizations which pretend to represent the artist have struck gold.&#xA;Being able to cajole and bribe the largest Irish Internet Service Provider&#xA;(ISP) - Eircom; has worked only too well. Although Eircom has said it will only&#xA;obey by having a court order - it has agreed never to oppose these - which makes&#xA;it complicit in the act of censorship. My Letter to Our ISP, Eircom, IRMA, EFF:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Letter to EU Commissioner on 95 Year Copyright Extension [Updated]</title>
      <link>/year/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Feb 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/year/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently read a Slashdot article&#xA;&amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://slashdot.org/article.pl?sid=08/02/14/1626228&#34;&gt;EU Commissioner proposes 95 year copyright&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;I am a staunch supporter of the European project; or at least the ideals it is&#xA;based on to create a peaceful, demcratic union of countries with a common&#xA;background and share similiar goals. Intrigued by the article I read it only to&#xA;find out that a local man who used to represent my area was responsible. I had&#xA;to write to him to ask how he lost his mind&amp;hellip;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Linux and Patents: Just Patently Wrong</title>
      <link>/linux-and-patents-just-patently-wrong/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/linux-and-patents-just-patently-wrong/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So I read the news&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theregister.co.uk/2007/10/12/novell_red_hat_linux_patent_sued/&#34;&gt;Novell and Red Hat are being sued for patent infringement&lt;/a&gt;.&#xA;This is all about multiple workspaces that can hold various graphical user&#xA;elements, a Xerox Parc patent which dates to the early 1990&amp;rsquo;s. Xerox Palo Alto&#xA;Research center invented the graphical user interface in the 1980&amp;rsquo;s, only to&#xA;been, licensed and used by Steve Jobs in Mac OS Classic. Now IP Innovation, a&#xA;submarine patent troll, who make no products and bought the patent want their&#xA;payday. The logical step is to go after the biggest infringer to set a precedent&#xA;for your patent, and then make your way to all the smaller companies who&#xA;infringe. Well logically of course that would be Apple or Microsoft. Apple has&#xA;already paid them a reported 20 million dollars, and well no-one knows what&#xA;Microsoft has done, but this fish is smelly. From the Register Article:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Apple - Play Nice....</title>
      <link>/apple-play-nice/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Sep 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/apple-play-nice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;../../img/07/AppleLogo.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../img/07/AppleLogo.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Is the much beloved Apple the new Microsoft? First there was IBM, the big all&#xA;crushing corporate machine that was humbled by the next big giant in the form of&#xA;Microsoft, so it seems Apple&amp;rsquo;s turn is long overdue. The next few weeks are&#xA;crucial to this crossroads in which Apple finds itself: It owes a HUGE amount to&#xA;the BSD (an open source Unix clone) which is the foundation for not just OS X,&#xA;but the iPhone and now the iPod Touch. Basically without the kernel that runs&#xA;these fantastic devices, Apple would still be up shit creek without a paddle.&#xA;Granted the iPod would have been a huge success probably still, but OS X&amp;rsquo;s core&#xA;is the foundation for the real money making Apple will do over the next few&#xA;years, a point that is not lost on Mr. Jobs as the company intelligently markets&#xA;different segments to different markets of which I have first hand experience&#xA;of: Go to the Apple site for education and they extol the brilliance of a&#xA;Macbook and make they deal sweeter by throwing in an iPod Nano. But if you go to&#xA;a link I was provided in a college advert; they bring to a page pointing out key&#xA;areas a mac can make a difference. I picked Computer Science naturally, and the&#xA;site extolled the virtues of Open Source, a Unix base and programming tools like&#xA;Xcode.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Update on RTE and the Creative Commons</title>
      <link>/update-on-rte-and-creative-commons/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/update-on-rte-and-creative-commons/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Unbeknownst to me, with&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dueyfinster.com/2007/05/irish-elections-creative-commons.html&#34; title=&#34;RTE, Irish Elections &amp;amp; Creative Commons&#34;&gt;my quick thinking on the positive developments regarding CBS releasing democratic debates&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;under a permissive license in the United States has caused&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ferguscassidy.ie/2007/05/08/one-for-everyone-in-the-audience/&#34;&gt;quite&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cearta.ie/2007/05/speech-just-wants-to-be-free/&#34;&gt;few&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mulley.net/2007/05/08/first-come-the-parodies/&#34;&gt;Irish&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.irishelection.com/05/web-roundup-day-10/&#34;&gt;bloggers&lt;/a&gt; to echo my call&#xA;on RTE&amp;rsquo;s stance on releasing the Irish Election 2007 debates. If you agree we&#xA;should be allowed to download, remix and share the debates while giving RTE&#xA;credit for production, please:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.petitiononline.com/Speech/petition.html&#34; title=&#34;RTE Creative Commons Petition&#34;&gt;Sign the Petition!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UK Parliamentary debate &#34;Copyright is not a pension fund&#34;</title>
      <link>/uk-parliamentary-debate-is-not-pension/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/uk-parliamentary-debate-is-not-pension/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I found this doing a search for Domino Records DRM. I&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.riaaradar.com/&#34; title=&#34;RIAA Radar&#34;&gt;looked up some of my favourite artists&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;to see if they were part of the &amp;ldquo;MAFIAA&amp;rdquo; that is the&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/RIAA&#34; title=&#34;Recording Industry Association of America&#34;&gt;RIAA&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;(Recording Industry Association of America), not surprisingly some were (70% of&#xA;sold music worldwide is put out by this cartel). I got rather confused when a&#xA;Franz Ferdinand album appeared on the list, when their debut album did not.&#xA;Seems the record label did a deal with Sony for distribution. I found a piece of&#xA;information quite old now (May 2006), but interesting anyway:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Get the facts, about &#34;Get the Facts&#34;</title>
      <link>/get-facts-about-get-facts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/get-facts-about-get-facts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just a quick blurb about some things Microsoft like to say: Don&amp;rsquo;t believe it,&#xA;well at least not it all anyway. On the&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.microsoft.com/ireland/getthefacts/default.mspx&#34; title=&#34;Irish Get the Facts&#34;&gt;Irish &amp;ldquo;Get the Facts&amp;rdquo; page&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;(on Windows Server vs. Linux), they make critical errors of judgement a person&#xA;reasonably well versed in computing could deconstruct. First of all, Linux isn&amp;rsquo;t&#xA;a server, its a kernel, like the Windows kernel. So comparing &amp;ldquo;Windows Server&#xA;2003&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;Linux&amp;rdquo; is misleading to say the least, and stupid to say the most. You&#xA;could run any server software on Linux you wished, even Windows Server 2003 if&#xA;Microsoft ported it! For the sake of argument, I think they are comparing&#xA;themselves to Apache, which runs 60% of worldwide&#xA;servers&lt;a href=&#34;http://news.netcraft.com/archives/2007/01/05/january_2007_web_server_survey.html&#34; title=&#34;Netcraft Server Marketshare&#34;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Law and the Interweb</title>
      <link>/law-and-interweb/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/law-and-interweb/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am writing this because, I regret to say, the stupidity of humanity. People&#xA;nowadays define their own law on the Web and the Internet (don’t know the&#xA;difference, you should), while disregarding real life. Maybe its a lack of&#xA;understanding about technology or law, I don’t know. One things for sure, common&#xA;sense can go a long way. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thecommitments.net/&#34; title=&#34;The Commitments Official Website&#34;&gt;Take for example this website on the&#xA;Commitments&lt;/a&gt;, which prohibits linking from unauthorised sites! You&#xA;see? I just broke the law right there, amazing dontcha think? The person who&#xA;designed or put the statement up, is a total complete and utter idiot, and I&#xA;don’t care if thats considered slander! Imagine if every site was to do this?&#xA;Search engines would be just another litagation filled business, like so many&#xA;other. With Lawyers reviewing every site to go into the database, Google would&#xA;have a handful, maybe a 100 sites, instead of the usual billions it indexes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
