<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Foss on Neil Grogan</title>
    <link>/tags/foss/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Foss on Neil Grogan</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/foss/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Wordpress 2.6</title>
      <link>/wordpress-26/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/wordpress-26/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Open Source star of the blogging world&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ekiga&#39;s Vorbis</title>
      <link>/ekigas-vorbis/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/ekigas-vorbis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am all for open standards, but they face huge problems. Not least is lack of&#xA;intergration between them. Take SIP used by VOIP providers, such as&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wengo.com/&#34;&gt;OpenWengo&lt;/a&gt;. While OpenWengo is open source, and it is SIP, they are not&#xA;helpful in informing you how to use other clients, or dial other OpenWengo&#xA;users from other networks.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What I am really talking about is the need for an all-in-one communications&#xA;program, that is multi-platform. Their is already open source code for: Google&#xA;Talk (aka Jabber), MSN, AOL, ICQ, SIP, H.323, Yahoo! but why isn’t their an&#xA;all-in-one client? Surely it would be easy to reimplement some code from other&#xA;programs into Ekiga (SIP, H.323) , Kopete or Gaim (both Jabber, MSN, Yahoo,&#xA;AOL and ICQ)? I know GoogleTalk is based on SIP, so why not SIP compatability?&#xA;That is poor implementation which is fragmenting the Open Source community,&#xA;how are we going to challenge MSN’s userbase with this sort of fragmentation?&#xA;That said I like Google Talk and its way of doing things. Also it is rumoured&#xA;GoogleTalk will be interoperable with AOL at protocol level, since Google owns&#xA;5% of AOL.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
