<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Podcast on Neil Grogan</title>
    <link>/tags/podcast/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Podcast on Neil Grogan</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/podcast/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Favourite Podcasts</title>
      <link>/fave-podcasts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/fave-podcasts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the last while I&amp;rsquo;ve been collecting wonderful podcast episodes from the hundreds of hours I&amp;rsquo;ve listened to. I&amp;rsquo;ve even workshopped some of my favourites with colleagues and friends (they all approve!). Luckily a neat service called &lt;a href=&#34;https://huffduffer.com/&#34;&gt;HuffDuffer&lt;/a&gt; allows you to create a personalised feed from episodes spanning any podcast you see fit. All you need is a direct link to the MP3 or indeed any format audio file.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So here it is, my favourite episodes spanning many podcasts. Mostly I love good stories, with unexpected twists. I suppose you could simplify that to &amp;ldquo;Surprise and Delight&amp;rdquo;. Be prepared to be entertained, surprised and delighted&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stitcher is (audio) podcasts done right</title>
      <link>/stitcher/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/stitcher/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just a quick post about a great application I&amp;rsquo;ve seen mentioned by &lt;a href=&#34;http://geekbeat.tv/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&gt;Cali Lewis&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.stitcher.com/&#34;&gt;Stitcher&lt;/a&gt;. If your a talk radio fan like me, you&amp;rsquo;ll really appreciate this app! Ever since I switched from an iPhone 4 to a Galaxy S3 and stopped using Apple&amp;rsquo;s Podcast application it has been frustrating to keep up to date with podcasts.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve used BeyondPod on Android (which I&amp;rsquo;ve praised before - excellent Google Reader integration). I then tried to search for a third party podcast application on the iPad that would synchronise with Google Reader. First there were none, then some (like Feedler and Instacast) but all have been bitterly disappointing with Google Reader integration. Instacast could import OPML (after a messy bundling of feeds in Google Reader) and Feedler could read the feeds (but not handle the video and audio contained within the feed item properly). To be honest I&amp;rsquo;d given up hope, I said to myself I&amp;rsquo;d chalk it up to fate and just buy a Nexus tablet when the iPad 2 was no longer serviceable. But - happily - I was wrong and had been looking in the wrong places&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Record your terminal session</title>
      <link>/record-your-terminal-session/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/record-your-terminal-session/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As I&amp;rsquo;ve mentioned before&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, I regularly watch technology podcasts and I&amp;rsquo;ve had a subscription to sites like &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.lynda.com&#34; title=&#34;Lynda Training Videos&#34;&gt;Lynda.com&lt;/a&gt;. Between those and Youtube, I&amp;rsquo;ve watched an awful lot of technology how-to videos and 90% of them are quite poor in terms of editing, sound and being coherent/properly scripted. Sometimes though it&amp;rsquo;s a joy to genuinely learn something new in a short, concise and to the point video.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;iframe src=&#34;http://revision3.com/html5player-v12777?external=true&amp;width=555&amp;height=312&#34; width=&#34;555&#34; height=&#34;312&#34;  frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowFullScreen=&#34;allowfullscreen&#34; &gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This haktip is right up there with being among the best: short, concise, to the point and about a utility that will be super-useful to me. In work I&amp;rsquo;m in an agile software development team and I spend a lot of time on the command line. I &lt;strong&gt;like&lt;/strong&gt; the command line, but many don&amp;rsquo;t (personal preference I guess). As part of being agile, we produce a lot of video demos to stakeholders. Increasingly though the demos we produce are just as useful for the team - you can&amp;rsquo;t be every team member at once and this provides huge visibility to the team of progress. Our software is a Unix product, but we develop on Windows - so Camtasia is usually used - which is fine for GUI demos. This handy utility will be great to demo CLI stuff we do.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tech Video Podcasts Worth Watching</title>
      <link>/tech-video-podcasts-worth-watching/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/tech-video-podcasts-worth-watching/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I try to listen to as many &lt;strike&gt;podcasts&lt;/strike&gt; (&lt;em&gt;netcasts?&lt;/em&gt;) as I can.&#xA;They fall in to two categories: Irish radio and technology.  Luckily, there is&#xA;so much competition in this space it&amp;rsquo;s hard to pick the best - so quality is high!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tech News Today (TNT)&lt;/strong&gt; by the TWiT Network&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/embed/ZiOI7GbVhoY&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;allowfullscreen&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Regular and fills you right up to the minute with the latest tech news.&#xA;Can replace RSS of many blogs (HUGE time saver) since lively debate of&#xA;tech topics is the order of the day.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Haiku: Open Source BeOS clone</title>
      <link>/haiku-open-source-beos-clone/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/haiku-open-source-beos-clone/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I usually listen&#xA;to podcasts on the excellent Twit.tv network and it goes without saying&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.twit.tv/floss&#34;&gt;Floss Weekly&lt;/a&gt; is one of my favourites. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.twit.tv/floss120&#34;&gt;A&#xA;recent episode&lt;/a&gt; covered&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.haiku-os.org/&#34;&gt;Haiku&lt;/a&gt; - an open source operating system&#xA;based on the design of the old BeOS. What&amp;rsquo;s very interesting about&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/BeOS&#34;&gt;BeOS&lt;/a&gt; is the design, an integrated&#xA;all in one operating system - and the fact Apple almost purchased it.&#xA;That&amp;rsquo;s amazing to me, literally in one fell swoop, if Apple had of&#xA;offered the 200 million Be Systems wanted, there would be no NextStep&#xA;into Apple and by extension - Steve Jobs. It&amp;rsquo;s especially poignant since&#xA;Apple just surpassed Microsoft to become the second most valuable&#xA;American company.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best Radio Podcasts</title>
      <link>/best-radio-podcasts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/best-radio-podcasts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Even while podcasts are relatively new (well a couple of years - like blogs),&#xA;Irish Radio Stations are surprisingly well in on the act. Even our incumbent&#xA;state broadcaster, RTE, is podcasting en-masse on both RTE Radio 1 and RTE&#xA;2FM. To recieve podcasts, you need podcasting software, start by getting&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://juicereceiver.sourceforge.net/index.php&#34;&gt;Juice Reciever&lt;/a&gt;(Formerly&#xA;iPodder), available for Linux, BSD, MAC and Windows. I will start with my top&#xA;5 Irish Radio podcasts:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Click Online</title>
      <link>/click-online/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/click-online/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In case you have never looked at it, Click Online is the flagship  technology&#xA;program for the BBC. It broadcasts on the Internet and can  be viewed even on&#xA;a 56k modem. I have been watching click online for  over a year and a half&#xA;now, I first saw it on BBC World, while holidaying  in Portugal. It also&#xA;broadcasts on BBC News 24 at 7am on a Sunday morning  (I have never seen it at&#xA;this time!). Although by its nature a technical  program, it is very much&#xA;aimed at the average PC user and so most things  are explained fully.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
