<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Health on Neil Grogan</title>
    <link>/tags/health/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Health on Neil Grogan</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/health/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Tonsillectomy</title>
      <link>/tonsillectomy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/tonsillectomy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve recently undergone a tonsillectomy - the process of removing the lymph node&#xA;tissue hanging idly at the back of your throat. I know I write mainly technology&#xA;articles, but I thought a departure was warranted from the usual faire.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My main takeaway from having it done is twofold: it&amp;rsquo;s not as bad as you think&#xA;and it&amp;rsquo;s as bad as you think. They seem like contradictory statements, so I&amp;rsquo;ll&#xA;need to explain myself right? Okay.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kerataconus and Me</title>
      <link>/kerataconus-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/kerataconus-me/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/f/f3/KC-lens.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;Well this is&#xA;not a technology related post, but I get asked about it alot and people have&#xA;sketchy details about what it is (ie. they know my vision is messed up).&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Keratoconus&lt;/strong&gt; (from Greek: &lt;em&gt;kerato-&lt;/em&gt; horn, cornea; and &lt;em&gt;konos&lt;/em&gt; cone), is a&#xA;degenerative non-inflammatory disorder of the eye in which structural changes&#xA;within the cornea cause it to thin and change to a more conical shape than its&#xA;normal gradual curve. In plain English, light bends in a distorted way to make&#xA;vision ghosted, blurry and less sharp. Glasses cannot fix this problem as they&#xA;fix issues with your natural lense behind the cornea, as usually it has improper&#xA;focus.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
