<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Review on Neil Grogan</title>
    <link>/tags/review/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Review on Neil Grogan</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/review/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes and Nix Cluster</title>
      <link>/k8s-nix-cluster/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/k8s-nix-cluster/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;About this time last year, I purchased 3 mini computers with the aim of making a &lt;a href=&#34;https://kubernetes.io/&#34;&gt;Kubernetes&lt;/a&gt; cluster. I followed an excellent youtube video: &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/2yplBzPCghA?si=1Fq1Fx0PSvXP8krE&#34;&gt;This homelab setup is my favorite one yet - Dreams of Autonomy&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dreamsofautonomy/homelab&#34;&gt;Github Repository&lt;/a&gt;) which described the machines to buy (Beelink EQ 13 Mini), how to upgrade the &lt;abbr title=&#34;Solid State Disk&#34;&gt;SSD&lt;/abbr&gt; and &lt;abbr title=&#34;Random Access Memory&#34;&gt;RAM&lt;/abbr&gt;, how to provision them with &lt;a href=&#34;https://nixos.org&#34;&gt;NixOS&lt;/a&gt;, setup &lt;a href=&#34;https://k3s.io&#34;&gt;K3S&lt;/a&gt;, and connect using &lt;a href=&#34;https://kubectl.docs.kubernetes.io/guides/&#34;&gt;kubectl&lt;/a&gt; to manage the cluster. You will also have to modify your router&amp;rsquo;s &lt;abbr title=&#34;Dynamic Host Configuration Protocol&#34;&gt;DHCP&lt;/abbr&gt; settings so you can give the cluster static &lt;abbr title=&#34;Internet Protocol&#34;&gt;IP&lt;/abbr&gt; addresses.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Picade</title>
      <link>/picade/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/picade/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Picade is an arcade machine you build yourself which uses a raspberry pi as the brains. It is available from &lt;a href=&#34;https://shop.pimoroni.com/products/picade&#34;&gt;Pimoroni&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Framework 13 AMD</title>
      <link>/framework13/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2024 22:52:53 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/framework13/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently bought a &lt;a href=&#34;https://frame.work&#34;&gt;Framework 13&lt;/a&gt; laptop as a personal&#xA;machine. If you are not aware - Framework makes build-it-yourself laptops. I&#xA;wanted to review different parts of the process and give an overview of how it&amp;rsquo;s&#xA;been from ordering to delivery.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>iOS Shells, Prompt vs. Mosh</title>
      <link>/mosh/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/mosh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a big fan of the shell and the productivity it brings, you can have a text&#xA;editor, command to run a server and more within easy reach. I use a shell at&#xA;work, at home and on the go. On the go could be using my iPad or iPhone. One of&#xA;the first SSH clients on iOS was iSSH, which I used many years ago. After this,&#xA;Panic released a professional class application called &lt;a href=&#34;https://panic.com/prompt/&#34;&gt;Prompt&lt;/a&gt;. Prompt is&#xA;what I&amp;rsquo;ve happily used for the last few years, but the 10 minute background&#xA;process limit is a constant pain. Just a quick switch away for a few minutes,&#xA;and you have to reconnect. That&amp;rsquo;s fine once or twice, but when it happens many&#xA;times it seriously slows your productivity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Plain Text Accounting</title>
      <link>/ledger/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/ledger/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For the last few years, I&amp;rsquo;ve always wanted to budget properly and see where my&#xA;money was going. But like all habits that are good for you, looking after your&#xA;finances takes time, care and attention. I started off by researching the market&#xA;for budgeting software. A lot of the prepackged software out there was very&#xA;US-centric, including Quicken, Microsoft Money and&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mint.com&#34;&gt;Mint.com&lt;/a&gt;. I eventually settled on and bought a license&#xA;for &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ynab.com&#34;&gt;You Need a Budget&lt;/a&gt;, because: it had a budgeting&#xA;methodology, very good Euro support and was cross platform with&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Adobe_AIR&#34;&gt;Adobe Air&lt;/a&gt;. YNAB lasted me well for a&#xA;few years, with its pretty graphs and ease of expense entry. I even liked their&#xA;much pared-down companion iOS app at the time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>iPad Pro Review</title>
      <link>/ipadpro/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/ipadpro/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After some thought initially on a new laptop, I decided to spring for an iPad&#xA;Pro 12.9&amp;quot;. So far I am really glad I did, the computer comes with me everywhere.&#xA;I bring it to work, to visit family, on trips and everywhere in between.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s the ultimate work computer in many ways, always with you, light enough and&#xA;comfortable enough for real work™. The keyboard shortcuts in iOS have improved&#xA;massively from iOS 8 to iOS 9 to the point of actually being useful and the&#xA;split screen view is actually rather nice to use (I never &amp;ldquo;got&amp;rdquo; it on a Mac).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remote: Office Not Required</title>
      <link>/remote-book/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/remote-book/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently read &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.co.uk/Remote-Required-David-Heinemeier-Hansson/dp/0091954673&#34;&gt;Remote: Office Not Required&lt;/a&gt; by David Heinemeier-Hansson&#xA;(who created Ruby on Rails) and Jason Fried (who co-founded 37 Signals with&#xA;Heinemeier-Hansson). This book is really a case study in why the future of work&#xA;will be remote, of which the book did convince me (but I would say, I already&#xA;believed).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../img/16/remote-book.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The book is really structured to convince those who do not believe in the&#xA;premise of the title. It talks about many successful companies who have&#xA;transformed themselves to work remotely fully and large corporations who save&#xA;lots of money on office space (IBM, being one example).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanical Keyboards</title>
      <link>/mech-kb/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/mech-kb/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Early last year, I purchased two &lt;a href=&#34;http://codekeyboards.com&#34;&gt;Code Keyboards&lt;/a&gt; (one for work and one for&#xA;home). The Code Keyboards are designed by &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.codinghorror.com&#34;&gt;Jeff Atwood&lt;/a&gt; (who founded &lt;a href=&#34;http://stackoverflow.com&#34;&gt;Stack&#xA;Overflow&lt;/a&gt;). Mechanical keyboards are “old style” in that the switches are&#xA;from an era where everything was mechanical, unlike today where everything is&#xA;glass. So mechanical keyboards have ardent fans and people who don’t really care&#xA;for them.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../img/16/code_kb.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I did a lot of research before I purchased, talking to various people in work&#xA;who are very knowledgeable about mechanical keyboards (The best community for&#xA;advice, discussion and group buys is &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/mechanicalkeyboards&#34;&gt;/r/mechanicalkeyboards&lt;/a&gt; on reddit.).&#xA;The variety of hardware and opinions is positively mind melting. If you are&#xA;doing your own research, you should definitely come across &lt;a href=&#34;http://cherryswitches.com&#34;&gt;Cherry switches&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;(a very established German brand). Switches are what sit between your key that&#xA;you see (with the letter printed on top) and the electronic board that converts&#xA;the key press to a signal the computer can understand.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ulysses App</title>
      <link>/ulysses-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/ulysses-app/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently purchased&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://geo.itunes.apple.com/ie/app/ulysses-mobile/id950335311?mt=8&amp;amp;uo=4&amp;amp;at=1001l4PJ&#34;&gt;Ulysses Mobile&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;after a&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.macstories.net/reviews/review-ulysses-2-5-for-ipad-and-now-iphone/&#34;&gt;recommendation from Macstories&lt;/a&gt;.&#xA;My first impression was how expensive it was priced and what really makes a&#xA;&lt;em&gt;premium writing application&lt;/em&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Needless to say, I&amp;rsquo;m not a huge writer. But I do have a real fondness for plain&#xA;text (it will survive the apocalypse) and by extension,&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://daringfireball.net/projects/markdown/&#34;&gt;Markdown by John Gruber.&lt;/a&gt; The&#xA;problem for Ulysses is this: there&amp;rsquo;s lots of really great Markdown applications&#xA;for iOS, two of which I have written about: Editorial (my favourite) and Byword&#xA;(not so keen on this app).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Roost Laptop Stand</title>
      <link>/roost-stand/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/roost-stand/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I backed the Roost laptop stand on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kickstarter.org&#34;&gt;Kickstarter&lt;/a&gt;,&#xA;which already had a successful run in their first Kickstarter campaign. I&amp;rsquo;ve&#xA;been delighted with the result so far, it lives up to the promises of being&#xA;super light but yet durable and strong. Here&amp;rsquo;s a photo of it:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../img/16/roost.png&#34; alt=&#34;Roost Laptop stand holding a macbook&#34; title=&#34;Roost Stand&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It came with a really nice case which holds the Roost underneath and has pockets&#xA;for a portable keyboard (I use a&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.logitech.com/en-us/product/illuminated-keyboard-for-mac-ipad-iphone&#34;&gt;Logitech K811&lt;/a&gt;)&#xA;and mouse (I use a&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.logitech.com/en-us/product/marathon-mouse-m705&#34;&gt;Logitech Marathon M705&lt;/a&gt;).&#xA;It works great for a really comfortable and ergonomic desk wherever you may&#xA;travel (or set up to work). Highly recommended!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Maintainable Software Book</title>
      <link>/maintain-soft-book/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/maintain-soft-book/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently read O&amp;rsquo;Reilly&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.co.uk/Building-Mantainable-Software-Guidelines-Future-Proof/dp/1491953527/&#34;&gt;Building Maintainable Software&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;(Java Edition). It provides good insight as to what to look for to create&#xA;maintainability in enterpise software systems.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;10-suggestions-the-book-provides&#34;&gt;10 suggestions the book provides:&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Write shorter units&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Write simpler units (measured in&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cyclomatic_complexity&#34;&gt;Cyclomatic Complexity&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Write code once only&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Keep interfaces very small&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Seperate code in to modules&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Couple modules loosely&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Keep modules evenly sized&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Keep codebase small (and look for ways to right-size)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Automate development pipeline and your tests&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Write clean code and refactor as you go&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Overall I thought the book was very well laid out, easy to read and easy to&#xA;understand. I&amp;rsquo;d recommend it to anyone new to software development, but most of&#xA;the tips contained within the book should be very familiar to the seasoned&#xA;developer.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deliveries App</title>
      <link>/deliveries-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/deliveries-app/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://geo.itunes.apple.com/ie/app/deliveries-a-package-tracker/id290986013?mt=8&amp;amp;uo=4&amp;amp;at=1001l4PJ&#34;&gt;Deliveries&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;helps you track packages from major shopping (Amazon, Apple) as well as nearly&#xA;every major package distribution company like DHL, UPS and FedEx. I&amp;rsquo;ve used the&#xA;app for years and it&amp;rsquo;s really impressed me.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It can sync via iCloud or the Junecloud cloud service by the makers of the app,&#xA;Junecloud (not confusing at all, hey!). It started on the Mac as a simple&#xA;dashboard widget (for those of you who remember those, rarely used these days),&#xA;but it&amp;rsquo;s since grown to have&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://geo.itunes.apple.com/ie/app/deliveries-a-package-tracker/id924726344?mt=12&amp;amp;uo=4&amp;amp;at=1001l4PJ&#34;&gt;its own Mac app also&lt;/a&gt;.&#xA;Considering many people will have a lot of packages coming from everywhere this&#xA;Christmas, it&amp;rsquo;s definitely a really useful app to have!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Editorial App</title>
      <link>/editorial-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/editorial-app/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://itunes.apple.com/ie/app/editorial/id673907758?mt=8&amp;amp;uo=4&amp;amp;at=1001l4PJ&#34; title=&#34;editorial&#34;&gt;Editorial&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;is an iPhone and iPad plain text editor that&amp;rsquo;s great for markdown&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. It also&#xA;has some nifty automation workflows, in which you can use Python scripts. These&#xA;can search the web, scrape data, transform text and much more…&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I pretty much wrote this blog post (and many more) in Editorial. It&amp;rsquo;s much&#xA;better then the competition for markdown in particular.&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://itunes.apple.com/ie/app/byword/id482063361?mt=8&amp;amp;uo=4&amp;amp;at=1001l4PJ&#34; title=&#34;byword&#34;&gt;Byword&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;is an obvious competitor, which I really can&amp;rsquo;t recommend (nothing inherently&#xA;wrong with Byword, just doesn&amp;rsquo;t suit me).&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.macstories.net/reviews/editorial-1-2-brings-powerful-new-text-editing-features-more-ios-automation/&#34;&gt;MacStories has an in -depth Editorial review&lt;/a&gt;,&#xA;which is well worth a long read.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Soulver App</title>
      <link>/soulver-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/soulver-app/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My favourite text number crunching app on iOS bar none is &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.acqualia.com/soulver/&#34;&gt;Soulver&lt;/a&gt;. What&#xA;makes it the best?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Fast to load&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Simple user interface that gets out of the way&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Contextual Keyboards (my favourite is the currency keyboard)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Can reuse calculations from previous lines (and name calculations).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;iCloud sync&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.acqualia.com/soulver/&#34;&gt;Soulver&lt;/a&gt; is great for when a spreadsheet is just to heavy. I use it a lot for&#xA;it currency conversion, makes it easy to have multiple line items in different&#xA;currencies (say GBP &amp;amp; USD) and get a total in one (EUR). Also for splitting the&#xA;bills at a resturant, each line could be a food item (so if two desserts cost&#xA;the same, you can see quickly and only add lines relevant for each participant).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Drafts App</title>
      <link>/drafts-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/drafts-app/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My favourite text capture app on iOS bar none is &lt;a href=&#34;http://agiletortoise.com/drafts/&#34;&gt;Drafts&lt;/a&gt; by Agile Tortoise.&#xA;What makes it the best?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;No fluff, loads fast&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Simple user interface that gets out of the way&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Extensible actions (which you can add to from their &lt;a href=&#34;http://drafts4-actions.agiletortoise.com&#34;&gt;directory&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;iCloud sync&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve tried a lot of other apps like &lt;a href=&#34;http://bywordapp.com/&#34;&gt;Byword&lt;/a&gt; (Not worth the money I think),&#xA;Apples&amp;rsquo; built-in Notes app, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.textasticapp.com/&#34;&gt;Textastic&lt;/a&gt; and so on. None felt as efficient or&#xA;as flexible as Drafts. With Drafts, I can trust my text can be anywhere I need&#xA;it to be.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>De&#39;Longhi Magnifica ESAM4200 Bean to Cup</title>
      <link>/coffee-machine/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/coffee-machine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve had this &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.co.uk/gp/product/B001EOMZ5E/ref=oh_aui_detailpage_o07_s00?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&#34;&gt;DeLonghi&lt;/a&gt; machine for a year and a half now, and I possibly am&#xA;slightly a little in love. It was the best rated coffee machine (at time of&#xA;purchase) on Amazon and it doesn&amp;rsquo;t dissapoint. For the purpose, it&amp;rsquo;s wonderful:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Make great coffee fast, without a mess.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re looking for more, I would have a look at the more expensive models.&#xA;When I shopped around at the time, I read that the internals of this machine are&#xA;just as good as the ones that DeLonghi sells that are twice as expensive. Mostly&#xA;the price difference comes down to the &amp;ldquo;extraneous&amp;rdquo; features. Where this machine&#xA;falls down is in a few areas:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stitcher is (audio) podcasts done right</title>
      <link>/stitcher/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/stitcher/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just a quick post about a great application I&amp;rsquo;ve seen mentioned by&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://geekbeat.tv/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&gt;Cali Lewis&lt;/a&gt;:&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.stitcher.com/&#34;&gt;Stitcher&lt;/a&gt;. If your a talk radio fan like&#xA;me, you&amp;rsquo;ll really appreciate this app! Ever since I switched from an iPhone 4 to&#xA;a Galaxy S3 and stopped using Apple&amp;rsquo;s Podcast application it has been&#xA;frustrating to keep up to date with podcasts.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve used BeyondPod on Android (which I&amp;rsquo;ve praised before - excellent Google&#xA;Reader integration). I then tried to search for a third party podcast&#xA;application on the iPad that would synchronise with Google Reader. First there&#xA;were none, then some (like Feedler and Instacast) but all have been&#xA;bitterly disappointing with Google Reader integration. Instacast could&#xA;import OPML (after a messy bundling of feeds in Google Reader) and Feedler could&#xA;read the feeds (but not handle the video and audio contained within&#xA;the feed item properly). To be honest I&amp;rsquo;d given up hope, I said to myself I&amp;rsquo;d&#xA;chalk it up to fate and just buy a Nexus tablet when the iPad 2 was no longer&#xA;serviceable. But - happily - I was wrong and had been looking in the wrong&#xA;places&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First Experiences with an ARM Chromebook</title>
      <link>/first-experiences-with-arm-chromebook/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/first-experiences-with-arm-chromebook/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I  recently bought a&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B009LL9VDG/ref=as_li_qf_sp_asin_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B009LL9VDG&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=duefinsblo-20&#34;&gt;Samsung&#xA;Chromebook (Wi-Fi, 11.6-Inch)&lt;/a&gt;. I am fascinated by living tied to the web,&#xA;indeed my honours computer science thesis deals with this in relation to mobile&#xA;applications (and hybrid half-app/ half-website). Spurred on by the excellent&#xA;reviews this Chromebook has gotten (&amp;quot;&lt;i&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s $1,000 worth of design made with&#xA;$100 worth of materials&lt;/i&gt;&amp;quot; -&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theverge.com/2012/10/24/3549368/samsung-chromebook-review-series-3&#34;&gt;The&#xA;Verge&lt;/a&gt; and &amp;ldquo;&lt;i&gt;You simply won&amp;rsquo;t find a netbook this nice for that little&#xA;money.&lt;/i&gt;&amp;rdquo; -&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.engadget.com/2012/11/07/samsung-chromebook-review-2012/&#34;&gt;Engadget&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review of Steve Jobs Biography</title>
      <link>/review-of-steve-jobs-biography/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/review-of-steve-jobs-biography/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently finished reading Steve Jobs, the biography by Walter Isaacson. I&#xA;can&amp;rsquo;t add much more then the extensive coverage that it has recieved in the&#xA;press to date. Instead I paraphrase really badly a friend of mine, Noel Hudson:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;All that book thought me was dropping acid and treating people really badly&#xA;works as a life strategy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While that&amp;rsquo;s not entirely true it is a humourous look at the books tone. It has&#xA;a grain of truth, Walter Issacson really focuses on the warts and all&#xA;representation of Steve Jobs. He defines him very much in terms of how other&#xA;people percieved him, whether that should have been the mainstay of the book is&#xA;up for debate. Overall it&amp;rsquo;s a good book, what I liked most is the history&#xA;lessons of the creation of the mac and how the Disney/Pixar relationship went&#xA;down before the merger. I also felt Walter Issacson left it hanging at the end&#xA;and that he knows much more that he can&amp;rsquo;t publish due to Apple&amp;rsquo;s corporate&#xA;strategy being tied to Jobs so much (like the comment he made about cracking the&#xA;UI for a TV).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Notepad&#43;&#43;: A Great Windows Editor</title>
      <link>/notepad-a-great-windows-editor/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/notepad-a-great-windows-editor/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I spend a lot of my day in heavy development tools such as Eclipse&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, but&#xA;often for editing simple XML I just want a quick tool to make fast changes. If I&#xA;use the CLI (or Linux) it&amp;rsquo;ll be &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vim.org&#34;&gt;Vim&lt;/a&gt;, if I&amp;rsquo;m on Mac it&amp;rsquo;ll&#xA;be &lt;a href=&#34;http://macromates.com/&#34;&gt;Textmate&lt;/a&gt; but on Windows it&amp;rsquo;s&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://notepad-plus-plus.org/&#34;&gt;Notepad++&lt;/a&gt;. I haven&amp;rsquo;t found an editor on Windows&#xA;as clean as Notepad++ (if you use a tool professionally, you get to know it&amp;rsquo;s&#xA;quirks pretty fast) for editing text of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>@ACR884 Tech Slot #003 – eReaders</title>
      <link>/acr884-tech-slot-003/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/acr884-tech-slot-003/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our third slot on&#xA;&lt;a title=&#34;Athlone Community Radio&#34; href=&#34;http://athlonecommunityradio.ie/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Athlone&#xA;Community Radio&lt;/a&gt;. Aired the third Monday in January 2012 on ACR 88.4FM in&#xA;Athlone, Co. Westmeath, Ireland.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;topics-covered&#34;&gt;Topics Covered:&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kindle&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sony eReader&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this episode Patrick and Neil discuss the main players in the eBook market,&#xA;as well as what eBooks are and the advanatages and disadvantages.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Subscribe:&lt;/strong&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;//itunes.apple.com/ie/podcast//id494862406&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img title=&#34;iTunes Podcast Button&#34; src=&#34;http://dueyfinster.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/itunes_podcast.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Subscribe to ACR884 Tech Slot in iTunes!&#34; width=&#34;80&#34; height=&#34;15&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://feeds.feedburner.com/acr884tech&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://dueyfinster.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/podcast_rss_button.gif&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;audio controls=&#34;controls&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;source src=&#34;http://dueyfinster.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/technologyslot16-01-12.mp3&#34; type=&#34;audio/mp3&#34; /&gt;&#xA;  Your browser does not support the audio tag.&#xA;&lt;/audio&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Download Link:&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://dueyfinster.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/technologyslot16-01-12.mp3&#34;&gt;TechnologySlot16-01-12&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review of the Motorola Xoom Wifi</title>
      <link>/review-of-motorola-xoom-wifi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/review-of-motorola-xoom-wifi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently bought the wifi version of the Motorola Xoom. I did not get the 3G&#xA;version to keep costs down (no second carrier subscription in addition to&#xA;smartphone I own). Here&amp;rsquo;s my review, let it be noted I&amp;rsquo;ve been an iOS user since&#xA;version 2 (iPhone 3G) and although I have used devices from Android 1.6 and up -&#xA;I&amp;rsquo;ve never &amp;rsquo;lived&amp;rsquo; with them.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;../../files/2011/08/Mot_Xoom_Wiki_jeh.jpg&#34; title=&#34;Motorola Xoom&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../files/2011/08/Mot_Xoom_Wiki_jeh.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Motorola Xoom Tablet&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;figcaption&gt;Motorola Xoom&lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;aesthetics--design&#34;&gt;Aesthetics &amp;amp; Design&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;First of all the design is very well executed. It looks and feels like a premium&#xA;tablet should (should that be iPad competitor?). The ports are a clear winner&#xA;and still are over any other tablet. I haven&amp;rsquo;t got the video dock yet, but I&#xA;ampositiveit&amp;rsquo;ll be a great addition to my big HDTV. The only gripe really is&#xA;that it doesn&amp;rsquo;t charge through usb, which I believe is because it has two&#xA;batteries. It charges through supplied plug insanely fast! It lasts all day and&#xA;then some with heavy use also. I haven&amp;rsquo;t left the thing alone long enough to&#xA;test the standby time, but I am sure it&amp;rsquo;s good also. The 10.1&amp;quot; screen feels like&#xA;the &amp;lsquo;right&amp;rsquo; size for a tablet and I&amp;rsquo;ll besurprisedif more tablets don&amp;rsquo;t end up&#xA;adopting a screen size closer to the Xoom&amp;rsquo;s. The heft is a bit much, I would&#xA;like it to be a small bit lighter - but nearly all tablets with proper glass&#xA;screens will be heavy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Plantronics .655 USB Headset Review</title>
      <link>/usb-headset-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/usb-headset-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I got a Plantronics .655 USB Headset mainly for the ability to do VOIP well.&#xA;Those of you who come here often know &lt;a href=&#34;http://neil.grogan.ie/2011/03/review.html&#34;&gt;I reviewed Sennheiser HD595&#xA;before&lt;/a&gt;, which is a headset built for the quality of reproduction (I use&#xA;that one for music).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s not much you can say about a VOIP headset, so I am going to keep this&#xA;short! The Plantronics .655 USB isn&amp;rsquo;t the most comfortable headset and the usb&#xA;connection seemed like a plus as I&amp;rsquo;d never owned a USB headset. The mic quality&#xA;is a lot better with the USB connection (though I am guessing 90% is down to the&#xA;fact it&amp;rsquo;s directional and pointed at your mouth), but the sound won&amp;rsquo;t be.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tech Video Podcasts Worth Watching</title>
      <link>/tech-video-podcasts-worth-watching/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/tech-video-podcasts-worth-watching/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I try to listen to as many &lt;strike&gt;podcasts&lt;/strike&gt; (&lt;em&gt;netcasts?&lt;/em&gt;) as I can.&#xA;They fall in to two categories: Irish radio and technology. Luckily, there is so&#xA;much competition in this space it&amp;rsquo;s hard to pick the best - so quality is high!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tech News Today (TNT)&lt;/strong&gt; by the TWiT Network&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/embed/ZiOI7GbVhoY&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;allowfullscreen&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Regular and fills you right up to the minute with the latest tech news. Can&#xA;replace RSS of many blogs (HUGE time saver) since lively debate of tech topics&#xA;is the order of the day.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sennheiser HD595 Review</title>
      <link>/senn-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/senn-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;During last summer I purchased a set of Sennheiser HD595&amp;rsquo;s - a great product for&#xA;Audiophiles. I have to say for someone who constantly listens to a lot of&#xA;music - good headphones like these are a must. They are expensive for sure, but&#xA;Sennheiser do seem to have a great durability and solid build quality. This is&#xA;my first set of such high quality headphones, so bear that in mind - I can&amp;rsquo;t&#xA;speak for other manufacturers in this space.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>iPhone 4 Review</title>
      <link>/iphone4-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/iphone4-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I purchased the iPhone 4 shortly after its release in Summer 2010. I have&#xA;obviously been so quick to review this device, the iPhone 5 is upon us! My&#xA;philosophy for reviewing items is you &lt;strong&gt;have to live with them&lt;/strong&gt;. Well boy have&#xA;I lived with my iPhone 4! As I write this on it, I do marvel at how good the&#xA;hardware is. I&amp;rsquo;ve dropped this extremely expensive device on occasions &lt;i&gt;too&#xA;numerous to count&lt;/i&gt;, so luckily it is designed well.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Top Chrome Extensions</title>
      <link>/my-top-chrome-extensions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/my-top-chrome-extensions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Below I present some very useful extensions I use while using Google Chrome, in&#xA;no particular order.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/_Wq0iRacWX8o/TOpquOK6RLI/AAAAAAAAAlE/oGVd0x63zCc/s200/20001.png&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://chrome.google.com/extensions/detail/gighmmpiobklfepjocnamgkkbiglidom&#34;&gt;Adblock&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Blocks ads just like Firefox extension and makes the web less junky to look&#xA;at. You can whitelist good ads, and an argument could be had your harming&#xA;websites revenue stream, but a lot of nasty tricks such as spyware, malware&#xA;have used ads as a vector to spread. Not least the dishonesty some sites use&#xA;in splitting up articles in to 10 pages to pump ad revenue.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/_Wq0iRacWX8o/TOpsbEDdBMI/AAAAAAAAAlI/4yyhlRHjWN0/s1600/1001.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/_Wq0iRacWX8o/TOpsbEDdBMI/AAAAAAAAAlI/4yyhlRHjWN0/s200/1001.png&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://chrome.google.com/extensions/detail/flcpelgcagfhfoegekianiofphddckof&#34;&gt;KB SSL Enforcer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Garmin Zumo 660 Motorcycle GPS</title>
      <link>/motorcycle-gps/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/motorcycle-gps/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been over a week since I received my Garmin Zumo 660 Motorcycle GPS unit. I&#xA;thought I&amp;rsquo;d give it a run-down for potential buyers on my experience for the&#xA;first week. Firstly I should mention, I&amp;rsquo;ve never owned another Garmin unit, and&#xA;had two mobile GPS&amp;rsquo; units before (one being Nokia N800 with Bluetooth external&#xA;GPS and other Apple iPhone 3G). The reason I bring this up is that a lot of the&#xA;reviews I&amp;rsquo;ve seen written compare it to it&amp;rsquo;s predecessor, Zumo 550, which&#xA;obviously I can&amp;rsquo;t do.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Honda Bros Motorcycle</title>
      <link>/honda-bros-motorcycle/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/honda-bros-motorcycle/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently purchased - known as a&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://books.google.com/books?id=O_YDAAAAMBAJ&amp;amp;pg=PT23&#34;&gt;cult motorbike&lt;/a&gt; - a&#xA;Honda BROS (known in the US as a HawkGT). It is a 400cc V-Twin 1991 model, with&#xA;33BHP / 24.6Kw out of the factory. That put&amp;rsquo;s it under the legal limit for a&#xA;learner motorcycle in the A category of license in Ireland. I&amp;rsquo;ve been&#xA;progressing through bikes, slowly gaining confidence and experience. I posted&#xA;about my &lt;a href=&#34;../../2008/09/yamaha-yq-aerox-best-moped-ever.html&#34;&gt;Yamaha YQ50&lt;/a&gt;, My&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;../../2009/12/yamaha-majesty-400c-review.html&#34;&gt;Yamaha YP125 (Majesty)&lt;/a&gt; and now it&amp;rsquo;s&#xA;a Honda BROS&amp;rsquo; turn!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Yamaha Majesty 400c Review</title>
      <link>/yamaha-majesty-400c-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/yamaha-majesty-400c-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I own a Majesty 125cc 2002. The video below is the updated (and more powerful)&#xA;model:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(Some of the) New features:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2x the amount of space&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Parking break (for hills! Think handbrake if your a car driver)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Liquid-cooled 400cc&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;ABS brakes&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Dual Halogen Headlights&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Larger rear lights&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Csr-like oversize dials on dash&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It looks good, good, good. I haven&amp;rsquo;t looked at price, but my last two bikes are&#xA;Yamaha and I&amp;rsquo;ve had little trouble with them. I like the bigger bikes that have&#xA;loads of built in storage (panniers look a bit unnatural) and a bike that&amp;rsquo;s&#xA;confident in itself to not have to show off it&amp;rsquo;s braun but rather it&amp;rsquo;s brains&#xA;with good safety and road handling ;)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>iPhone 3G Review</title>
      <link>/iphone-3g-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/iphone-3g-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently got an iPhone 3G and away from all that Apple mania; I thought I&#xA;would give an honest review. This is framed in the mindset of all the past Nokia&#xA;devices (which I have posted about here also) which I have owned.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Okay so where to start? Well I think a good place would be what I could have&#xA;bought instead. Strange place for a review; but its good to see what is out&#xA;there and what I was looking at beforehand.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>KDE 4.2 Beta 2</title>
      <link>/beta-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/beta-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently I downloaded the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kubuntu.org/&#34;&gt;Kubuntu&lt;/a&gt; packages of the new&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kde.org/&#34;&gt;KDE&lt;/a&gt; 4.2 beta 2. For those of you who don&amp;rsquo;t know; KDE is&#xA;the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kde.org/&#34;&gt;K Desktop Environment&lt;/a&gt;; which includes a window&#xA;manager (&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kwin&#34;&gt;KWin&lt;/a&gt;), common desktop&#xA;applications, its own menu&#xA;(&lt;a href=&#34;http://home.kde.org/~binner/kickoff/sneak_preview.html&#34;&gt;Kickoff&lt;/a&gt;), browser&#xA;(&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.konqueror.org/&#34;&gt;Konqueror&lt;/a&gt;), file manager&#xA;(&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dolphin_(software)&#34;&gt;dolphin&lt;/a&gt;) etc. Basically it&#xA;is the most popular desktop environment on Linux next to&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/GNOME&#34;&gt;Gnome&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://kde.org/announcements/announce_4.2-beta1/desktop_thumb.png&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&#xA;*KDE 4.2 Beta 2 with Kickoff Menu visible&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;**What is so special about KDE? **&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The philosophy of KDE is the advanced configuration it allows through its&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/GUI&#34;&gt;Graphical User Interface&lt;/a&gt; (GUI), this is&#xA;versus &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gnome.org/&#34;&gt;Gnome&lt;/a&gt; which chooses sane defaults and leaves&#xA;configuration in hard to reach places and out-of-sight. This isn&amp;rsquo;t to say KDE&#xA;doesn&amp;rsquo;t choose sane defaults; it does and is very user-friendly. KDE has&#xA;always been the more Windows-like of the major desktop environments and this&#xA;hasn&amp;rsquo;t really changed in KDE 4.X series. KDE is available in popular&#xA;distributions of Linux such as Kubuntu, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mandriva.com/&#34;&gt;Mandriva&lt;/a&gt;,&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.opensuse.org/en/&#34;&gt;OpenSuse&lt;/a&gt;. The special part about 4.X series is&#xA;that for the first time for any Linux desktop environment; it is fully&#xA;cross-platform, easily installs and works on Microsoft Windows and Apple Mac&#xA;OS X.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://kde.org/announcements/announce_4.2-beta2/panel.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://kde.org/announcements/announce_4.2-beta2/panel_thumb.png&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;KDE 4.2 Panel; with KOrganizer calendar open&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Profiling Firefox Extensions I have installed</title>
      <link>/profiling-firefox-extensions-i-have/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/profiling-firefox-extensions-i-have/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;My Current Firefox Extensions: A-Z*&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;../../img/08/74.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../img/08/74.png&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/1865&#34;&gt;Adblock Plus&lt;/a&gt;; because&#xA;ads are for people that don&amp;rsquo;t know how to avoid them! Not only do they stop&#xA;your banwidth from being wasted; they make a ton of websites more usuable. It&#xA;takes care of Flash Ads as well as static ones; using a filter that is&#xA;constantly updated. So even if some of the webs more devious and sneaky&#xA;advertisers try to circumvent it; AdBlock can have a fix to everyone online&#xA;within hours. It is definately my favourite extension! I don&amp;rsquo;t block certain&#xA;ads like Google, Yahoo, Microsoft (the ones with decent reputations) as that&#xA;is how the people behind really good websites I frequent make a living. But&#xA;for all the rest trying to do pop-ups and pop-unders; I am sorry your days are&#xA;numbered! (Some people higly recommend&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/433&#34;&gt;flashblock&lt;/a&gt; but I haven&amp;rsquo;t&#xA;had a need to use it with AdBlock Plus yet).&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;../../img/08/943948800.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../img/08/943948800.png&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/743&#34;&gt;CustomizeGoogle&lt;/a&gt; adds neat&#xA;tricks to Google services such as always using a secure connection to Gmail;&#xA;links to other search engines, page histories, Favicons to search and streaming&#xA;results pages. Comes in handy once in a while; but I don&amp;rsquo;t use it daily.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Yamaha YQ Aerox - best moped ever?</title>
      <link>/yamaha-yq-aerox-best-moped-ever/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/yamaha-yq-aerox-best-moped-ever/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well I think so! Got one there 2 months ago and forgot to write a blog post&#xA;about it. I got a &amp;lsquo;01 model for a bargain price I believe; but this theory has&#xA;yet to be tested (I&amp;rsquo;ll wait for a year to be up). As I mentioned before in&#xA;previous posts my parent&amp;rsquo;s house is now in a remote location with no train/buses&#xA;anywhere nearby. So transport was essential! At this time also there was a major&#xA;crack down on learner drivers not being accompanied by a fully licensed driver&#xA;(of two years). So by the time I&amp;rsquo;d saved the money for the car; got 10 lessons&#xA;and convinced anyone I knew with over two years full driving experience to&#xA;accompany me; even to work - was just to much hassle - hence the moped which has&#xA;no such onerous requirements. In fact only one it does really have is that you&#xA;can&amp;rsquo;t have passengers - I won&amp;rsquo;t be carrying anyone anyways - so I am not too&#xA;bothered. Anyhoo take a look at the photos I took when I got it. I have done it&#xA;up since then: new tyres, resprayed exhaust, full service; new mirrors; repaired&#xA;exhaust; flushed out radiator and put in proper coolant just to name a few. So&#xA;it sounds allot better and drives better than ever!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why I think Amarok rocks....</title>
      <link>/why-i-think-amarock-rocks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/why-i-think-amarock-rocks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I just purchased an&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://49100.spreadshirt.net/en/DE/Shop/Article/Index/article/Amarok-Hoodie-Navy-1117657&#34;&gt;Amarok hoodie&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;and&lt;a href=&#34;http://49100.spreadshirt.net/en/DE/Shop/Article/Index/article/Amarok-Classic-Sports-Tee-1094948&#34;&gt;t-shirt&lt;/a&gt;;&#xA;and I couldn&amp;rsquo;t be happier supporting one of my favourite open source projects!&#xA;What makes it so good? Have you ever heard of Amarok? Chances are if your an OS&#xA;X or Windows user; you haven&amp;rsquo;t. All this is about to change! The amarok team are&#xA;busy porting it from it&amp;rsquo;s UNIX underpinnings to Windows and OS X.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://amarok.kde.org/features&#34;&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Whats to like about Amarok then?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://rokymotion.pwsp.net/promowiki/images/1/18/Amarok_Features-covers.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://rokymotion.pwsp.net/promowiki/images/1/18/Amarok_Features-covers.png&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;also is cool phonetically: am a rock!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A few days with A Nokia N810</title>
      <link>/few-days-with-nokia-n810/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jan 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/few-days-with-nokia-n810/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;../../img/08/HPIM0193.JPG&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../img/08/HPIM0193.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;../../tablet-to-hit-shops-soon&#34;&gt;I last discussed the Nokia N810 Internet Tablet in October&lt;/a&gt;;&#xA;when details were only starting to filter out. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t expected for Nokia to&#xA;introduce an upgrade to the&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;../../nokia-n800&#34;&gt;N800 Internet Tablet (which I also reviewed here)&lt;/a&gt; so soon. I&#xA;certainly don&amp;rsquo;t envy the position of a small team getting the hardware and&#xA;software for a mini-computer right in such a short space of time. But needless&#xA;to say the N810 feels right; in fact it feels more right than the N770 which I&#xA;thought had the best design of all (be it functionality not so much style). The&#xA;N810 has bags of style; in a flashy brand-new-car sort of way; it looks&#xA;expensive and I believe Nokia plays to this in their pricing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nokia N810 Tablet to hit the shops soon...</title>
      <link>/tablet-to-hit-shops-soon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Oct 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/tablet-to-hit-shops-soon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nokia have announced an upgrade to the N800 Internet tablet, called the N810. I&#xA;suspect its called that because it is more of an incremental upgrade than a&#xA;total visual refresh it was going from an Nokia 770 to N800. Here it is:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;../../img/07/n810gps.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../img/07/n810gps.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(Picture Courtesy:&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.internettablettalk.com/2007/10/17/the-nokia-n810-internet-tablet/&#34;&gt;Internet Tablet Talk&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It sports a nice new hardware keyboard; inbuilt GPS (For satellite mapping) and&#xA;OS 2008 (an upgrade to the operating system it runs). The N800 will also benefit&#xA;from OS 2008, which will include GoogleTalk, Skype, Mozilla browser, among the&#xA;usual such as its email client, media player, file manager, control panel,&#xA;assorted games and an image/PDF viewer. The one feature it will emit is an&#xA;inbuilt FM Radio, which was axed to make the N810 a smaller tablet. It still&#xA;retains the best screen size for web browsing, bluetooth connectivity, and of&#xA;course Wifi which is central to the tablets existance! No word on what easter&#xA;eggs are included if any; on the N800 it was a radio and the N770 it was the&#xA;microphone.&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.engadget.com/2007/10/17/nokia-n810-hands-on/&#34;&gt;Engadget has a great writeup on it&lt;/a&gt;,&#xA;choc-a-bloc full of high resolution photos with size comparisons to Apples&#xA;iPhone.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review of the Official Ubuntu Book, Second Edition (2007)</title>
      <link>/review-of-official-ubuntu-book-second/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/review-of-official-ubuntu-book-second/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ec1.images-amazon.com/images/I/51tftxZawYL._SS500_.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://ec1.images-amazon.com/images/I/51tftxZawYL._SS500_.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;The&#xA;Ubuntu Book (2nd Edition) is a nicely put together book for dealing with the&#xA;Linux operating system in a number of clearly laid out and well presented&#xA;chapters. Chapters are as follows:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Introducing Ubuntu&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Installing Ubuntu&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Using Ubuntu on the Desktop&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Advanced Usage and Managing Ubuntu&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ubuntu Server&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Support / Typical Problems&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Using Kubuntu&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ubuntu Community&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ubuntu-Related Projects&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Using Edubuntu&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This book is a very complete introduction and contains suprising elements&#xA;related to finding out and joining the community of users - which you will not&#xA;find in other Ubuntu Books (such as O&amp;rsquo;Reilly&amp;rsquo;s Ubuntu Hacks) which make it a&#xA;unique and worthwhile addition to any Ubuntu users personal library. It is most&#xA;helpful to new users to Ubuntu, which sections on installing and help with&#xA;problems that could be faced. Having said that, it falls short on the amount of&#xA;truly unique information that it contains - most of the books contents can be&#xA;found on the web. What you are paying for is a well-laid out, well written&#xA;account of the Ubuntu-sphere and all that goes along with it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HP Photosmart R927 Review</title>
      <link>/hp-photosmart-r927/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/hp-photosmart-r927/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I just bought a HP Photosmart R927, an 8 Megapixel camera from Hewlett-Packard.&#xA;While I had seen and briefly used one before, I was excited again upon using my&#xA;own one (as all tech people are [read: geeks]). First of all don&amp;rsquo;t confuse me as&#xA;anyway into photography: I&amp;rsquo;m not and far from it. I had a criteria in mind when I&#xA;purchased and this was it:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Must work under any OS (Windows [a given], Mac and Linux [latter two I only use])&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Every camera I have come across mounts as a disc drive [think looking at&#xA;files on a cd or your local computer], but there is also PTP or &amp;ldquo;Picture&#xA;Transfer Protocol&amp;rdquo; in other words it doesn&amp;rsquo;t appear as picture files, rather PTP&#xA;triggers your computer to open your camera in your photo application. I was&#xA;unsure if this PTP would work under Mac or Linux, since I had only briefly seen&#xA;it as an option in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.digikam.org/&#34;&gt;digiKam&lt;/a&gt;. It turns out on Mac there&#xA;is &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apple.com/macosx/features/imagecapture/&#34;&gt;Image Capture&lt;/a&gt;, and&#xA;Ubuntu (My Linux distribution of choice) it automatically detects it and asks to&#xA;import photos into&lt;a href=&#34;http://f-spot.org/&#34;&gt;F-Spot&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Top 10 Applications of 2007</title>
      <link>/applications-of-2007/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/applications-of-2007/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a few items I&amp;rsquo;d like to share with everyone as I find them extremely&#xA;useful, hopefully you will too, thats if you have never used them! My Top 10&#xA;Apps of 2007 in descending order:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10.&lt;/strong&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.safer-networking.org/&#34; title=&#34;Spybot Search and Destroy&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Spybot Search and Destroy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Always a must on spyware infested Windows XP installs I come across&#xA;(Unfortunately all to often). It removes a lot of the bad stuff, and my most&#xA;used feature is system startup section, as I can stop all that crud from&#xA;loading and slowing everything to a crawl.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apple.com/itunes/&#34; title=&#34;iTunes&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;iTunes&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (OS X Version)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nokia N800 Review</title>
      <link>/nokia-n800/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/nokia-n800/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://img76.imageshack.us/my.php?image=nokian800internettabletdn5.jpg&#34; title=&#34;Hosted Kindly by Imageshack&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://img76.imageshack.us/img76/8830/nokian800internettabletdn5.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Nokia&#xA;N800&#34; title=&#34;Nokia N800&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;I&#xA;have one of those new&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://europe.nokia.com/phones/n800&#34; title=&#34;Nokia N800 Internet Tablet&#34;&gt;Nokia N800 Internet Tablet&lt;/a&gt;,&#xA;as many of you know I was one of the first to buy its predecessor, the Nokia 770&#xA;Internet Tablet. What do I think? Well I have put of writing this for 4 days, as&#xA;I wanted to really test it out. Before I start, I should say I was part of the&#xA;Nokia Developer Device program, and I got the Nokia N800 at a big discount, €300&#xA;off the €399 retail price in fact. Under headings below I will take about the&#xA;N800, and compare it to the 770:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nokia 6234 Video Test</title>
      <link>/video-test/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/video-test/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently got a hold of my Christmas present in advance, a new Nokia 6234 from&#xA;Vodafone Ireland. I did a short video test, maybe this could be the start of my&#xA;VideoBlogging career:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Well maybe not! But I do hope to have more videos on my blog! The video is of me&#xA;describing my living quarters and about my laptop. I needed to be a bit closer&#xA;to the phone as hearing me is difficult sometimes (not so in real life!), but&#xA;basically I just point out what you see and explain the phone won&amp;rsquo;t sync&#xA;address+calendar with my macbook :-( (My old phone did just that :-) ). I don&amp;rsquo;t&#xA;really mind, bluetooth works a charm and I can exchange files between it. All I&#xA;need now is a super 2GB mini memory card, for some quick music on the go!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best Radio Podcasts</title>
      <link>/best-radio-podcasts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/best-radio-podcasts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Even while podcasts are relatively new (well a couple of years - like blogs),&#xA;Irish Radio Stations are surprisingly well in on the act. Even our incumbent&#xA;state broadcaster, RTE, is podcasting en-masse on both RTE Radio 1 and RTE 2FM.&#xA;To recieve podcasts, you need podcasting software, start by getting&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://juicereceiver.sourceforge.net/index.php&#34;&gt;Juice Reciever&lt;/a&gt;(Formerly&#xA;iPodder), available for Linux, BSD, MAC and Windows. I will start with my top 5&#xA;Irish Radio podcasts:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Just Klik it!</title>
      <link>/just-klik-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/just-klik-it/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest complaints of Linux is that software doesn’t install to well,&#xA;or is very difficult to install. “Dependency Hell” (When software relies on&#xA;other bits of software to work), used to be quite commonplace. Ubuntu has&#xA;cleaned a lot of dependency hell up, and a new program for installing software&#xA;from the internet, is included in the new version, due to be released 1st&#xA;June 2006.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;That’s when I discovered a little gem called &lt;a href=&#34;http://klik.atekon.de/&#34; title=&#34;Klik it!&#34;&gt;Klik&lt;/a&gt; for many Linux&#xA;distributions. Simply lookup the piece of software you need, click on it and you&#xA;have it! No need to install! It places the whole program on the desktop, so it&#xA;is easily deletable and easily transferable. For example, if you have an office&#xA;application, and your friend doesn’t, simply copy that file on desktop to your&#xA;usb key or a cd, and copy to friends pc, done and dusted - Your friend has the&#xA;whole application! This is an obvious feature bonus over current Windows&#xA;version, XP.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nokia 770 Internet Tablet</title>
      <link>/internet-tablet/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/internet-tablet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I got it! UPS delivered the Nokia 770 Internet Tablet. What can I say? It is&#xA;pure magic! The features are great, it includes:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Web Browser (Opera)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Flash Player version 6&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Email Client&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Internet Radio&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;News Reader&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Media players, Image viewer&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;PDF viewer&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;File Manager&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Search&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Calculator&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;World Clock&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Notes&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sketch&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Games&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It runs on Linux, making it totally extendable. It even has its own developer&#xA;site at maemo.org, where applications can be downloaded. Hot on my list were&#xA;Doom (the Game) and GAIM (Instant Messenger, uses Google Talk, AOL, MSN, Yahoo,&#xA;Jabber, IRC, etc). Unfortunately their is no Skype for Nokia 770 just yet, but&#xA;hopefully it will be here soon. Nokia has promised an upgrade in 2006, that will&#xA;include VOIP, such as skype.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
