<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>linux on Neil Grogan</title><link>https://www.neilgrogan.com/tags/linux/</link><description>Recent content in linux on Neil Grogan</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.neilgrogan.com/tags/linux/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Linux Desktop has a place</title><link>https://www.neilgrogan.com/the-linux-desktop-has-place/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.neilgrogan.com/the-linux-desktop-has-place/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve seen an article by Miguel de Icaza, a great developer oft criticised for his love of Microsoft technologies on Linux. His latest piece is about his love for Mac OS X as a desktop and how he used to feel guilty about it (given his very impressive open source credentials).
I used to feel the same also. Android even as a platform more closely follows my ideals, yet I am exclusively an avid iOS user at this point.</description></item><item><title>Faster with Arch</title><link>https://www.neilgrogan.com/faster-with-arch/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.neilgrogan.com/faster-with-arch/</guid><description>I have recently switched my main desktop over to Arch Linux. If you have never heard about Arch Linux, it is a &amp;ldquo;roll your own&amp;rdquo; Linux distribution. This basically means from start to finish, the whole process is custom. Whether your system has a Graphical User Interface (GUI) or sound is totally up to you.
I switched from Ubuntu Linux, which is very much built for new people to Linux. I have been using Ubuntu since it&amp;rsquo;s release in 2004 (as old as this blog incidentally).</description></item><item><title>Best KDE/Linux?</title><link>https://www.neilgrogan.com/best-kdelinux/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.neilgrogan.com/best-kdelinux/</guid><description>via tuxradar.com For me it&amp;rsquo;s definitely Kubuntu, but I can see why they choose OpenSuSe. May I just mention the virtual machine builder system is awesome, pay attention Mr.Shuttleworth! Although PPA builds come a close second for useful online tools&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>HP to Follow Dell into Open Source? and Ubuntu Home Server</title><link>https://www.neilgrogan.com/hp-to-follow-dell-into-open-source/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Jul 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.neilgrogan.com/hp-to-follow-dell-into-open-source/</guid><description>HP it seems is responding to Dell&amp;rsquo;s initiative to sell Ubuntu on their computers. With the Ubuntu Dells reportedly selling very well and Dell rolling out the program worldwide, this hasn&amp;rsquo;t escaped the notice of the world&amp;rsquo;s number one computer manufacturer - HP. This is speculation from blogs that has been going on for months since Dell started to offer Ubuntu. The Direct to Dell Blog states:
This recent post from Tom Dryer caught my eye a couple of days ago, and thought I&amp;rsquo;d comment on it here.</description></item><item><title>In Sickness and in Health!</title><link>https://www.neilgrogan.com/in-sickness-and-in-health/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.neilgrogan.com/in-sickness-and-in-health/</guid><description>I have a throat infection, so I get a week off!! I went to the doctor and I am on vibramycin antibiotics. I was coughing blood (not nearly as nasty as it sounds). Now I can get some relaxation in before Christmas!! I hope to do a guide to restricted formats on Ubuntu soon, especially W32 Codecs and how to get all the good formats it offers (Divx, MPEG1-4, Windows Media, Quicktime Media and RealMedia)</description></item></channel></rss>