<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>linux on Neil Grogan</title>
    <link>/tags/linux/</link>
    <description>Recent content in linux on Neil Grogan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Why GNU Grep is fast</title>
      <link>/grep-fast/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/grep-fast/</guid>
      <description>Worth a read for those wishing to optimise programs that process a lot of data. It proves that less really is more&amp;hellip;
Money quote:
 The key to making programs fast is to make them do practically nothing.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fish Shell for Ubuntu and OS X</title>
      <link>/fish-shell/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/fish-shell/</guid>
      <description>A great guide to get up to speed with Fish shell. What is Fish? It&amp;rsquo;s a shell written from the ground up to be more easily understandable the the traditional shells (bash, tcsh). I don&amp;rsquo;t know yet if I&amp;rsquo;ll switch (anything you can do in Fish can be made to work in Bash). It&amp;rsquo;s an interesting concept and I&amp;rsquo;ll try it for a while&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SSH Config Aliases</title>
      <link>/ssh-config/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/ssh-config/</guid>
      <description>If your like me and you deal with a lot of servers for development or test and do it from a Unix machine, I&amp;rsquo;ve got a really handy tip: SSH hostname pattern matching.
Say I&amp;rsquo;ve got a SSH config file like this (at ~/.ssh/config ):
host s* HostName atrcu%h.example.com User example1 Port 22 host b* HostName atrcx%h.example.com User example2 Port 22 host ??* HostName atvts%h.example.com User example5 Port 2205  The ssh man page explains this really well:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Custom Colourful Bash Prompt</title>
      <link>/colour-bash/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/colour-bash/</guid>
      <description>Bash, a command line shell is one of the most used pieces of software in my daily work. I like scripting repetitive actions to save a lot time (it brings me great joy!). One of the simplest and easiest customisations is to add a bit of colour to your otherwise boring bash prompt (otherwise known as $PS1):
[ngrogan@localhost:~]$  can be turned in to this:
The thing about Bash is the colour codes to achieve this can look archaic:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Linux Desktop has a place</title>
      <link>/the-linux-desktop-has-place/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/the-linux-desktop-has-place/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve seen an article by Miguel de Icaza, a great developer oft criticised for his love of Microsoft technologies on Linux. His latest piece is about his love for Mac OS X as a desktop and how he used to feel guilty about it (given his very impressive open source credentials).
I used to feel the same also. Android even as a platform more closely follows my ideals, yet I am exclusively an avid iOS user at this point.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Record your terminal session</title>
      <link>/record-your-terminal-session/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/record-your-terminal-session/</guid>
      <description>As I&amp;rsquo;ve mentioned before1, I regularly watch technology podcasts and I&amp;rsquo;ve had a subscription to sites like Lynda.com. Between those and Youtube, I&amp;rsquo;ve watched an awful lot of technology how-to videos and 90% of them are quite poor in terms of editing, sound and being coherent/properly scripted. Sometimes though it&amp;rsquo;s a joy to genuinely learn something new in a short, concise and to the point video.
 This haktip is right up there with being among the best: short, concise, to the point and about a utility that will be super-useful to me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Faster with Arch</title>
      <link>/faster-with-arch/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/faster-with-arch/</guid>
      <description>I have recently switched my main desktop over to Arch Linux. If you have never heard about Arch Linux, it is a &amp;ldquo;roll your own&amp;rdquo; Linux distribution. This basically means from start to finish, the whole process is custom. Whether your system has a Graphical User Interface (GUI) or sound is totally up to you.
I switched from Ubuntu Linux, which is very much built for new people to Linux. I have been using Ubuntu since it&amp;rsquo;s release in 2004 (as old as this blog incidentally).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best KDE/Linux?</title>
      <link>/best-kdelinux/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/best-kdelinux/</guid>
      <description>via tuxradar.com For me it&amp;rsquo;s definitely Kubuntu, but I can see why they choose OpenSuSe. May I just mention the virtual machine builder system is awesome, pay attention Mr.Shuttleworth! Although PPA builds come a close second for useful online tools&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linux Desktop Environments?</title>
      <link>/linux-desktop-environments/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/linux-desktop-environments/</guid>
      <description>What are Desktop Environments? Wikipedia defines it as:
 In graphical computing, a desktop environment (DE) commonly refers to a style of graphical user interface &amp;hellip;&amp;hellip; A desktop environment typically consists of icons, windows, toolbars, folders, wallpapers, and desktop widgets. (See WIMP.)
 I would add a file manager and browser to this list also! Let&amp;rsquo;s look at the two most popular consumer Operating Systems (in three variants) and their Desktop Environments:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu in four years</title>
      <link>/ubuntu-in-four-years/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/ubuntu-in-four-years/</guid>
      <description>Last year was me celebrating four years of using the best operating system out there: Linux and the best distro Ubuntu. Ubuntu was my first foray in to Linux; and I haven&amp;rsquo;t left it since; although I have tried all the other major distros. I started with the first version of Ubuntu; Warthy Warthog:
Warthy had a text only installer and it took me quite a while to not only get used to the idea of this strange operating system; but the fear of leaving Windows-land where all that power usage knowledge would mean nothing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KDE 4.2 Beta 2</title>
      <link>/beta-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/beta-2/</guid>
      <description>Recently I downloaded the Kubuntu packages of the new KDE 4.2 beta 2. For those of you who don&amp;rsquo;t know; KDE is the K Desktop Environment; which includes a window manager (KWin), common desktop applications, its own menu (Kickoff), browser (Konqueror), file manager (dolphin) etc. Basically it is the most popular desktop environment on Linux next to Gnome.
*KDE 4.2 Beta 2 with Kickoff Menu visible
   **What is so special about KDE?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linux and Patents: Just Patently Wrong</title>
      <link>/linux-and-patents-just-patently-wrong/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/linux-and-patents-just-patently-wrong/</guid>
      <description>So I read the news Novell and Red Hat are being sued for patent infringement. This is all about multiple workspaces that can hold various graphical user elements, a Xerox Parc patent which dates to the early 1990&amp;rsquo;s. Xerox Palo Alto Research center invented the graphical user interface in the 1980&amp;rsquo;s, only to been, licensed and used by Steve Jobs in Mac OS Classic. Now IP Innovation, a submarine patent troll, who make no products and bought the patent want their payday.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gutsy coming along, Update to Dell Windows Refund..</title>
      <link>/gutsy-coming-along-update-to-dell/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/gutsy-coming-along-update-to-dell/</guid>
      <description>I just tried Herd 5 of Gutsy Gibbon, a beta release which will be Ubuntu 07.10 released in October. Obviously it is still early stages and a lot of things aren&amp;rsquo;t working quite as they should, but it looks very promising. Here&amp;rsquo;s some new stuff which should hit the final release:
 Compiz Fusion - Pretty Graphics that leave you in awe&amp;hellip; Bullet Proof X - Making sure you&amp;rsquo;ll never see a terminal prompt not of your own choosing, basically the graphics server should be &amp;lsquo;bulletproof&amp;rsquo; Appearance Manager - Making it easier to change yourbuntu&amp;rsquo;s look and feel Better Driver Support - More of those restricted drivers to make sure you can see your screen and use your wifi card Simplified Codecs install - It will now be painless, install ubuntu-restrictedcodecs (or kubuntu-restricted codecs) and you can see Youtube in all its glory, play a dvd, watch that porno WMV file (just kidding but I think thats all WMV is used for) and other such niceties of the propreitry world we have to put up with Firefox Codecs Plugin - Firefox will be hooked up to the package manager and prompt to install Flash/Java if you haven&amp;rsquo;t got it already, much the same way it prompts to get a codec when you throw a file at it that it cannot play in the movie player.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dell refunds me for Windows!</title>
      <link>/dell-refunds-me-for-windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/dell-refunds-me-for-windows/</guid>
      <description>As many of you know I am a Linux and Mac aficionado. For my Linux machines, all of them are Dell. I have been always pleased with Dells prices, how their machines work with Linux, their customer service and the fact they are made in Limerick, Ireland (I am from Ireland). I politely emailed Dell (well got up on my high horse), heres my first mail:
 I would like a refund of Windows XP since I am installing Ubuntu Linux on the computer when I get it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HP to Follow Dell into Open Source? and Ubuntu Home Server</title>
      <link>/hp-to-follow-dell-into-open-source/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jul 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/hp-to-follow-dell-into-open-source/</guid>
      <description>HP it seems is responding to Dell&amp;rsquo;s initiative to sell Ubuntu on their computers. With the Ubuntu Dells reportedly selling very well and Dell rolling out the program worldwide, this hasn&amp;rsquo;t escaped the notice of the world&amp;rsquo;s number one computer manufacturer - HP. This is speculation from blogs that has been going on for months since Dell started to offer Ubuntu. The Direct to Dell Blog states:
 This recent post from Tom Dryer caught my eye a couple of days ago, and thought I&amp;rsquo;d comment on it here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Windows Vista Security - Better than Linux?</title>
      <link>/windows-vista-security-better-than/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jul 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/windows-vista-security-better-than/</guid>
      <description>After reading a nice article written by Jeff Jones, a security researcher for Microsoft. He says he isn&amp;rsquo;t biased, saying he worked over 75% of his career outside Microsoft, using Slackware Linux, Unix, HP Unix etc. He claims Windows Vista has less security holes than popular versions of Linux, such as Ubuntu (he also compares Red Hat, Novell, Mac OS X). First let me say why his facts are distorted, and why he knows his facts are distorted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dell Sells Ubuntu 7.04</title>
      <link>/dell-sells-ubuntu-704/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 May 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/dell-sells-ubuntu-704/</guid>
      <description>Dell Computers has started selling Ubuntu Linux 7.04 on consumer machines in the United States. This can only be good news, as a supporter of Linux since late 2004/early 2005 I am fully behind this initiative to put Linux as a choice in front of people who buy computers. They are testing the market at the moment which explains why they are shipping stock drivers with the hardware, and no multimedia codecs (which is unfortunate, but understandable that this deal was done in 60 days).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ultimate Games Disc</title>
      <link>/ultimate-games-disc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/ultimate-games-disc/</guid>
      <description>I got inspiration over this past Easter holidays, being bored, I gave Linux Gaming a shot. I am not much of a gamer myself and most websites aren&amp;rsquo;t very helpful or have too small a focus (only shoot-em-ups, or only certain Linux distros etc.). Inspired by the fine folks at OpenSourceMac.org and OpenSourceWindows.org, I announce my own project: Ultimate Games Disc. UGD is a project I think I can make very successful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vista is released; Ubuntu gets .exe!</title>
      <link>/vista-is-released-ubuntu-gets-exe/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/vista-is-released-ubuntu-gets-exe/</guid>
      <description>Well as I write this it is a few days after Vista&amp;rsquo;s launch, and it has yet to set the software market alight. But this is nothing new, it happend with XP. How do you convince people the latest and greatest is worth the money? Microsoft is in a tough position due to stiff competition - old, working, fully-compatible windows machines don&amp;rsquo;t disappear into thin air. There has been a lot more FUD (Fear Uncertainty and Doubt)abput Vista already from the Free and Open Source camp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BBC to host Multi-OS Debate and My First Web Auction</title>
      <link>/bbc-to-host-multi-os-debate-my-first/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/bbc-to-host-multi-os-debate-my-first/</guid>
      <description>BBC are putting together a Mac, Windows and Linux user, to debate the pros and cons of being a users for each operating system. While this in itself is good news (more airtime for alternatives), most of the comments are highly in favour of Linux, then Mac and lastly Windows. This is part of the BBC&amp;rsquo;s coverage of Windows Vista. My hope for the future is that Mac and Linux gain at least 10% each (20% total) over the next 5 years of the home desktop market, as this will push innovation forward, like AMD and Intel competition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Widget for our RSS feed!</title>
      <link>/new-widget-for-our-rss-feed/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/new-widget-for-our-rss-feed/</guid>
      <description>Thanks to Dashcode, the tool for making dashboard widgets, there is now an RSS one for this site! Currently it only works on Mac OS X, but KDE 4 should support dashboard widgets (they are really just bits of javascript, css and html).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Video iPod and Freespire</title>
      <link>/video-ipod-and-freespire/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/video-ipod-and-freespire/</guid>
      <description>Well I guess you can call me a hardcore Apple Computer fan, I have a Macbook, an iPod Nano (1st Gen 4GB) and now a 80GB iPod Video! I bought i for a couple of reasons, namely price and storage. I had been put off before since I thought they were too bulky ( I know a couple of people who have older generation iPod Videos) after being with the Nano for over a year (its still chugging along gleefully).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I am getting an Apple MacBook</title>
      <link>/feel-i-need-to-confess-why-i-am-buying/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/feel-i-need-to-confess-why-i-am-buying/</guid>
      <description>I feel I need to confess why I am buying a MacBook, have I turned soft to my Open Source/Free Software ways? No, definately 100% NOT. I’ll explain why: I think Apple Computer has an incredible product in Mac OSx. For anyone who has not used it before, pop into a 3G store and ask to have a go. When someone releases a good a product as that, they deserve money, in my opinion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Just Klik it!</title>
      <link>/just-klik-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/just-klik-it/</guid>
      <description>One of the biggest complaints of Linux is that software doesn’t install to well, or is very difficult to install. “Dependency Hell” (When software relies on other bits of software to work), used to be quite commonplace. Ubuntu has cleaned a lot of dependency hell up, and a new program for installing software from the internet, is included in the new version, due to be released 1st June 2006.
That’s when I discovered a little gem called Klik for many Linux distributions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtual Ubuntu</title>
      <link>/virtual-ubuntu/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/virtual-ubuntu/</guid>
      <description>So you have heard of Ubuntu, maybe they have even shipped you a free disc or you have downloaded one? Like most users, even advanced PC users, they get nervous about installing Linux and afraid of what they might have to learn. Touted as the brighest star, Ubuntu really does outshine other Linuxes, with usability, features and great range of software. Now you can try Ubuntu on Windows.
How can I try it, is what I always get asked, without risk to my computer?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linux VS. Windows</title>
      <link>/linux-vs-windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/linux-vs-windows/</guid>
      <description>I use Linux, I also use Windows. I see the merits of the two, as they are different. Most people don’t see this distinction, that although the two OSes do many of the same functions, they remain lightyears apart. I have to admit I preach Linux to the hilt, I shouldn’t, but I do. I get skeptical Windows users who ask me what Linux does better, and I am stuck for an answer, as it does a lot of tasks better.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In Sickness and in Health!</title>
      <link>/in-sickness-and-in-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/in-sickness-and-in-health/</guid>
      <description>I have a throat infection, so I get a week off!! I went to the doctor and I am on vibramycin antibiotics. I was coughing blood (not nearly as nasty as it sounds). Now I can get some relaxation in before Christmas!! I hope to do a guide to restricted formats on Ubuntu soon, especially W32 Codecs and how to get all the good formats it offers (Divx, MPEG1-4, Windows Media, Quicktime Media and RealMedia)</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>