<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Linux on Neil Grogan</title>
    <link>/tags/linux/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Linux on Neil Grogan</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Linux, Freesat and Saorview</title>
      <link>/linux-freesat-saorview/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/linux-freesat-saorview/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently replaced a rusty satellite dish and faulty LNB (it has been in use in the house I moved in to for 10+ years I&amp;rsquo;d guess) and decided to try install one myself. Here in Ireland, the two main broadcast methods of receiving TV are satellite (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.freesat.co.uk/&#34;&gt;Freesat&lt;/a&gt; / &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sky.com/ie/&#34;&gt;Sky&lt;/a&gt;) and terrestrial aerial (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.saorview.ie/&#34;&gt;Saorview&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;An issue I have one larger sitting room TV and one small living room TV. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t get both to be Samsung (out of stock on smallest sizes - which seem to be going out of fashion). So both TVs had very different methods of switching between satellite and aerial connections. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if it is a hardware limitation (they make switching tuners slow to hide this), a licensing issue (broadcasters pay to be on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.freesat.co.uk/&#34;&gt;Freesat&lt;/a&gt; EPG for example) or a software issue (seems least likely). The fact multiple TV brands (in my case Phillips/Samsung) make it this clunky - makes me think it&amp;rsquo;s a licensing issue. I wanted to solve this by using an external box and having one mental model for navigating broadcast TV.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why GNU Grep is fast</title>
      <link>/grep-fast/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/grep-fast/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Worth a read for those wishing to optimise programs that process a lot of data. It proves that less really is more&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Money quote:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The key to making programs fast is to make them do practically nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fish Shell for Ubuntu and OS X</title>
      <link>/fish-shell/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/fish-shell/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A great guide to get up to speed with Fish shell. What is Fish? It&amp;rsquo;s a shell written from the ground up to be more easily understandable the the traditional shells (bash, tcsh). I don&amp;rsquo;t know yet if I&amp;rsquo;ll switch (anything you can do in Fish can be made to work in Bash). It&amp;rsquo;s an interesting concept and I&amp;rsquo;ll try it for a while&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SSH Config Aliases</title>
      <link>/ssh-config/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/ssh-config/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If your like me and you deal with a lot of servers for development or test and do it from a Unix machine, I&amp;rsquo;ve got a really handy tip: SSH hostname pattern matching.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Say I&amp;rsquo;ve got a SSH config file like this (at &lt;code&gt;~/.ssh/config&lt;/code&gt; ):&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;host s*&#xA;    HostName atrcu%h.example.com&#xA;    User example1&#xA;    Port 22&#xA;host b*&#xA;    HostName atrcx%h.example.com&#xA;    User example2&#xA;    Port 22&#xA;host ??*&#xA;    HostName atvts%h.example.com&#xA;    User example5&#xA;    Port 2205&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The ssh man page explains this really well:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Custom Colourful Bash Prompt</title>
      <link>/colour-bash/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/colour-bash/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Bash, a command line shell is one of the most used pieces of software in my daily work. I like scripting repetitive actions to save a lot time (it brings me great joy!). One of the simplest and easiest customisations is to add a bit of colour to your otherwise boring bash prompt (otherwise known as $PS1):&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;[ngrogan@localhost:~]$&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;can be turned in to this:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;../../files/2013/05/ColourBashPrompt.png&#34; alt=&#34;My Custom Colour Bash Prompt&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The thing about Bash is the colour codes to achieve this can look archaic:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Linux Desktop has a place</title>
      <link>/the-linux-desktop-has-place/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/the-linux-desktop-has-place/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve seen an article by Miguel de Icaza, a great developer oft criticised for his love of Microsoft technologies on Linux. His &lt;a href=&#34;http://tirania.org/blog/archive/2012/Aug-29.html&#34;&gt;latest piece&lt;/a&gt; is about his love for Mac OS X as a desktop and how he used to feel guilty about it (given his very impressive open source credentials).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I used to feel the same also. Android even as a platform more closely follows my ideals, yet I am exclusively an avid iOS user at this point. But as I&amp;rsquo;ve learned more, the importance of pragmatism is clear. I use my personal iOS devices for countless hours a day and I really just want them to work. I want them to work in the way they were designed to do: quickly check email, browse the web, make calls, check messages and so forth.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Record your terminal session</title>
      <link>/record-your-terminal-session/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/record-your-terminal-session/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As I&amp;rsquo;ve mentioned before&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, I regularly watch technology podcasts and I&amp;rsquo;ve had a subscription to sites like &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.lynda.com&#34; title=&#34;Lynda Training Videos&#34;&gt;Lynda.com&lt;/a&gt;. Between those and Youtube, I&amp;rsquo;ve watched an awful lot of technology how-to videos and 90% of them are quite poor in terms of editing, sound and being coherent/properly scripted. Sometimes though it&amp;rsquo;s a joy to genuinely learn something new in a short, concise and to the point video.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;iframe src=&#34;http://revision3.com/html5player-v12777?external=true&amp;width=555&amp;height=312&#34; width=&#34;555&#34; height=&#34;312&#34;  frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowFullScreen=&#34;allowfullscreen&#34; &gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This haktip is right up there with being among the best: short, concise, to the point and about a utility that will be super-useful to me. In work I&amp;rsquo;m in an agile software development team and I spend a lot of time on the command line. I &lt;strong&gt;like&lt;/strong&gt; the command line, but many don&amp;rsquo;t (personal preference I guess). As part of being agile, we produce a lot of video demos to stakeholders. Increasingly though the demos we produce are just as useful for the team - you can&amp;rsquo;t be every team member at once and this provides huge visibility to the team of progress. Our software is a Unix product, but we develop on Windows - so Camtasia is usually used - which is fine for GUI demos. This handy utility will be great to demo CLI stuff we do.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Faster with Arch</title>
      <link>/faster-with-arch/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/faster-with-arch/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have recently switched my main desktop over to Arch Linux. If you have never heard about Arch Linux,&#xA;it is a &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;roll your own&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo; Linux distribution. This basically means from start to finish, the whole&#xA;process is custom. Whether your system has a Graphical User Interface (GUI) or sound is totally up to you.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I switched from Ubuntu Linux, which is very much built for new people to Linux. I have been using Ubuntu&#xA;since it&amp;rsquo;s release in 2004 (as old as this blog incidentally). I have found it slowly moving away from my&#xA;power user needs from the release of the KDE 4.0 desktop up to the recently introduced Unity desktop for&#xA;Ubuntu. Don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong I love the whizz-bang effects of the snazzier distributions (like Ubuntu) and&#xA;have used it to show people the power of Linux (and how really groundbreaking Compiz effects were at the&#xA;time, ~2005). It&amp;rsquo;s sad Compiz hasn&amp;rsquo;t got the kudos but since both Windows and OS X have copied from Compiz,&#xA;some more usability has been gained.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best KDE/Linux?</title>
      <link>/best-kdelinux/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/best-kdelinux/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tuxradar.com/content/get-best-kde-linux-distro&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://posterous.com/getfile/files.posterous.com/dueyfinster/nhcpemhIhaknDbFnGmyDrygFCmfgwJfwsfBiEbAdJcEzAGazExymJgjbkHIn/media_httpwwwtuxradarcomfilesLXF126roundslackware02jpg_lEmerdfCueGgscx.jpg.scaled1000.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://posterous.com/getfile/files.posterous.com/dueyfinster/nhcpemhIhaknDbFnGmyDrygFCmfgwJfwsfBiEbAdJcEzAGazExymJgjbkHIn/media_httpwwwtuxradarcomfilesLXF126roundslackware02jpg_lEmerdfCueGgscx.jpg.scaled500.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;via&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tuxradar.com/content/get-best-kde-linux-distro&#34;&gt;tuxradar.com&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;For me it&amp;rsquo;s definitely Kubuntu, but I can see why they choose OpenSuSe.&#xA;May I just mention the virtual machine builder system is awesome, pay&#xA;attention Mr.Shuttleworth! Although PPA builds come a close second for&#xA;useful online tools&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Linux Desktop Environments?</title>
      <link>/linux-desktop-environments/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/linux-desktop-environments/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What are Desktop Environments? Wikipedia defines it as:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In graphical computing, a &lt;strong&gt;desktop environment&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;strong&gt;DE&lt;/strong&gt;) commonly&#xA;refers to a style of &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Graphical_user_interface&#34; title=&#34;Graphical user interface&#34;&gt;graphical user&#xA;interface&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip; A desktop environment typically consists of&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Icon_(computing)&#34; title=&#34;Icon (computing)&#34;&gt;icons&lt;/a&gt;,&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Window_(computing)&#34; title=&#34;Window (computing)&#34;&gt;windows&lt;/a&gt;,&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Toolbar&#34; title=&#34;Toolbar&#34;&gt;toolbars&lt;/a&gt;,&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Directory_(file_systems)&#34; title=&#34;Directory (file systems)&#34;&gt;folders&lt;/a&gt;,&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Computer_wallpaper&#34; title=&#34;Computer wallpaper&#34;&gt;wallpapers&lt;/a&gt;,&#xA;and &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Widget_engine&#34; title=&#34;Widget engine&#34;&gt;desktop&#xA;widgets&lt;/a&gt;.&#xA;(See&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/WIMP_(computing)&#34; title=&#34;WIMP (computing)&#34;&gt;WIMP&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I would add a &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File_manager&#34;&gt;file manager&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;and &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Web_browser&#34;&gt;browser&lt;/a&gt; to this list&#xA;also! Let&amp;rsquo;s look at the two most popular consumer Operating Systems (in&#xA;three variants) and their Desktop Environments:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://draft.blogger.com/post-create.g?blogID=7231752728434532377&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;OS Name&lt;/strong&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Widgets&lt;/strong&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Window Manager&lt;/strong&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;File Manager&lt;/strong&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Browser&lt;/strong&gt;&#xA;Windows XP&#xA;Luna&#xA;Stack Window Manager&#xA;Windows File Explorer&#xA;Internet Explorer 6&#xA;Windows Vista&#xA;Aero&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Desktop_Window_Manager&#34; title=&#34;Desktop Window Manager&#34;&gt;Desktop Window&#xA;Manager&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Windows_Explorer&#34;&gt;Windows File Explorer&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Internet_Explorer&#34;&gt;Internet Explorer 7&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;Mac OS X&#xA;Cocoa&#xA;Quartz Compositor&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Finder_(software)&#34;&gt;Finder&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Safari_(web_browser)&#34;&gt;Safari 2.X&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;Now take Linux; really a Kernel, but packaged means an Operating System.&#xA;Which way you package it makes all the difference! You still use the&#xA;same drivers, the boot process is still the same, but when your machine&#xA;finishes its boot and launches all that graphics stuff anything can&#xA;appear: &lt;strong&gt;anything&lt;/strong&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s abstraction to have no real graphics in a&#xA;kernel other than that which are drivers to control hardware. This is&#xA;very strange to people who think in the Windows way (nb. I used to be&#xA;one of these). At the end of Windows XP booting I have never seen&#xA;anything but Luna; and most people don&amp;rsquo;t know its called that. So it is&#xA;very strange for people my age and slightly older who grew up over DOS&#xA;and Windows 3.1/95 line to have this fundamental shift in logic.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu in four years</title>
      <link>/ubuntu-in-four-years/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/ubuntu-in-four-years/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last year was me celebrating four years of using the best&#xA;operating system out there: &lt;a href=&#34;http://kernel.org/&#34;&gt;Linux&lt;/a&gt; and the best distro&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ubuntu.com/&#34;&gt;Ubuntu&lt;/a&gt;. Ubuntu was my first foray in to Linux; and I&#xA;haven&amp;rsquo;t left it since; although I have tried all the other&#xA;major distros. I started with the first version of Ubuntu;&#xA;Warthy Warthog:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/d/d0/Ubuntu-desktop-2-410-20080706.png/180px-Ubuntu-desktop-2-410-20080706.png&#34; alt=&#34;Warthy Warthog&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Warthy had a text only installer and it took me quite a while&#xA;to not only get used to the idea of this strange operating&#xA;system; but the fear of leaving Windows-land where all that&#xA;power usage knowledge would mean nothing. It meant nothing&#xA;in terms of the registry and other superficial stuff; but the&#xA;more I used Ubuntu and Linux the more I liked it. In fact in&#xA;2005 I ditched my XP installation altogether. I noticed there&#xA;wasn&amp;rsquo;t an Irish Ubuntu users group; so I mailed one of the&#xA;few people (around 5 I guess) that were around Mark Shuttleworth&#xA;to set it up and get a website going. It was an ill-advised&#xA;effort since I was too busy with examinations really to take&#xA;it on; so I gave it up soon after. But it is still going today,&#xA;people are still involved.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>KDE 4.2 Beta 2</title>
      <link>/beta-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/beta-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently I downloaded the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kubuntu.org/&#34;&gt;Kubuntu&lt;/a&gt; packages of&#xA;the new &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kde.org/&#34;&gt;KDE&lt;/a&gt; 4.2 beta 2. For those of you who&#xA;don&amp;rsquo;t know; KDE is the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kde.org/&#34;&gt;K Desktop Environment&lt;/a&gt;;&#xA;which includes a window manager&#xA;(&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kwin&#34;&gt;KWin&lt;/a&gt;), common desktop&#xA;applications, its own menu&#xA;(&lt;a href=&#34;http://home.kde.org/~binner/kickoff/sneak_preview.html&#34;&gt;Kickoff&lt;/a&gt;),&#xA;browser (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.konqueror.org/&#34;&gt;Konqueror&lt;/a&gt;), file manager&#xA;(&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dolphin_(software)&#34;&gt;dolphin&lt;/a&gt;) etc.&#xA;Basically it is the most popular desktop environment on Linux next to&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/GNOME&#34;&gt;Gnome&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://kde.org/announcements/announce_4.2-beta1/desktop_thumb.png&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&#xA;*KDE 4.2 Beta 2 with Kickoff Menu visible&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;**What is so special about KDE? **&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The philosophy of KDE is the advanced configuration it allows through&#xA;its &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/GUI&#34;&gt;Graphical User Interface&lt;/a&gt; (GUI),&#xA;this is versus &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gnome.org/&#34;&gt;Gnome&lt;/a&gt; which chooses sane&#xA;defaults and leaves configuration in hard to reach places and&#xA;out-of-sight. This isn&amp;rsquo;t to say KDE doesn&amp;rsquo;t choose sane defaults; it&#xA;does and is very user-friendly. KDE has always been the more&#xA;Windows-like of the major desktop environments and this hasn&amp;rsquo;t really&#xA;changed in KDE 4.X series. KDE is available in popular distributions of&#xA;Linux such as Kubuntu, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mandriva.com/&#34;&gt;Mandriva&lt;/a&gt;,&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.opensuse.org/en/&#34;&gt;OpenSuse&lt;/a&gt;. The special part about 4.X&#xA;series is that for the first time for any Linux desktop environment; it&#xA;is fully cross-platform, easily installs and works on Microsoft Windows&#xA;and Apple Mac OS X.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Linux and Patents: Just Patently Wrong</title>
      <link>/linux-and-patents-just-patently-wrong/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/linux-and-patents-just-patently-wrong/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So I read the news &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theregister.co.uk/2007/10/12/novell_red_hat_linux_patent_sued/&#34;&gt;Novell and Red Hat are being sued for&#xA;patent&#xA;infringement&lt;/a&gt;.&#xA;This is all about multiple workspaces that can hold various graphical&#xA;user elements, a Xerox Parc patent which dates to the early 1990&amp;rsquo;s.&#xA;Xerox Palo Alto Research center invented the graphical user interface in&#xA;the 1980&amp;rsquo;s, only to been, licensed and used by Steve Jobs in Mac OS&#xA;Classic. Now IP Innovation, a submarine patent troll, who make no&#xA;products and bought the patent want their payday. The logical step is to&#xA;go after the biggest infringer to set a precedent for your patent, and&#xA;then make your way to all the smaller companies who infringe. Well&#xA;logically of course that would be Apple or Microsoft. Apple has already&#xA;paid them a reported 20 million dollars, and well no-one knows what&#xA;Microsoft has done, but this fish is smelly. From the Register&#xA;Article:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gutsy coming along, Update to Dell Windows Refund..</title>
      <link>/gutsy-coming-along-update-to-dell/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/gutsy-coming-along-update-to-dell/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ubuntu.com/themes/ubuntu07/images/ubuntulogo.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.ubuntu.com/themes/ubuntu07/images/ubuntulogo.png&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;I just tried Herd 5 of Gutsy Gibbon, a beta release which will be Ubuntu&#xA;07.10 released in October. Obviously it is still early stages and a lot&#xA;of things aren&amp;rsquo;t working quite as they should, but it looks very&#xA;promising. Here&amp;rsquo;s some new stuff which should hit the final release:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Compiz Fusion - Pretty Graphics that leave you in awe&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Bullet Proof X - Making sure you&amp;rsquo;ll never see a terminal prompt not&#xA;of your own choosing, basically the graphics server should be&#xA;&amp;lsquo;bulletproof&amp;rsquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Appearance Manager - Making it easier to change yourbuntu&amp;rsquo;s look and&#xA;feel&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Better Driver Support - More of those restricted drivers to make&#xA;sure you can see your screen and use your wifi card&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Simplified Codecs install - It will now be painless, install&#xA;ubuntu-restrictedcodecs (or kubuntu-restricted codecs) and you can&#xA;see Youtube in all its glory, play a dvd, watch that porno WMV file&#xA;(just kidding but I think thats all WMV is used for) and other such&#xA;niceties of the propreitry world we have to put up with&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Firefox Codecs Plugin - Firefox will be hooked up to the package&#xA;manager and prompt to install Flash/Java if you haven&amp;rsquo;t got it&#xA;already, much the same way it prompts to get a codec when you throw&#xA;a file at it that it cannot play in the movie player. The free&#xA;software Gnash replacement for Flash will come as standard and can&#xA;play Youtube Vids.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Dual Screen Glory - If your like me you have a nice and small&#xA;portable laptop, but that screen just won&amp;rsquo;t do all of the time,&#xA;thats why I personally have a 19&amp;quot; to plug my 13&amp;quot; MacBook into. With&#xA;Gutsy I should be able to plug and play over DVI.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;These are just some of the features that are being worked on for the&#xA;final release. Probably not all of them on the list will get into Gutsy&#xA;final, but lets hope they do! Gutsy+1 (slated for release April 2008)&#xA;has been announced as &amp;ldquo;Hardy Hereon&amp;rdquo; and should be a long term release&#xA;(5 years server and 3 years desktop updates and&#xA;patches).&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.kir.com/archives/dell_logo2.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.kir.com/archives/dell_logo2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dell refunds me for Windows!</title>
      <link>/dell-refunds-me-for-windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/dell-refunds-me-for-windows/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As many of you know&#xA;I am a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ubuntu.com/&#34;&gt;Linux&lt;/a&gt; and&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apple.com/mac&#34;&gt;Mac&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.google.ie/search?q=define:aficionado&amp;amp;ie=utf-8&amp;amp;amp;oe=utf-8&amp;amp;aq=t&amp;amp;rls=com.ubuntu:en-US:official&amp;amp;client=firefox-a&#34;&gt;aficionado&lt;/a&gt;.&#xA;For my Linux machines, all of them are &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dell.com/open&#34;&gt;Dell&lt;/a&gt;.&#xA;I have been always pleased with Dells prices, how their machines work&#xA;with Linux, their customer service and the fact they are made in&#xA;Limerick, Ireland (I am from Ireland). I politely emailed Dell (well got&#xA;up on my high horse), heres my first mail:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I would like a refund of Windows XP since I am installing Ubuntu Linux&#xA;on the computer when I get it. When I turn on the computer I am going&#xA;to decline the EULA, and I am within my rights to request this refund&#xA;(as part of Irish consumer laws). This also applies in Britian, see&#xA;here: (&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/technology/6144782.stm&#34;&gt;http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/technology/6144782.stm&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HP to Follow Dell into Open Source? and Ubuntu Home Server</title>
      <link>/hp-to-follow-dell-into-open-source/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jul 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/hp-to-follow-dell-into-open-source/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;HP it seems is responding to Dell&amp;rsquo;s initiative to&#xA;sell Ubuntu on their computers. With the Ubuntu Dells reportedly selling&#xA;very well and Dell rolling out the program worldwide, this hasn&amp;rsquo;t&#xA;escaped the notice of the world&amp;rsquo;s number one computer manufacturer - HP.&#xA;This is speculation from blogs that has been going on for months since&#xA;Dell started to offer Ubuntu. The Direct to Dell Blog states:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This &lt;a href=&#34;http://tomdryer.com/blog/index.php/2007/07/03/is-hp-going-to-start-offering-ubuntu/&#34;&gt;recent post from Tom&#xA;Dryer&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;caught my eye a couple of days ago, and thought I&amp;rsquo;d comment on it&#xA;here. If the rumors about HP offering Ubuntu are true, we&amp;rsquo;re glad to&#xA;see other vendors join us in support of Ubuntu and open source. We&#xA;welcome HP and other system vendors that want to join in this&#xA;initiative.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Windows Vista Security - Better than Linux?</title>
      <link>/windows-vista-security-better-than/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jul 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/windows-vista-security-better-than/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After reading a &lt;a href=&#34;http://blogs.csoonline.com/node/218&#34;&gt;nice article written by Jeff&#xA;Jones&lt;/a&gt;, a security researcher for&#xA;Microsoft. He says &lt;a href=&#34;http://blogs.csoonline.com/exactly_how_biased_am_i&#34;&gt;he isn&amp;rsquo;t&#xA;biased&lt;/a&gt;, saying he&#xA;worked over 75% of his career outside Microsoft, using Slackware Linux,&#xA;Unix, HP Unix etc. He claims Windows Vista has less security holes than&#xA;popular versions of Linux, such as Ubuntu (he also compares Red Hat,&#xA;Novell, Mac OS X). First let me say why his facts are distorted, and why&#xA;he knows his facts are distorted. His facts do raise an issue of slow&#xA;patching of vulnerabilities across the software Industry, but Linux&#xA;performs the best consistently because anyone can audit the code. Here&amp;rsquo;s&#xA;why his comparisons are uneven:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dell Sells Ubuntu 7.04</title>
      <link>/dell-sells-ubuntu-704/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 May 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/dell-sells-ubuntu-704/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dell Computers has started&#xA;selling Ubuntu Linux 7.04 on consumer machines in the United States.&#xA;This can only be good news, as a supporter of Linux since late&#xA;2004/early 2005 I am fully behind this initiative to put Linux as a&#xA;choice in front of people who buy computers. They are testing the market&#xA;at the moment which explains why they are shipping stock drivers with&#xA;the hardware, and no multimedia codecs (which is unfortunate, but&#xA;understandable that this deal was done in 60 days). I think this is&#xA;quite an achievement for Canonical and Mark Shuttleworth (Ubuntu&#xA;Founder), as they get to do the traditional Linux business model: you&#xA;pay for support, and if you don&amp;rsquo;t need it, you don&amp;rsquo;t buy it. This could&#xA;confuse some people in the shorter term, but long term its a winner:&#xA;Dell does what it does best (Hardware) and Software is left to Ubuntu&amp;rsquo;s&#xA;parent company Canonical. This is opposed to Microsoft getting Dell to&#xA;provide support for both hardware and software, sometimes a messy&#xA;business in which the consumer does not know which to turn to and can&#xA;often be left out in the cold. I hope Dell extends this to Europe and&#xA;6the rest of the world soon, and makes a decent stab at promoting a free&#xA;software desktop. Dell list advantages in one of their videos:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ultimate Games Disc</title>
      <link>/ultimate-games-disc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/ultimate-games-disc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I got inspiration over this past Easter holidays, being bored, I gave&#xA;Linux Gaming a shot. I am not much of a gamer myself and most websites&#xA;aren&amp;rsquo;t very helpful or have too small a focus (only shoot-em-ups, or&#xA;only certain Linux distros etc.). Inspired by the fine folks at&#xA;OpenSourceMac.org and OpenSourceWindows.org, I announce my own project:&#xA;Ultimate Games Disc. UGD is a project I think I can make very&#xA;successful. My aims are as follows:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vista is released; Ubuntu gets .exe!</title>
      <link>/vista-is-released-ubuntu-gets-exe/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/vista-is-released-ubuntu-gets-exe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well as&#xA;I write this it is a few days after Vista&amp;rsquo;s launch, and it has yet to&#xA;set the software market alight. But this is nothing new, it happend with&#xA;XP. How do you convince people the latest and greatest is worth the&#xA;money? Microsoft is in a tough position due to stiff competition - old,&#xA;working, fully-compatible windows machines don&amp;rsquo;t disappear into thin&#xA;air. There has been a lot more FUD (Fear Uncertainty and Doubt)abput&#xA;Vista already from the Free and Open Source camp. Some of the harsh&#xA;critiscims will be justified, others probably not. Regardless this will&#xA;not hurt Microsofts marketing whatsoever, the average user doesn&amp;rsquo;t share&#xA;concerns over digital restriction/rights management - yet. Microsoft say&#xA;it will be on 100m PC&amp;rsquo;s by years end. I don&amp;rsquo;t think it will be as fast&#xA;as Microsoft would like, due to: 1) People wait for service packs. 2)&#xA;People don&amp;rsquo;t upgrade PC&amp;rsquo;s as fast now. Most things people identify their&#xA;computer with is increasingly online, a worrying trend if I were&#xA;Microsoft, this creates platform independence for the average user,&#xA;granted not the gamers, or other highly specialised software vendors.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BBC to host Multi-OS Debate and My First Web Auction</title>
      <link>/bbc-to-host-multi-os-debate-my-first/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/bbc-to-host-multi-os-debate-my-first/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://img111.imageshack.us/img111/7099/tuxcasefront7rw.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Tux, the Linux&#xA;Penguin&#34; title=&#34;Tux, the Linux Penguin&#34;&gt;BBC&#xA;are putting together a Mac, Windows and Linux user, to &lt;a href=&#34;http://news.bbc.co.uk/2/hi/technology/6288119.stm&#34; title=&#34;Mac Linux and Windows Debate&#34;&gt;debate the pros&#xA;and cons of being a users for each operating&#xA;system&lt;/a&gt;.&#xA;While this in itself is good news (more airtime for alternatives), most&#xA;of the comments are highly in favour of Linux, then Mac and lastly&#xA;Windows. This is part of the BBC&amp;rsquo;s coverage of Windows Vista. My hope&#xA;for the future is that Mac and Linux gain at least 10% each (20% total)&#xA;over the next 5 years of the home desktop market, as this will push&#xA;innovation forward, like AMD and Intel competition.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Widget for our RSS feed!</title>
      <link>/new-widget-for-our-rss-feed/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/new-widget-for-our-rss-feed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://img216.imageshack.us/img216/1396/picture2tn0.png&#34; alt=&#34;Duey Finsters RSS&#xA;Widget&#34; title=&#34;Duey Finsters&#xA;RSS Widget&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thanks to Dashcode, the tool for making dashboard widgets, there is now an RSS&#xA;one for this site! Currently it only works on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apple.com/macosx/leopard/index.html&#34; title=&#34;Mac OS X&#34;&gt;Mac OS X&lt;/a&gt;, but &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kde.org&#34; title=&#34;K Desktop Enviroment&#34;&gt;KDE&lt;/a&gt; 4&#xA;should support dashboard widgets (they are really just bits of javascript, css&#xA;and html).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Video iPod and Freespire</title>
      <link>/video-ipod-and-freespire/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/video-ipod-and-freespire/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://img412.imageshack.us/img412/8155/imageshj0.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;IPod Video (Image Hosted by&#xA;ImageShack.us)&#34; title=&#34;IPod&#xA;Video (Image Hosted by ImageShack.us)&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Well I guess you can call me a hardcore &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apple.ie&#34; title=&#34;Apple Computer&#34;&gt;Apple Computer&lt;/a&gt; fan, I have a Macbook, an iPod Nano (1st Gen 4GB) and now a&#xA;80GB iPod Video! I bought i for a couple of reasons, namely price and storage.&#xA;I had been put off before since I thought they were too bulky ( I know a&#xA;couple of people who have older generation iPod Videos) after being with the&#xA;Nano for over a year (its still chugging along gleefully). What can I say? I&#xA;am impressed! Battery life is huge to me and well to be frank, its amazing. My&#xA;first MP3 player was a Creative Nomad Jukebox II (circa 2002), which I still&#xA;have. I know only one person who owned an MP3 player before me, and its nice&#xA;to be there from the start, you appreciate the little details most people&#xA;don´t, as they are new to mp3 players, so they expect it as standard. I now&#xA;get all the latest tech podcasts, so I am very happy with that!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why I am getting an Apple MacBook</title>
      <link>/feel-i-need-to-confess-why-i-am-buying/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/feel-i-need-to-confess-why-i-am-buying/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I feel I need to confess why I am buying a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apple.com/uk/macbook/macbook.html&#34; title=&#34;MacBook&#34;&gt;MacBook&lt;/a&gt;, have I turned soft to&#xA;my &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.opensource.org/&#34; title=&#34;Open Source&#34;&gt;Open Source&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fsf.org/&#34; title=&#34;Free Software Foundation&#34;&gt;Free Software&lt;/a&gt; ways? No, definately 100% NOT. I’ll&#xA;explain why: I think Apple Computer has an incredible product in Mac OSx. For&#xA;anyone who has not used it before, pop into a 3G store and ask to have a go.&#xA;When someone releases a good a product as that, they deserve money, in my&#xA;opinion. Under “the” free software license (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gnu.org/licenses/gpl.txt&#34; title=&#34;GNU General Public License&#34;&gt;GNU General Public License&lt;/a&gt;) it&#xA;is permissable for anyone to charge for software licensed under it, as long as&#xA;an offer of source code is given (for 3 years afterwards). Deep down I love&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ubuntulinux.org/&#34; title=&#34;Ubuntu Linux&#34;&gt;Ubuntu&lt;/a&gt;, and I will install it as soon as possible when they release a&#xA;version for the Intel powered Apple computers. In fact I will use my Laptop to&#xA;showcase Ubuntu you had of told me November last year I’d spend well over&#xA;€1,000 on an &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apple.com/&#34; title=&#34;Apple Computer&#34;&gt;Apple Computer&lt;/a&gt;, I would have told you that I hated Apple, and&#xA;would never consider it! What has changed my mind? I got a iPod Nano for&#xA;Christmas ‘05 and thought it was great, but the Nano on its own still wouldn’t&#xA;convince me to get a Mac.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Just Klik it!</title>
      <link>/just-klik-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/just-klik-it/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest complaints of Linux is that software doesn’t install to&#xA;well, or is very difficult to install. “Dependency Hell” (When software relies&#xA;on other bits of software to work), used to be quite commonplace. Ubuntu has&#xA;cleaned a lot of dependency hell up, and a new program for installing software&#xA;from the internet, is included in the new version, due to be released 1st June&#xA;2006.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;That’s when I discovered a little gem called &lt;a href=&#34;http://klik.atekon.de/&#34; title=&#34;Klik it!&#34;&gt;Klik&lt;/a&gt; for many Linux&#xA;distributions. Simply lookup the piece of software you need, click on it and&#xA;you have it! No need to install! It places the whole program on the desktop,&#xA;so it is easily deletable and easily transferable. For example, if you have an&#xA;office application, and your friend doesn’t, simply copy that file on desktop&#xA;to your usb key or a cd, and copy to friends pc, done and dusted - Your friend&#xA;has the whole application! This is an obvious feature bonus over current&#xA;Windows version, XP.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Virtual Ubuntu</title>
      <link>/virtual-ubuntu/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/virtual-ubuntu/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So you have heard of Ubuntu, maybe they have even shipped you a free disc or&#xA;you have downloaded one? Like most users, even advanced PC users, they get&#xA;nervous about installing Linux and afraid of what they might have to learn.&#xA;Touted as the brighest star, Ubuntu really does outshine other Linuxes, with&#xA;usability, features and great range of software. Now you can try Ubuntu on&#xA;Windows.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.vmware.com/img/ubuntu.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Ubuntu Logo&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Linux VS. Windows</title>
      <link>/linux-vs-windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/linux-vs-windows/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I use Linux, I also use Windows. I see the merits of the two, as they are&#xA;different. Most people don’t see this distinction, that although the two OSes&#xA;do many of the same functions, they remain lightyears apart. I have to admit I&#xA;preach Linux to the hilt, I shouldn’t, but I do. I get skeptical Windows users&#xA;who ask me what Linux does better, and I am stuck for an answer, as it does a&#xA;lot of tasks better.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Sickness and in Health!</title>
      <link>/in-sickness-and-in-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/in-sickness-and-in-health/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have a throat infection, so I get a week off!! I went to the doctor and I am&#xA;on vibramycin antibiotics. I was coughing blood (not nearly as nasty as it&#xA;sounds). Now I can get some relaxation in before Christmas!! I hope to do a&#xA;guide to restricted formats on Ubuntu soon, especially  W32 Codecs and how to&#xA;get all the good formats it offers (Divx, MPEG1-4, Windows Media, Quicktime&#xA;Media and RealMedia)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
