<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>review hardware on Neil Grogan</title><link>/tags/review-hardware/</link><description>Recent content in review hardware on Neil Grogan</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/review-hardware/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Garmin Zumo 660 Motorcycle GPS</title><link>/motorcycle-gps/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/motorcycle-gps/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s been over a week since I received my Garmin Zumo 660 Motorcycle GPS unit. I thought I&amp;rsquo;d give it a run-down for potential buyers on my experience for the first week. Firstly I should mention, I&amp;rsquo;ve never owned another Garmin unit, and had two mobile GPS&amp;rsquo; units before (one being Nokia N800 with Bluetooth external GPS and other Apple iPhone 3G). The reason I bring this up is that a lot of the reviews I&amp;rsquo;ve seen written compare it to it&amp;rsquo;s predecessor, Zumo 550, which obviously I can&amp;rsquo;t do.</description></item><item><title>Yamaha Majesty 400c Review</title><link>/yamaha-majesty-400c-review/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/yamaha-majesty-400c-review/</guid><description>I own a Majesty 125cc 2002. The video below is the updated (and more powerful) model:
(Some of the) New features:
2x the amount of space Parking break (for hills! Think handbrake if your a car driver) Liquid-cooled 400cc ABS brakes Dual Halogen Headlights Larger rear lights Csr-like oversize dials on dash It looks good, good, good. I haven&amp;rsquo;t looked at price, but my last two bikes are Yamaha and I&amp;rsquo;ve had little trouble with them.</description></item><item><title>Nokia N800 Review</title><link>/nokia-n800/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/nokia-n800/</guid><description>I have one of those new Nokia N800 Internet Tablet, as many of you know I was one of the first to buy its predecessor, the Nokia 770 Internet Tablet. What do I think? Well I have put of writing this for 4 days, as I wanted to really test it out. Before I start, I should say I was part of the Nokia Developer Device program, and I got the Nokia N800 at a big discount, €300 off the €399 retail price in fact.</description></item></channel></rss>