<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>travel on Neil Grogan</title><link>/tags/travel/</link><description>Recent content in travel on Neil Grogan</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/travel/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Go Bag(s)</title><link>/gobag/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/gobag/</guid><description>I follow Casey Liss&amp;rsquo; blog and recently he had a great post about a technology &amp;ldquo;go pack&amp;rdquo;. Lifehacker has written about this over the years, and the Wirecutter has a great article I shared here on this very blog. Also Casey linked to a great post by Katie Floyd on Twitter:
https://twitter.com/KatieFloyd/status/630707145999314946
I finally took the hint / inspiration from all these posts, and I decided time was right to put together my own &amp;ldquo;go bag&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>Going on Holidays? Check these Gadgets</title><link>/holiday-gadgets/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/holiday-gadgets/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m a big Wirecutter fan and they don&amp;rsquo;t disappoint with this travel guide.</description></item><item><title>Inter-railing around Europe</title><link>/inter-railing-around-europe/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/inter-railing-around-europe/</guid><description>As you read this, I have already embarked on an inter-railing trip around Europe. Some of the cities in the itinerary:
Amsterdam Cologne Nürburgring (Rock Am Ring festival) Prague Bratislava I&amp;rsquo;ll definitely post up some pictures when I get back. I planned this trip with a few classmates to coincide with the completion of our four year honours degree in Computer Science.</description></item><item><title>German Trip</title><link>/german-trip/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/german-trip/</guid><description>I recently travelled to Munich, Germany on a recent exchange (1st-9th Feb, 2006). Not knowing what to expect, I found a very different Germany from the text book one you read about (Bavarian Trad Dress, Beer-drinking, Pretzel Eating, Sausage loving etc!). Of course all of these elements were present, but I think a modern German society closely reflects American one, in a lot of ways. Germans are the largest group by ethnicity in United States, so maybe its just German culture prevalent in America?</description></item></channel></rss>