<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Travel on Neil Grogan</title>
    <link>/tags/travel/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Travel on Neil Grogan</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/travel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Go Bag(s)</title>
      <link>/gobag/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/gobag/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I follow Casey Liss&amp;rsquo; blog and recently he had a great post about a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.caseyliss.com/2015/8/9/go-pack&#34;&gt;technology &amp;ldquo;go pack&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;. Lifehacker has written about &lt;a href=&#34;http://lifehacker.com/5903929/put-together-a-killer-go-bag-this-weekend&#34;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://lifehacker.com/the-tech-commuters-go-bag-1279587407&#34;&gt;over&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://lifehacker.com/the-tech-essentials-daily-bag-1723128314&#34;&gt;the&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://lifehacker.com/the-geek-essentials-bag-1441875871&#34;&gt;years&lt;/a&gt;, and the Wirecutter has a great article &lt;a href=&#34;https://ngrogan.com/holiday-gadgets&#34;&gt;I shared here on this very blog&lt;/a&gt;. Also Casey linked to a great post by &lt;a href=&#34;http://katiefloyd.com/blog/creating-a-tech-go-bag&#34;&gt;Katie Floyd&lt;/a&gt; on Twitter:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/KatieFloyd/status/630707145999314946&#34;&gt;https://twitter.com/KatieFloyd/status/630707145999314946&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I finally took the hint / inspiration from all these posts, and I decided time was right to put together my own &amp;ldquo;go bag&amp;rdquo;. Here&amp;rsquo;s a picture of my tech go bag:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Going on Holidays? Check these Gadgets</title>
      <link>/holiday-gadgets/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/holiday-gadgets/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a big Wirecutter fan and they don&amp;rsquo;t disappoint with this travel guide.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Visit to CERN</title>
      <link>/cern/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/cern/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am currently in Switzerland on a business trip. In between work, I managed to get some time over the Swiss national holiday to visit the &lt;acronym title=&#34;European Nuclear Research Centre&#34;&gt;CERN&lt;/acronym&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;http://home.web.cern.ch/&#34;&gt;CERN&lt;/a&gt; is world famous for the invention of &lt;acronym title=&#34;World Wide Web&#34;&gt;WWW&lt;/acronym&gt; and of course most recently, the almost certainty that the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Higgs_boson&#34;&gt;Higgs Boson&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;acronym title=&#34;also known as&#34;&gt;aka&lt;/acronym&gt;. &amp;ldquo;The God Particle&amp;rdquo;) - the particle that gives energy mass - exists.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The CERN tour is completely free and highly recommended. I visited the &lt;a href=&#34;http://atlas.ch/&#34;&gt;Atlas experiment&lt;/a&gt; with a colleague (who just so happened to have a Phd. in Physics) and questions were encouraged at every turn. What impressed me the most was the fact that there was no stupid questions. You can be a Phd weilding Physicist or a child and each question was handled the same by the staff. The guide (an active researcher at CERN) even expressed disappointment at the Higgs:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inter-railing around Europe</title>
      <link>/inter-railing-around-europe/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/inter-railing-around-europe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As you read this, I have already embarked on an inter-railing&#xA;trip around Europe. Some of the cities in the itinerary:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Amsterdam&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cologne&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Nürburgring (Rock Am Ring festival)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Prague&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Bratislava&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll definitely post up some pictures when I get back. I planned&#xA;this trip with a few classmates to coincide with the completion of&#xA;our four year honours degree in Computer Science.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FON, New Job and Commuting!</title>
      <link>/fon-new-job-and-commuting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/fon-new-job-and-commuting/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I regularly read other Irish blogs to see whats happening and whats the latest&#xA;tech thing amongst others. It seems that may have come to fruition, with FON,&#xA;a community wifi project, sending me out a free router!! I am exicted about&#xA;this, as I hope to convince all my neighbours eventually to get it, and maybe&#xA;who knows, I may even achieve the biggest fon hotspot, if I take my campaign&#xA;estate wide, to neighbours all around! I want to “eat my own dog food” as they&#xA;say, so I will wait until I have recieved and used my router before I&#xA;recommend it to non-technical people. I have read of long delays on FON’s&#xA;forums, so I expect iot should be here within two to three weeks, maybe a&#xA;little longer. Also it comes with a european plug, not a Irish/British one,&#xA;which is a bit of a disappointment that I will have to root out the&#xA;screwdriver to make it fit!!!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>German Trip</title>
      <link>/german-trip/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/german-trip/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently travelled to Munich, Germany on a recent exchange (1st-9th Feb,&#xA;2006). Not knowing what to expect, I found a very different Germany from the&#xA;text book one you read about (Bavarian Trad Dress, Beer-drinking, Pretzel&#xA;Eating, Sausage loving etc!). Of course all of these elements were present,&#xA;but I think a modern German society closely reflects American one, in a lot of&#xA;ways. Germans are the largest group by ethnicity in United States, so maybe&#xA;its just German culture prevalent in America?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
