<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>apple hardware on Neil Grogan</title><link>https://www.neilgrogan.com/tags/apple-hardware/</link><description>Recent content in apple hardware on Neil Grogan</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.neilgrogan.com/tags/apple-hardware/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>iPhone 6 and Apple Watch</title><link>https://www.neilgrogan.com/apple-annouces-iphone6-watch/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.neilgrogan.com/apple-annouces-iphone6-watch/</guid><description>Interesting announcements yesterday by Apple, finally releasing an iWatch. A lot of the talk on tech sites was reminiscent of the famous CMDR Taco (of Slashdot) line: &amp;ldquo;Less space then a nomad. Lame.&amp;rdquo;
I happened to own a Nomad shortly after that famous quote was made. So we can see, quoting Steve Jobs &amp;ldquo;[They] have no taste&amp;rdquo; is applicable to me! I just don&amp;rsquo;t get the watch yet. As a permanent contact wearer, I&amp;rsquo;m waiting for Google Glass in a contact lens!</description></item><item><title>iPad Evolution?</title><link>https://www.neilgrogan.com/ipad-evolution/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.neilgrogan.com/ipad-evolution/</guid><description>Since Apple released an iPad there have been various competitors announced, so it got me thinking what would it take for me to buy one? I haven&amp;rsquo;t bought the first generation iPad because the lack of a camera on a device so obviously good for fullscreen video calls has baffled me. I guess they have to store up some ideas since they need a new hardware iteration every year, Apple&amp;rsquo;s revenue model depends on that vital hardware refresh cycle.</description></item><item><title>Is a Mac Pro overpriced?</title><link>https://www.neilgrogan.com/is-mac-pro-overpriced/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.neilgrogan.com/is-mac-pro-overpriced/</guid><description>Gizmodo seem to think so:
The $2,500 Mac Pro, desperately in need of a refresh, gives you a 2.66GHz Quad-Core Xeon (essentially an i7), 3GB of RAM (triple channel, but seriously?), 640GB hard drive (again, seriously?) and a nominal graphics card. Spend $800 more and you&amp;rsquo;ll get a another processor and 3GB more RAM.
The $2200, 27-inch iMac obviously includes a screen, plus you get a 2.8GHz Quad-Core (i7), 1TB drive, 4GB of RAM and a nominal graphics card.</description></item></channel></rss>