<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>work on Neil Grogan</title><link>https://www.neilgrogan.com/tags/work/</link><description>Recent content in work on Neil Grogan</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.neilgrogan.com/tags/work/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Bell Curve is Wrong</title><link>https://www.neilgrogan.com/bell-curve/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.neilgrogan.com/bell-curve/</guid><description>Interesting study here: apparently performance of people in a company is never related to a bell curve, but is more like a ski slope. So the majority of people are carried by the few in terms of performance. What I really want to know is pay for these people like a ski slope? Cause I bet it ain&amp;rsquo;t.</description></item><item><title>Document it Please</title><link>https://www.neilgrogan.com/doc-it-please/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.neilgrogan.com/doc-it-please/</guid><description>Very good technical documentation skills are a must for any Software Engineer - to explain how a system works in detail forces you to think about the flaws present within the design. &amp;ldquo;Bad smells&amp;rdquo; of documentation often can be a sign of weaknesses on your product. Is this section too verbose or did we make it too complex for the customer? Should we explain ancillary parts of our system (either operating system components or other applications?</description></item><item><title>Is 4K the new 3D? - The Networked Society Blog</title><link>https://www.neilgrogan.com/is-4k-the-new-3d-the-networked-society-blog/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.neilgrogan.com/is-4k-the-new-3d-the-networked-society-blog/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;d love to own a 4K screen, the more lifelike the images the better it&amp;rsquo;ll be for movies. I&amp;rsquo;d imagine filesizes are 4x as large as HD also, which will be an issue that might kill off optical storage (and require better broadband). It&amp;rsquo;s a shame the author tried to compare it to 3D (which objectively is still a flop) but he mentions the issues in that technology (namely: field of vision).</description></item><item><title>Software Engineering Job</title><link>https://www.neilgrogan.com/software-engineering-job/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.neilgrogan.com/software-engineering-job/</guid><description>I had been applying for jobs since I started my last year in college and I am delighted to say even before I completed my final year, I have gained full time employment. I would say it is luck, but my family thinks it&amp;rsquo;s down to a lot of hard work and good grades! Either way, it&amp;rsquo;s a great feeling in probably the most competitive jobs market (for potential employees) in years.</description></item></channel></rss>