<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Work on Neil Grogan</title>
    <link>/tags/work/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Work on Neil Grogan</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/work/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Adventures with Docker</title>
      <link>/docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docker/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a huge fan of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.docker.com&#34;&gt;Docker&lt;/a&gt; ever since I started to use&#xA;it, approximately a year after it was started. It&amp;rsquo;s one of those technologies&#xA;where when you start to use it, you immediately know it&amp;rsquo;s going to be a sea&#xA;change in how things are done in the industry. It&amp;rsquo;s definitely going to be more&#xA;impactful then&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Virtual_machine&#34;&gt;Virtual Machines&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve used Docker to great effect where I work. We&amp;rsquo;re building a huge system&#xA;called Ericsson Network Manager, which will manage the networks of the future.&#xA;As such, it&amp;rsquo;s a hugely complex problem to compartmentalise parts of the product,&#xA;to be able to just use the part that you work directly on.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bell Curve is Wrong</title>
      <link>/bell-curve/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/bell-curve/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Interesting study here: apparently performance of people in a company is never&#xA;related to a bell curve, but is more like a ski slope. So the majority of people&#xA;are carried by the few in terms of performance. What I really want to know is&#xA;pay for these people like a ski slope? Cause I bet it ain&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Document it Please</title>
      <link>/doc-it-please/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/doc-it-please/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Very good technical documentation skills are a must for any Software Engineer -&#xA;to explain how a system works in detail forces you to think about the flaws&#xA;present within the design. &amp;ldquo;Bad smells&amp;rdquo; of documentation often can be a sign of&#xA;weaknesses on your product. Is this section too verbose or did we make it too&#xA;complex for the customer? Should we explain ancillary parts of our system&#xA;(either operating system components or other applications?) within our&#xA;documentation besides the inherent risks (out-of-date documentation)?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is 4K the new 3D? - The Networked Society Blog</title>
      <link>/is-4k-the-new-3d-the-networked-society-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/is-4k-the-new-3d-the-networked-society-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d love to own a 4K screen, the more lifelike the images the better it&amp;rsquo;ll be&#xA;for movies. I&amp;rsquo;d imagine filesizes are 4x as large as HD also, which will be an&#xA;issue that might kill off optical storage (and require better broadband). It&amp;rsquo;s a&#xA;shame the author tried to compare it to 3D (which objectively is still a flop)&#xA;but he mentions the issues in that technology (namely: field of vision).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Software Engineering Job</title>
      <link>/software-engineering-job/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/software-engineering-job/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I had been applying for jobs since I started my last year in college and I am&#xA;delighted to say even before I completed my final year, I have gained full time&#xA;employment. I would say it is luck, but my family thinks it&amp;rsquo;s down to a lot of&#xA;hard work and good grades! Either way, it&amp;rsquo;s a great feeling in probably the most&#xA;competitive jobs market (for potential employees) in years.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Open Sourcing your CV</title>
      <link>/open-sourcing-your-cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/open-sourcing-your-cv/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just like software. it can be really useful to open source other things in life,&#xA;collaboration is nearly always a good thing. John Buckman, CEO of Magnatune&#xA;Records knows this principle all too well. He gave a speech at a Red Hat&#xA;conference a while back, and he talked about the importance of music artists&#xA;sharing the &amp;ldquo;source&amp;rdquo;, i.e. basically sharing the method of how the produced the&#xA;music in the first place. This allows easier mixing, and a higher chamnce your&#xA;work could be featured on TV or in a film, and you get paid&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FON, New Job and Commuting!</title>
      <link>/fon-new-job-and-commuting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/fon-new-job-and-commuting/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I regularly read other Irish blogs to see whats happening and whats the latest&#xA;tech thing amongst others. It seems that may have come to fruition, with FON, a&#xA;community wifi project, sending me out a free router!! I am exicted about this,&#xA;as I hope to convince all my neighbours eventually to get it, and maybe who&#xA;knows, I may even achieve the biggest fon hotspot, if I take my campaign estate&#xA;wide, to neighbours all around! I want to “eat my own dog food” as they say, so&#xA;I will wait until I have recieved and used my router before I recommend it to&#xA;non-technical people. I have read of long delays on FON’s forums, so I expect&#xA;iot should be here within two to three weeks, maybe a little longer. Also it&#xA;comes with a european plug, not a Irish/British one, which is a bit of a&#xA;disappointment that I will have to root out the screwdriver to make it fit!!!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
