<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>hardware on Neil Grogan</title><link>/tags/hardware/</link><description>Recent content in hardware on Neil Grogan</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/hardware/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Ikea in the TV Business?</title><link>/ikea-in-the-tv-business/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/ikea-in-the-tv-business/</guid><description>Ikea the TV Business? Who would have forseen the day. After looking at their video I must say I can see the reasons quite clearly: TV&amp;rsquo;s look awkward in almost everyones home. They don&amp;rsquo;t fit in our units, the cables are in awkward positions and you can never find the remote1. I&amp;rsquo;m a fan of all things cheap and Ikea I must confess, so I&amp;rsquo;ll be watching this development with great interest!</description></item><item><title>What Really Happened Aboard Air France 447</title><link>/air-france-447/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/air-france-447/</guid><description>Incredibly well-written article. Just shows the power of human misunderstanding and lack of clear judgement.</description></item><item><title>Cleaning your PS3's fans?</title><link>/cleaning-your-ps3s-fans/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/cleaning-your-ps3s-fans/</guid><description>Below is a neat trick to clean out your Playstation 3&amp;rsquo;s fans if they become a bit noisy. Before I have used a can of compressed air, but this method is really neat and definitely lowered the fan sound emanating from my PS3.
&amp;lt;embed width=&amp;quot;320&amp;quot; height=&amp;quot;266&amp;quot; src=&amp;quot;http://www.youtube.com/v/JhU4_Rm0GQU&amp;amp;fs=1&amp;amp;source=uds&amp;quot; type=&amp;quot;application/x-shockwave-flash&amp;quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/embed&amp;gt; Thanks goes to my former classmate Alan Smith for alerting me to this, Thanks Al!</description></item><item><title>Dogs chew things?</title><link>/dogs-chew-things/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/dogs-chew-things/</guid><description>Lesson learned: never leave a expensive. Take these pictures I shot after the dog attacked my motorcycle! I still love dogs as pets, they are man&amp;rsquo;s best friend and just like best friends they can screw up. The only thing I am most upset about now is the dog can&amp;rsquo;t pay for the repairs&amp;hellip; Forgive and forget Fritzie? Thats a girl&amp;hellip;
P.S. If anyone knows anyone thats in the seat repairing business, let me know!</description></item><item><title>Sony Subsidises Supercomputers for the US Military?</title><link>/sony-subsidises-supercomputers-for-us/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/sony-subsidises-supercomputers-for-us/</guid><description>Ars has a great article about how Sony through the Playstation 3&amp;rsquo;s awesome power (can&amp;rsquo;t you tell which of this generations consoles I own?) and subsidy (based on recoup of selling games and hardware - a model pioneered with the PS1)
With respect to cell processors, a single 1U server configured with two 3.2GHz cell processors can cost up to $8K while two Sony PS3s cost approximately $600. Though a single 3.</description></item><item><title>Summer - One Month On.....</title><link>/summer-one-month-on/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/summer-one-month-on/</guid><description>Well one month in Summer 2008! Summer has been okay so far; I&amp;rsquo;ve had nothing much to report hence lack of Tech posts. Sure the iPhone 3G looks good, Google/Yahoo/Microsoft spats interesting but after a while it become a bit circular and repetitive.
I&amp;rsquo;ve recently started working at the UK&amp;rsquo;s leading retailer for touring/car/bike and accessories; as well as a move to the south east of Ireland; that much further to the capital: Dublin.</description></item><item><title>Planning the Computer Build</title><link>/planning-computer-build/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/planning-computer-build/</guid><description>Planning to build a computer can be fun also. Researching parts, making sure they work well together (if they are on Manufacturers QVL). Making a list of all the parts you need is the beginning of the purchasing, assembly and then seeing your machine in action! Lots of guides online help with the planning stage; but nearly all are advice and tips. How do you know which is biased? Are the benchmarks relevant to what you are building your machine for?</description></item><item><title>Computer Systems - Dismantling PC's is fun!</title><link>/computer-systems-dismantling-pcs-is-fun/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/computer-systems-dismantling-pcs-is-fun/</guid><description>I found a new pastime: dismantling pc&amp;rsquo;s. It my not sound like great fun, but its a challenge to do it right and make sure you don&amp;rsquo;t break your pc at the end of it all. Nothing feels of so much relief when you see the BIOS boot up again after ripping everything you can out and cramming it all back in. It stands to you in developing problem solving skills, which of course employers love.</description></item></channel></rss>