<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Google on Neil Grogan</title>
    <link>/tags/google/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Google on Neil Grogan</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/google/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>First Experiences with an ARM Chromebook</title>
      <link>/first-experiences-with-arm-chromebook/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/first-experiences-with-arm-chromebook/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I  recently bought a&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B009LL9VDG/ref=as_li_qf_sp_asin_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B009LL9VDG&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=duefinsblo-20&#34;&gt;Samsung&#xA;Chromebook (Wi-Fi, 11.6-Inch)&lt;/a&gt;. I am fascinated by living tied to the web,&#xA;indeed my honours computer science thesis deals with this in relation to mobile&#xA;applications (and hybrid half-app/ half-website). Spurred on by the excellent&#xA;reviews this Chromebook has gotten (&amp;quot;&lt;i&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s $1,000 worth of design made with&#xA;$100 worth of materials&lt;/i&gt;&amp;quot; -&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theverge.com/2012/10/24/3549368/samsung-chromebook-review-series-3&#34;&gt;The&#xA;Verge&lt;/a&gt; and &amp;ldquo;&lt;i&gt;You simply won&amp;rsquo;t find a netbook this nice for that little&#xA;money.&lt;/i&gt;&amp;rdquo; -&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.engadget.com/2012/11/07/samsung-chromebook-review-2012/&#34;&gt;Engadget&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chrome vs. Internet Explorer Audience</title>
      <link>/chrome-vs-internet-explorer-audience/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/chrome-vs-internet-explorer-audience/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Lately both Google and Microsoft have been advertising their respective browsers&#xA;on British Television (received in Ireland by the vast majority of the&#xA;population). It&amp;rsquo;s interesting the different approach each company is taking.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chrome ad:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&#34;allowfullscreen&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/embed/E0qDrRJT4zE&#34; width=&#34;560&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To me the Chrome ad is very family oriented, stressing the utility of the web&#xA;and the ease of reaching people and staying in touch. No surprise they&#xA;didn&amp;rsquo;t feature Facebook, which is what the vast majority use to keep in&#xA;touch.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Are Android Smartphones Bigger Than the iPhone?</title>
      <link>/why-are-android-smartphones-bigger-than-the-iphone/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/why-are-android-smartphones-bigger-than-the-iphone/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;tl;dr&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; It&amp;rsquo;s because LTE chipsets are very large and power hungry right now.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>@ACR884 Tech Slot #002 - Tablets</title>
      <link>/acr884-tech-slot-002-tablets/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/acr884-tech-slot-002-tablets/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&#x9;&lt;li&gt;iPad&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&#x9;&lt;li&gt;Motorola Xoom&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&#x9;&lt;li&gt;HP Slate&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&#x9;&lt;li&gt;Android tablet apps&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&#x9;&lt;li&gt;iOs tablet apps&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;In this episode Patrick and Neil discuss the main players in the tablet market as well as Neils top Android and iOs tablet apps.&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Subscribe:&lt;/strong&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;//itunes.apple.com/ie/podcast//id494862406&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img title=&#34;iTunes Podcast Button&#34; src=&#34;http://dueyfinster.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/itunes_podcast.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Subscribe to ACR884 Tech Slot in iTunes!&#34; width=&#34;80&#34; height=&#34;15&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;audio controls=&#34;controls&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;source src=&#34;http://dueyfinster.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/technologydec1911.mp3&#34; type=&#34;audio/mp3&#34; /&gt;&#xA;  Your browser does not support the audio tag.&#xA;&lt;/audio&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Download Link:&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://dueyfinster.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/technologydec1911.mp3&#34;&gt;Technology&#xA;Slot Dec 19 11&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>All About Platforms</title>
      <link>/all-about-platforms/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/all-about-platforms/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If your passion is in technology, you often sigh with the marketing buzzwords&#xA;used in sales. &lt;em&gt;Cloud Computing&lt;/em&gt; doesn&amp;rsquo;t actually mean anything specific&#xA;(or could mean a lot of things). It&amp;rsquo;s that a lot of things to a lot of people&#xA;who makes it useful as a term, an  ideology, a way of explaining why&#xA;&lt;em&gt;you-oh-so-need-to-do-this-now&lt;/em&gt;. Cloud computing for me is a platform&#xA;description. I think of the myriad of hosting companies who offer a platform to&#xA;build your service atop.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Top Chrome Extensions</title>
      <link>/my-top-chrome-extensions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/my-top-chrome-extensions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Below I present some very useful extensions I use while using Google Chrome, in&#xA;no particular order.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/_Wq0iRacWX8o/TOpquOK6RLI/AAAAAAAAAlE/oGVd0x63zCc/s200/20001.png&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://chrome.google.com/extensions/detail/gighmmpiobklfepjocnamgkkbiglidom&#34;&gt;Adblock&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Blocks ads just like Firefox extension and makes the web less junky to look&#xA;at. You can whitelist good ads, and an argument could be had your harming&#xA;websites revenue stream, but a lot of nasty tricks such as spyware, malware&#xA;have used ads as a vector to spread. Not least the dishonesty some sites use&#xA;in splitting up articles in to 10 pages to pump ad revenue.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/_Wq0iRacWX8o/TOpsbEDdBMI/AAAAAAAAAlI/4yyhlRHjWN0/s1600/1001.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/_Wq0iRacWX8o/TOpsbEDdBMI/AAAAAAAAAlI/4yyhlRHjWN0/s200/1001.png&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://chrome.google.com/extensions/detail/flcpelgcagfhfoegekianiofphddckof&#34;&gt;KB SSL Enforcer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WebM promises Open Web Video</title>
      <link>/webm-promises-open-web-video/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/webm-promises-open-web-video/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve written &lt;a href=&#34;../../2008/12/firefox-and-opera-lead-web-video-way.html&#34;&gt;about my desire for open web video before&lt;/a&gt;, and now it&#xA;looks as if it&amp;rsquo;s finally going to happen. Lead by Google&amp;rsquo;s acquisition of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.on2.com/&#34;&gt;On2&#xA;technologies&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/VP8&#34;&gt;VP8&lt;/a&gt; codec has been renamed as &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.webmproject.org/&#34;&gt;WebM&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; and open&#xA;sourced. &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vorbis&#34;&gt;Vorbis&lt;/a&gt; will be the audio. &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Matroska&#34;&gt;Matroska&lt;/a&gt; the container for the new&#xA;format. An Open Source developer for x264 does a &lt;a href=&#34;http://x264dev.multimedia.cx/?p=377&#34;&gt;great teardown of the format&#xA;vs. h.264 here&lt;/a&gt;. The patent minefield stateside is still not clear by&#xA;any means, but with a strong backer like Google, it&amp;rsquo;s probably the best&#xA;protection your going to get. Announcements, including links to nightlies, dev&#xA;and beta channel browsers with WebM support are below:&amp;lt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gmail Video Chat</title>
      <link>/gmail-video-chat/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/gmail-video-chat/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/_JE4qNpFW6Yk/SRkwSMYD_aI/AAAAAAAAAJ8/gsDJdA4WBgY/s1600/video_chat.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/_JE4qNpFW6Yk/SRkwSMYD_aI/AAAAAAAAAJ8/gsDJdA4WBgY/s200/video_chat.png&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;I am an avid &lt;a href=&#34;http://mail.google.com/&#34;&gt;Gmail&lt;/a&gt; user through Google Apps. I use&#xA;the calender, chat, code, sites, pages, docs the whole lot. One of my friends&#xA;even jokes &amp;ldquo;You should just work at Google Marketing&amp;rdquo;. Yes I like most of&#xA;Google&amp;rsquo;s products; but I am a products guy; I use whats good, cheap and fast&#xA;(pick two). Google has the cheap down due to ad-revenue; for the moment anyways&#xA;in the current financial turmoil.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Will Google Buy Skype?</title>
      <link>/will-google-buy-skype/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/will-google-buy-skype/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been all over the tech news world lately; apparently&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.google.ie/&#34;&gt;Google&lt;/a&gt; is muling over taking Skype off of Ebay&amp;rsquo;s hands.&#xA;Ebay has already written down the value of&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Skype&#34;&gt;Skype&lt;/a&gt; as a large loss on their purchase&#xA;price of $2.6 billion in stock and cash. But&#xA;w&lt;a href=&#34;http://about.skype.com/online.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://about.skype.com/online.png&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;ould&#xA;Skype&amp;rsquo;s G-branded future be any better?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I think it would be. Skype is a strong international brand for voice calls,&#xA;instant messaging and video calls; but of course it competes directly with&#xA;Google Talk. Skype as a company has made a lot of mistakes; but they actually&#xA;produces some of the best technology for p2p VOIP out there in the marketplace.&#xA;Skype is particularly strong in redundancy, cost of network operation (since&#xA;it&amp;rsquo;s p2p every user carries&amp;rsquo; each others traffic; most people have no idea of&#xA;this fact) and routing around the most draconian network admins out their&#xA;through their routers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Free Domain name off AOL, too good to be true?</title>
      <link>/free-domain-name-off-aol-too-good-to-be/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/free-domain-name-off-aol-too-good-to-be/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.aol.com/&#34; title=&#34;AOL&#34;&gt;AOL&lt;/a&gt;, the longtime dialup king, who esperate to keep customers at its&amp;rsquo; site&#xA;who have switched to broadband, is &lt;a href=&#34;https://domains.aol.com/personaldomain/app/domainHomeSearch&#34; title=&#34;AOL Free Domains&#34;&gt;offering free dot com and dot net&#xA;domains&lt;/a&gt;. There are a few caches however, one must be in possession of a US mobile&#xA;phone (cell) number. Luckily I have a cousin stateside willing to help out ;-) .&#xA;I got to register NeilGrogan.com (My actual name) which I hadn&amp;rsquo;t bothered with before.&#xA;AOL is the legal owner however, so has all the say legally to the name. At the minute&#xA;it provides 100 2GB email accounts with the free domain, and if you visit the address&#xA;online, it redirects to an AIM Pages profile of the owner (for all intents and purposes,&#xA;it&amp;rsquo;s another social networking site). Its a good way to drum up interest in its online&#xA;offerings, but they should be more flexible. If anyone is in any doubt, this is just&#xA;an &amp;lsquo;alright&amp;rsquo; kind of deal, AOL say they will give you the option to buy the name&#xA;back in the future, but I won&amp;rsquo;t hold my breath.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google buy YouTube, GTalk for everyone and Blogger Bliss</title>
      <link>/google-buy-youtube-gtalk-for-everyone/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/google-buy-youtube-gtalk-for-everyone/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;rsquo;t posted in a while :-( Ah well here it goes: Well we&amp;rsquo;ve all seen the&#xA;news Google has bought YouTube for a reported 1.65 Billion US dollars, the deal&#xA;was reportedly sealed at at Dennys in California (gotta admire that style and&#xA;sophistication). I think its way overvalued Youtube, at 24m per employee! We all&#xA;know it serves 100m videos a day, but it has been living off measly venture&#xA;capital and hasn&amp;rsquo;t got a verifiable steady income stream, which I guess is where&#xA;Google enter with Adwords&amp;hellip;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Design, Ranking, Gmail Hosted, OS 2006 Finale and YouOS</title>
      <link>/new-design-ranking-gmail-hosted-os-2006/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/new-design-ranking-gmail-hosted-os-2006/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hope you like the new look Duey Finsters. Like Google style hoo-pah, we are&#xA;still in “Beta” mode (or is it “Alpha”? Depends on who you ask!). I would be&#xA;extremely grateful for people to report issues, with the folloxing browsers IE&#xA;5.5, 6 &amp;amp; 7, Opera 9, Firefox 1.5.X , Mozilla 1.X , Safari on all platforms&#xA;Windows, Linux and Mac (BSD if you want!). Great news also in ranking, the site&#xA;has gone from 8.5 millionth, to just under 4 million (#3,945,836 to be exact)&#xA;in three and a half months! I am working on releasing the design to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.oswd.org/&#34;&gt;OSWD&lt;/a&gt; and&#xA;in Wordpress theme format, for others to extend and enjoy (If you feel like&#xA;helping out, contact me).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google will organise your life</title>
      <link>/google-will-organise-your-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/google-will-organise-your-life/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Google have released a calendar, as part of their mission to “Organise the&#xA;Worlds Information”. While it is what you expect from Google, the Calendar did&#xA;not impress me a whole lot. It does have an intuitive interface, that is easy to&#xA;use. It does integrate with Gmail, although the full extent has yet to be seen,&#xA;as they fall short of mentioning it in Gmail at all, but I would expect this to&#xA;change. I see great potential for users though, and where Google is heading.&#xA;They will eventually integrate it with GoogleTalk and Gmail, producing a hybrid&#xA;interface where you can organise a conference on GoogleTalk, schedule it on your&#xA;calendar (which is syncronised with your PC and your workgroup server [therby&#xA;informing fellow employees]), submit video of it to Google Video, write minutes with&#xA;writely, email minutes with Gmail, that mail (with document and video) being attached&#xA;to the meeting on the Calendar, which is in turn archived on your PC in Google Desktop&#xA;and your Gmail Drive. While that is only one scenario, it is very possible. Google&#xA;have already leaked information on their eagerness to hold the entire contents of&#xA;ones&amp;rsquo; hard drive on the internet.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ekiga&#39;s Vorbis</title>
      <link>/ekigas-vorbis/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/ekigas-vorbis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am all for open standards, but they face huge problems. Not least is lack of&#xA;intergration between them. Take SIP used by VOIP providers, such as&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wengo.com/&#34;&gt;OpenWengo&lt;/a&gt;. While OpenWengo is open source, and it is SIP, they are not&#xA;helpful in informing you how to use other clients, or dial other OpenWengo users&#xA;from other networks.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What I am really talking about is the need for an all-in-one communications&#xA;program, that is multi-platform. Their is already open source code for: Google&#xA;Talk (aka Jabber), MSN, AOL, ICQ, SIP, H.323, Yahoo! but why isn’t their an&#xA;all-in-one client? Surely it would be easy to reimplement some code from other&#xA;programs into Ekiga (SIP, H.323) , Kopete or Gaim (both Jabber, MSN, Yahoo, AOL&#xA;and ICQ)? I know GoogleTalk is based on SIP, so why not SIP compatability? That&#xA;is poor implementation which is fragmenting the Open Source community, how are&#xA;we going to challenge MSN’s userbase with this sort of fragmentation? That said&#xA;I like Google Talk and its way of doing things. Also it is rumoured GoogleTalk&#xA;will be interoperable with AOL at protocol level, since Google owns 5% of AOL.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Video</title>
      <link>/google-video/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/google-video/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What a fantastic service Google now offer with their Google Video platform.&#xA;There are a couple of reasons why I like it, mainly because it is available to&#xA;upload your videos on all platforms (Windows, Linux and Mac) and is available on&#xA;Mozilla-based browsers (Firefox, Netscape), Opera and Internet Explorer.This is&#xA;important in creating a better all round user experience. If only Yahoo! would&#xA;follow Googles example and open up Launch Cast to other browsers besides an&#xA;outdated version of Netscape and Internet Explorer.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Future.....</title>
      <link>/future/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/future/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While using instant messenger I had a brainwave, what will the tech landscape&#xA;look like in the future? So here is What I think could happen: IBM will buy Sun&#xA;MicroSystems and make a new opensource OS, it will be based on Ubuntu. Microsoft&#xA;will purchase AOL and roll out its products on the Web, such as MS Office, it&#xA;will have a slow start to Vista, but it will pick up through peoples eagerness&#xA;to buy the latest hardware. Google will buy Opera, invest in Mozilla and&#xA;consolidate Opera into Mozilla, it will also buy Adobe (for their PDF format),&#xA;get its way to publish an online bookstore through Google Book Search. Yahoo&#xA;will continue to buy extra companies to add to its list of a zillion services,&#xA;such as Flickr and Del.icio.us.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Duey Finster</title>
      <link>/dueyfinster/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Oct 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/dueyfinster/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Awake Mornin at nearly six am I am writing this at six am in my cousins home&#xA;because I heard this is a good way to get a gmail invite!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
