<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>google on Neil Grogan</title><link>/tags/google/</link><description>Recent content in google on Neil Grogan</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/google/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>First Experiences with an ARM Chromebook</title><link>/first-experiences-with-arm-chromebook/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/first-experiences-with-arm-chromebook/</guid><description>I recently bought a Samsung Chromebook (Wi-Fi, 11.6-Inch). I am fascinated by living tied to the web, indeed my honours computer science thesis deals with this in relation to mobile applications (and hybrid half-app/ half-website). Spurred on by the excellent reviews this Chromebook has gotten (&amp;quot;It&amp;rsquo;s $1,000 worth of design made with $100 worth of materials&amp;quot; - The Verge and &amp;ldquo;You simply won&amp;rsquo;t find a netbook this nice for that little money.</description></item><item><title>Chrome vs. Internet Explorer Audience</title><link>/chrome-vs-internet-explorer-audience/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/chrome-vs-internet-explorer-audience/</guid><description>Lately both Google and Microsoft have been advertising their respective browsers on British Television (received in Ireland by the vast majority of the population). It&amp;rsquo;s interesting the different approach each company is taking.
Chrome ad:
To me the Chrome ad is very family oriented, stressing the utility of the web and the ease of reaching people and staying in touch. No surprise they didn&amp;rsquo;t feature Facebook, which is what the vast majority use to keep in touch.</description></item><item><title>Why Are Android Smartphones Bigger Than the iPhone?</title><link>/why-are-android-smartphones-bigger-than-the-iphone/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/why-are-android-smartphones-bigger-than-the-iphone/</guid><description>tl;dr It&amp;rsquo;s because LTE chipsets are very large and power hungry right now.</description></item><item><title>@ACR884 Tech Slot #002 - Tablets</title><link>/acr884-tech-slot-002-tablets/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/acr884-tech-slot-002-tablets/</guid><description> iPad Motorola Xoom HP Slate Android tablet apps iOs tablet apps In this episode Patrick and Neil discuss the main players in the tablet market as well as Neils top Android and iOs tablet apps. Subscribe: Your browser does not support the audio tag. Download Link: Technology Slot Dec 19 11</description></item><item><title>All About Platforms</title><link>/all-about-platforms/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/all-about-platforms/</guid><description>If your passion is in technology, you often sigh with the marketing buzzwords used in sales. Cloud Computing doesn&amp;rsquo;t actually mean anything specific (or could mean a lot of things). It&amp;rsquo;s that a lot of things to a lot of people who makes it useful as a term, an ideology, a way of explaining why you-oh-so-need-to-do-this-now. Cloud computing for me is a platform description. I think of the myriad of hosting companies who offer a platform to build your service atop.</description></item><item><title>My Top Chrome Extensions</title><link>/my-top-chrome-extensions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/my-top-chrome-extensions/</guid><description>Below I present some very useful extensions I use while using Google Chrome, in no particular order.
Adblock
Blocks ads just like Firefox extension and makes the web less junky to look at. You can whitelist good ads, and an argument could be had your harming websites revenue stream, but a lot of nasty tricks such as spyware, malware have used ads as a vector to spread. Not least the dishonesty some sites use in splitting up articles in to 10 pages to pump ad revenue.</description></item><item><title>WebM promises Open Web Video</title><link>/webm-promises-open-web-video/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/webm-promises-open-web-video/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve written about my desire for open web video before, and now it looks as if it&amp;rsquo;s finally going to happen. Lead by Google&amp;rsquo;s acquisition of On2 technologies, the VP8 codec has been renamed as &amp;ldquo;WebM&amp;rdquo; and open sourced. Vorbis will be the audio. Matroska the container for the new format. An Open Source developer for x264 does a great teardown of the format vs. h.264 here. The patent minefield stateside is still not clear by any means, but with a strong backer like Google, it&amp;rsquo;s probably the best protection your going to get.</description></item><item><title>Gmail Video Chat</title><link>/gmail-video-chat/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/gmail-video-chat/</guid><description>I am an avid Gmail user through Google Apps. I use the calender, chat, code, sites, pages, docs the whole lot. One of my friends even jokes &amp;ldquo;You should just work at Google Marketing&amp;rdquo;. Yes I like most of Google&amp;rsquo;s products; but I am a products guy; I use whats good, cheap and fast (pick two). Google has the cheap down due to ad-revenue; for the moment anyways in the current financial turmoil.</description></item><item><title>Will Google Buy Skype?</title><link>/will-google-buy-skype/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/will-google-buy-skype/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s been all over the tech news world lately; apparently Google is muling over taking Skype off of Ebay&amp;rsquo;s hands. Ebay has already written down the value of Skype as a large loss on their purchase price of $2.6 billion in stock and cash. But would Skype&amp;rsquo;s G-branded future be any better?
I think it would be. Skype is a strong international brand for voice calls, instant messaging and video calls; but of course it competes directly with Google Talk.</description></item><item><title>Free Domain name off AOL, too good to be true?</title><link>/free-domain-name-off-aol-too-good-to-be/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/free-domain-name-off-aol-too-good-to-be/</guid><description>AOL, the longtime dialup king, who esperate to keep customers at its&amp;rsquo; site who have switched to broadband, is offering free dot com and dot net domains. There are a few caches however, one must be in possession of a US mobile phone (cell) number. Luckily I have a cousin stateside willing to help out ;-) . I got to register NeilGrogan.com (My actual name) which I hadn&amp;rsquo;t bothered with before.</description></item><item><title>Google buy YouTube, GTalk for everyone and Blogger Bliss</title><link>/google-buy-youtube-gtalk-for-everyone/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/google-buy-youtube-gtalk-for-everyone/</guid><description>I haven&amp;rsquo;t posted in a while :-( Ah well here it goes: Well we&amp;rsquo;ve all seen the news Google has bought YouTube for a reported 1.65 Billion US dollars, the deal was reportedly sealed at at Dennys in California (gotta admire that style and sophistication). I think its way overvalued Youtube, at 24m per employee! We all know it serves 100m videos a day, but it has been living off measly venture capital and hasn&amp;rsquo;t got a verifiable steady income stream, which I guess is where Google enter with Adwords&amp;hellip;.</description></item><item><title>New Design, Ranking, Gmail Hosted, OS 2006 Finale and YouOS</title><link>/new-design-ranking-gmail-hosted-os-2006/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/new-design-ranking-gmail-hosted-os-2006/</guid><description>Hope you like the new look Duey Finsters. Like Google style hoo-pah, we are still in “Beta” mode (or is it “Alpha”? Depends on who you ask!). I would be extremely grateful for people to report issues, with the folloxing browsers IE 5.5, 6 &amp;amp; 7, Opera 9, Firefox 1.5.X , Mozilla 1.X , Safari on all platforms Windows, Linux and Mac (BSD if you want!). Great news also in ranking, the site has gone from 8.</description></item><item><title>Google will organise your life</title><link>/google-will-organise-your-life/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/google-will-organise-your-life/</guid><description>Google have released a calendar, as part of their mission to “Organise the Worlds Information”. While it is what you expect from Google, the Calendar did not impress me a whole lot. It does have an intuitive interface, that is easy to use. It does integrate with Gmail, although the full extent has yet to be seen, as they fall short of mentioning it in Gmail at all, but I would expect this to change.</description></item><item><title>Ekiga's Vorbis</title><link>/ekigas-vorbis/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/ekigas-vorbis/</guid><description>I am all for open standards, but they face huge problems. Not least is lack of intergration between them. Take SIP used by VOIP providers, such as OpenWengo. While OpenWengo is open source, and it is SIP, they are not helpful in informing you how to use other clients, or dial other OpenWengo users from other networks.
What I am really talking about is the need for an all-in-one communications program, that is multi-platform.</description></item><item><title>Google Video</title><link>/google-video/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/google-video/</guid><description>What a fantastic service Google now offer with their Google Video platform. There are a couple of reasons why I like it, mainly because it is available to upload your videos on all platforms (Windows, Linux and Mac) and is available on Mozilla-based browsers (Firefox, Netscape), Opera and Internet Explorer.This is important in creating a better all round user experience. If only Yahoo! would follow Googles example and open up Launch Cast to other browsers besides an outdated version of Netscape and Internet Explorer.</description></item><item><title>The Future.....</title><link>/future/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/future/</guid><description>While using instant messenger I had a brainwave, what will the tech landscape look like in the future? So here is What I think could happen: IBM will buy Sun MicroSystems and make a new opensource OS, it will be based on Ubuntu. Microsoft will purchase AOL and roll out its products on the Web, such as MS Office, it will have a slow start to Vista, but it will pick up through peoples eagerness to buy the latest hardware.</description></item><item><title>Duey Finster</title><link>/dueyfinster/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Oct 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/dueyfinster/</guid><description>Awake Mornin at nearly six am I am writing this at six am in my cousins home because I heard this is a good way to get a gmail invite!</description></item></channel></rss>