<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>hardware review on Neil Grogan</title><link>https://www.neilgrogan.com/tags/hardware-review/</link><description>Recent content in hardware review on Neil Grogan</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.neilgrogan.com/tags/hardware-review/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Mechanical Keyboards</title><link>https://www.neilgrogan.com/mech-kb/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.neilgrogan.com/mech-kb/</guid><description>Early last year, I purchased two Code Keyboards (one for work and one for home). The Code Keyboards are designed by Jeff Atwood (who founded Stack Overflow). Mechanical keyboards are “old style” in that the switches are from an era where everything was mechanical, unlike today where everything is glass. So mechanical keyboards have ardent fans and people who don’t really care for them.
I did a lot of research before I purchased, talking to various people in work who are very knowledgeable about mechanical keyboards (The best community for advice, discussion and group buys is /r/mechanicalkeyboards on reddit.</description></item><item><title>Roost Laptop Stand</title><link>https://www.neilgrogan.com/roost-stand/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.neilgrogan.com/roost-stand/</guid><description>I backed the Roost laptop stand on Kickstarter, which already had a successful run in their first Kickstarter campaign. I&amp;rsquo;ve been delighted with the result so far, it lives up to the promises of being super light but yet durable and strong. Here&amp;rsquo;s a photo of it:
It came with a really nice case which holds the Roost underneath and has pockets for a portable keyboard (I use a Logitech K811) and mouse (I use a Logitech Marathon M705).</description></item><item><title>Review of the Motorola Xoom Wifi</title><link>https://www.neilgrogan.com/review-of-motorola-xoom-wifi/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.neilgrogan.com/review-of-motorola-xoom-wifi/</guid><description>I recently bought the wifi version of the Motorola Xoom. I did not get the 3G version to keep costs down (no second carrier subscription in addition to smartphone I own). Here&amp;rsquo;s my review, let it be noted I&amp;rsquo;ve been an iOS user since version 2 (iPhone 3G) and although I have used devices from Android 1.6 and up - I&amp;rsquo;ve never &amp;lsquo;lived&amp;rsquo; with them.
Motorola Xoom Aesthetics &amp;amp; Design First of all the design is very well executed.</description></item><item><title>Plantronics .655 USB Headset Review</title><link>https://www.neilgrogan.com/usb-headset-review/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.neilgrogan.com/usb-headset-review/</guid><description>I got a Plantronics .655 USB Headset mainly for the ability to do VOIP well. Those of you who come here often know I reviewed Sennheiser HD595 before, which is a headset built for the quality of reproduction (I use that one for music).
There&amp;rsquo;s not much you can say about a VOIP headset, so I am going to keep this short! The Plantronics .655 USB isn&amp;rsquo;t the most comfortable headset and the usb connection seemed like a plus as I&amp;rsquo;d never owned a USB headset.</description></item><item><title>Sennheiser HD595 Review</title><link>https://www.neilgrogan.com/senn-review/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.neilgrogan.com/senn-review/</guid><description>During last summer I purchased a set of Sennheiser HD595&amp;rsquo;s - a great product for Audiophiles. I have to say for someone who constantly listens to a lot of music - good headphones like these are a must. They are expensive for sure, but Sennheiser do seem to have a great durability and solid build quality. This is my first set of such high quality headphones, so bear that in mind - I can&amp;rsquo;t speak for other manufacturers in this space.</description></item><item><title>Honda Bros Motorcycle</title><link>https://www.neilgrogan.com/honda-bros-motorcycle/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.neilgrogan.com/honda-bros-motorcycle/</guid><description>I recently purchased - known as a cult motorbike - a Honda BROS (known in the US as a HawkGT). It is a 400cc V-Twin 1991 model, with 33BHP / 24.6Kw out of the factory. That put&amp;rsquo;s it under the legal limit for a learner motorcycle in the A category of license in Ireland. I&amp;rsquo;ve been progressing through bikes, slowly gaining confidence and experience. I posted about my Yamaha YQ50, My Yamaha YP125 (Majesty) and now it&amp;rsquo;s a Honda BROS&amp;rsquo; turn!</description></item><item><title>Yamaha YQ Aerox - best moped ever?</title><link>https://www.neilgrogan.com/yamaha-yq-aerox-best-moped-ever/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.neilgrogan.com/yamaha-yq-aerox-best-moped-ever/</guid><description>Well I think so! Got one there 2 months ago and forgot to write a blog post about it. I got a &amp;lsquo;01 model for a bargain price I believe; but this theory has yet to be tested (I&amp;rsquo;ll wait for a year to be up). As I mentioned before in previous posts my parent&amp;rsquo;s house is now in a remote location with no train/buses anywhere nearby. So transport was essential!</description></item><item><title>A few days with A Nokia N810</title><link>https://www.neilgrogan.com/few-days-with-nokia-n810/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Jan 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.neilgrogan.com/few-days-with-nokia-n810/</guid><description>I last discussed the Nokia N810 Internet Tablet in October; when details were only starting to filter out. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t expected for Nokia to introduce an upgrade to the N800 Internet Tablet (which I also reviewed here) so soon. I certainly don&amp;rsquo;t envy the position of a small team getting the hardware and software for a mini-computer right in such a short space of time. But needless to say the N810 feels right; in fact it feels more right than the N770 which I thought had the best design of all (be it functionality not so much style).</description></item><item><title>HP Photosmart R927 Review</title><link>https://www.neilgrogan.com/hp-photosmart-r927/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.neilgrogan.com/hp-photosmart-r927/</guid><description>I just bought a HP Photosmart R927, an 8 Megapixel camera from Hewlett-Packard. While I had seen and briefly used one before, I was excited again upon using my own one (as all tech people are [read: geeks]). First of all don&amp;rsquo;t confuse me as anyway into photography: I&amp;rsquo;m not and far from it. I had a criteria in mind when I purchased and this was it:
Must work under any OS (Windows [a given], Mac and Linux [latter two I only use]) Every camera I have come across mounts as a disc drive [think looking at files on a cd or your local computer], but there is also PTP or &amp;ldquo;Picture Transfer Protocol&amp;rdquo; in other words it doesn&amp;rsquo;t appear as picture files, rather PTP triggers your computer to open your camera in your photo application.</description></item><item><title>Nokia 6234 Video Test</title><link>https://www.neilgrogan.com/video-test/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.neilgrogan.com/video-test/</guid><description>I recently got a hold of my Christmas present in advance, a new Nokia 6234 from Vodafone Ireland. I did a short video test, maybe this could be the start of my VideoBlogging career:
Well maybe not! But I do hope to have more videos on my blog! The video is of me describing my living quarters and about my laptop. I needed to be a bit closer to the phone as hearing me is difficult sometimes (not so in real life!</description></item><item><title>Nokia 770 Internet Tablet</title><link>https://www.neilgrogan.com/internet-tablet/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.neilgrogan.com/internet-tablet/</guid><description>I got it! UPS delivered the Nokia 770 Internet Tablet. What can I say? It is pure magic! The features are great, it includes:
Web Browser (Opera) Flash Player version 6 Email Client Internet Radio News Reader Media players, Image viewer PDF viewer File Manager Search Calculator World Clock Notes Sketch Games It runs on Linux, making it totally extendable. It even has its own developer site at maemo.</description></item></channel></rss>