<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>networking on Neil Grogan</title><link>/tags/networking/</link><description>Recent content in networking on Neil Grogan</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/networking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Ubiquiti Unifi with Sonos on a separate VLAN</title><link>/ubnt-sonos/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/ubnt-sonos/</guid><description>Change network settings on Unifi controller Further to getting my Unifi gear last year, I&amp;#39;ve started to organise the virtual local area networks (VLANs) to increase security. I&amp;#39;ve created a separate guest wifi network and a separate internet of things (IoT) network. One issue you&amp;#39;ll run in to is that a lot of modern devices work by broadcasting their presence on the network and that doesn&amp;#39;t work well normally across VLANs.</description></item><item><title>Ubuntu 20.04 Vagrant with Packer</title><link>/vagrant-ubuntu-fossa/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/vagrant-ubuntu-fossa/</guid><description>Ubuntu have recently released the new 20.04 LTS codenamed &amp;ldquo;Focal Fossa&amp;rdquo;. I&amp;rsquo;d also recently seen a tool that piqued my interest, Hashicorp Packer. Packer builds machine images that can be deployed to a cloud or as a virtual machine, or just even a plain disk image. You can even generate many images at once, really simplfying deployment. Very handy if you wanted to create virtual machines for a cluster for example, with a similar but slightly different configuration.</description></item><item><title>Logging from Ubuntu to Synology</title><link>/synlog/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/synlog/</guid><description>I recently had a bug in the snap version of Docker.
How slow is LiveReload? Not as much as you think!</description></item><item><title>Ubiquiti Home Network</title><link>/ubnt/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/ubnt/</guid><description>Over the summer, I upgraded my home network to Ubiquiti gear. Ubiquiti do business Wifi, all the way up to covering stadiums. I first heard about them from Troy Hunt and then again from Marco Arment on Accidental Tech Podcast. Ubiquiti are popular in prosumer space - for people serious about good Wifi.
So far it&amp;rsquo;s been an excellent experience and I&amp;rsquo;d highly recommend it. After setting it up (there is a few moving pieces) it has been running without any intervention from me.</description></item><item><title>Irish SOPA Law: An Overview</title><link>/irish-sopa-law-an-overview/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/irish-sopa-law-an-overview/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Reflection on 9-11</title><link>/nerf-war/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/nerf-war/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s been 10 years since the anniversary of 9/11 and much of the world has changed a lot in that period. We&amp;rsquo;ve had full body scanners at airports, marshalls on flights, bombs hidden in toner cartridges and two wars. I reflected on this and remembered two really good articles I&amp;rsquo;ll share here on the topic. Hopefully we&amp;rsquo;ve changed for the better.
Yesterday I finally wrote something that&amp;rsquo;s been bothering me for about ten years: The fact that Al Qaeda can&amp;rsquo;t be as big and bad as it&amp;rsquo;s made out to be, because its whole design violates every rule of guerrilla organisation.</description></item><item><title>Thoughts on IPv6</title><link>/thoughts-on-ipv6/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/thoughts-on-ipv6/</guid><description>A multitude of websites have been reporting the impending doom of ipv4 exhaustion, which is going to happen soon. All the top level address&amp;rsquo; will be gone, but the regional registries will still have stocks of address&amp;rsquo; in to 2011. As a user of ipv6, I thought I could share sone thoughts/insights on the events ahead&amp;hellip;
Below is a very good video which one of my favourite tech shows, Hak5 made with an IPv6 Consultant, Joe Klein.</description></item></channel></rss>