<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>hardware linux windows on Neil Grogan</title><link>/tags/hardware-linux-windows/</link><description>Recent content in hardware linux windows on Neil Grogan</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2007 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/hardware-linux-windows/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Gutsy coming along, Update to Dell Windows Refund..</title><link>/gutsy-coming-along-update-to-dell/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/gutsy-coming-along-update-to-dell/</guid><description>I just tried Herd 5 of Gutsy Gibbon, a beta release which will be Ubuntu 07.10 released in October. Obviously it is still early stages and a lot of things aren&amp;rsquo;t working quite as they should, but it looks very promising. Here&amp;rsquo;s some new stuff which should hit the final release:
Compiz Fusion - Pretty Graphics that leave you in awe&amp;hellip; Bullet Proof X - Making sure you&amp;rsquo;ll never see a terminal prompt not of your own choosing, basically the graphics server should be &amp;lsquo;bulletproof&amp;rsquo; Appearance Manager - Making it easier to change yourbuntu&amp;rsquo;s look and feel Better Driver Support - More of those restricted drivers to make sure you can see your screen and use your wifi card Simplified Codecs install - It will now be painless, install ubuntu-restrictedcodecs (or kubuntu-restricted codecs) and you can see Youtube in all its glory, play a dvd, watch that porno WMV file (just kidding but I think thats all WMV is used for) and other such niceties of the propreitry world we have to put up with Firefox Codecs Plugin - Firefox will be hooked up to the package manager and prompt to install Flash/Java if you haven&amp;rsquo;t got it already, much the same way it prompts to get a codec when you throw a file at it that it cannot play in the movie player.</description></item></channel></rss>