<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>ios review on Neil Grogan</title><link>https://www.neilgrogan.com/tags/ios-review/</link><description>Recent content in ios review on Neil Grogan</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.neilgrogan.com/tags/ios-review/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Ulysses App</title><link>https://www.neilgrogan.com/ulysses-app/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.neilgrogan.com/ulysses-app/</guid><description>I recently purchased Ulysses Mobile after a recommendation from Macstories. My first impression was how expensive it was priced and what really makes a premium writing application?
Needless to say, I&amp;rsquo;m not a huge writer. But I do have a real fondness for plain text (it will survive the apocalypse) and by extension, Markdown by John Gruber. The problem for Ulysses is this: there&amp;rsquo;s lots of really great Markdown applications for iOS, two of which I have written about: Editorial (my favourite) and Byword (not so keen on this app).</description></item><item><title>Deliveries App</title><link>https://www.neilgrogan.com/deliveries-app/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.neilgrogan.com/deliveries-app/</guid><description>Deliveries helps you track packages from major shopping (Amazon, Apple) as well as nearly every major package distribution company like DHL, UPS and FedEx. I&amp;rsquo;ve used the app for years and it&amp;rsquo;s really impressed me.
It can sync via iCloud or the Junecloud cloud service by the makers of the app, Junecloud (not confusing at all, hey!). It started on the Mac as a simple dashboard widget (for those of you who remember those, rarely used these days), but it&amp;rsquo;s since grown to have its own Mac app also.</description></item><item><title>Editorial App</title><link>https://www.neilgrogan.com/editorial-app/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.neilgrogan.com/editorial-app/</guid><description>Editorial is an iPhone and iPad plain text editor that&amp;rsquo;s great for markdown1. It also has some nifty automation workflows, in which you can use Python scripts. These can search the web, scrape data, transform text and much more…
I pretty much wrote this blog post (and many more) in Editorial. It&amp;rsquo;s much better then the competition for markdown in particular. Byword is an obvious competitor, which I really can&amp;rsquo;t recommend (nothing inherently wrong with Byword, just doesn&amp;rsquo;t suit me).</description></item><item><title>Soulver App</title><link>https://www.neilgrogan.com/soulver-app/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.neilgrogan.com/soulver-app/</guid><description>My favourite text number crunching app on iOS bar none is Soulver. What makes it the best?
Fast to load Simple user interface that gets out of the way Contextual Keyboards (my favourite is the currency keyboard) Can reuse calculations from previous lines (and name calculations). iCloud sync Soulver is great for when a spreadsheet is just to heavy. I use it a lot for it currency conversion, makes it easy to have multiple line items in different currencies (say GBP &amp;amp; USD) and get a total in one (EUR).</description></item><item><title>Drafts App</title><link>https://www.neilgrogan.com/drafts-app/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.neilgrogan.com/drafts-app/</guid><description>My favourite text capture app on iOS bar none is Drafts by Agile Tortoise. What makes it the best?
No fluff, loads fast Simple user interface that gets out of the way Extensible actions (which you can add to from their directory) iCloud sync I&amp;rsquo;ve tried a lot of other apps like Byword (Not worth the money I think), Apples&amp;rsquo; built-in Notes app, Textastic and so on. None felt as efficient or as flexible as Drafts.</description></item></channel></rss>