<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Europe on Neil Grogan</title>
    <link>/tags/europe/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Europe on Neil Grogan</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2006 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/europe/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Europe&#39;s New Voice</title>
      <link>/europes-new-voice/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/europes-new-voice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As tech savvy readers will be aware, dot EU is the latest domain to go into&#xA;public use. What is a domain? A domain is the name used for internet site like&#xA;&amp;ldquo;dueyfinster.eu&amp;rdquo;. It has already sold over 1.25 million names already, this&#xA;entering the third day of the public sale. Their have been bitter critics of how&#xA;it has dealt out, with heated arguments over some domains such as Polo.eu, which&#xA;was claimed by no less than 3 entities: Volkswagen, Ralph Lauren and Nestle.&#xA;Volkswagen won out eventually, all because they got their application in first.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Eurosceptics</title>
      <link>/eurosceptics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Dec 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/eurosceptics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The British Press annoys me so much, they way they constantly get it wrong&#xA;across the board about the EU. I am a fond supporter of the EU for all its&#xA;faults and cracks. But I love freedom of the press and like organisations who&#xA;uphold basic journalistic standards, such as the BBC. This leads me onto the&#xA;evil man behind it all, Rupert Murdoch owner of The Sun, BSkyB Television, The&#xA;Times and other media outlets. It seems all he pushes is his agenda, whether it&#xA;be the Bush Right-Christian agenda on Fox in the US or Eurosceptic view in his&#xA;British interests.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
