<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>programming on Neil Grogan</title><link>https://www.neilgrogan.com/tags/programming/</link><description>Recent content in programming on Neil Grogan</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.neilgrogan.com/tags/programming/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Python 3 In-Memory Zip File</title><link>https://www.neilgrogan.com/py-bin-zip/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.neilgrogan.com/py-bin-zip/</guid><description>In Python, BytesIO is the way to store binary data in memory. Most examples you’ll see using zip files in memory is to store string data and indeed the most common example you’ll find online from the zipfile module is zipfile.writestr(file_name, &amp;#34;Text Data&amp;#34;). But what if you want to store binary data of a PDF or Excel Spreadsheet that’s also in memory? You could use zipfile.write() (designed to take binary data) but then you can’t specify a filename (since our in-memory file was never written to a location on disk).</description></item><item><title>Programming is hard</title><link>https://www.neilgrogan.com/programming-is-hard/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.neilgrogan.com/programming-is-hard/</guid><description>A great essay on why programming is hard:
It&amp;rsquo;s harder than you think. Right now you&amp;rsquo;re probably underestimating the amount of frustration and discomfort you&amp;rsquo;re about to experience, without realizing that by doing so you&amp;rsquo;re creating all sorts of subtle barriers to obtaining a deep understanding of programming.
Language does matter I find this part extremely true: my first language is Java. Every programming language I&amp;rsquo;ve tried since has been through comparing it to Java.</description></item><item><title>Why Should I Care What Color the Bikeshed Is?</title><link>https://www.neilgrogan.com/why-should-i-care-what-color-bikeshed/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.neilgrogan.com/why-should-i-care-what-color-bikeshed/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;The really, really short answer is that you should not. The somewhat longer answer is that just because you are capable of building a bikeshed does not mean you should stop others from building one just because you do not like the color they plan to paint it. This is a metaphor indicating that you need not argue about every little feature just because you know enough to do so. Some people have commented that the amount of noise generated by a change is inversely proportional to the complexity of the change.</description></item><item><title>Comp Sci - An Interview with Stanford's Undegraduate Professor</title><link>https://www.neilgrogan.com/comp-sci-interview-with-stanfords/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.neilgrogan.com/comp-sci-interview-with-stanfords/</guid><description>This is the guy who runs Stanford University Undergraduate programme. He talks about the future of computer science:
Computer Science will evolve more than most other subjects as it expands into other areas, especially Biology and other areas people don&amp;rsquo;t normally associate with it Industry ties with Colleges are going to be very important Computer Science with Law is the next big area Thanks to Robert Scoble for doing the interview.</description></item></channel></rss>