<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Radio on Neil Grogan</title><link>/tags/radio/</link><description>Recent content in Radio on Neil Grogan</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/radio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>All Music Radio</title><link>/181fm/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/181fm/</guid><description>On holidays in Lithuania recently I was eating in a restaurant and noticed the music was all in English. It&amp;rsquo;s not the first time I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed a non English speaking country playing all English songs in bars, restaurants and taxis. Rather what was unusual was the very few ads and the fact it was an American station.
I&amp;rsquo;m no fan of ads, and am a huge fan of audio in general - be it spoken word or music.</description></item><item><title>The @ACR884 Tech Slot #005</title><link>/the-acr884-tech-slot-005/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/the-acr884-tech-slot-005/</guid><description>Our fifth slot on Athlone Community Radio. Aired the third Monday in March 2012 on ACR 88.4FM in Athlone, Co. Westmeath, Ireland.
Topics Covered: iPad 3 Launch Netflix vs. Lovefilm Online TV: RTE Player, AERtv, 3Player, Filmon In this episode Patrick and Neil discuss the most popular streaming video on the market and the launch of the iPad 3.
Subscribe: Listen now: Your browser does not support the audio tag. Download Link: TechnologySlot19-mar-12</description></item><item><title>The @ACR884 Tech Slot #004</title><link>/acr884-tech-slot-004/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/acr884-tech-slot-004/</guid><description>Our fourth slot on Athlone Community Radio. Aired the third Monday in January 2012 on ACR 88.4FM in Athlone, Co. Westmeath, Ireland.
Topics Covered:
TuneIn Radio App Path App Twitter App Facebook App In this episode Patrick and Neil discuss the most popular apps on the market, across all major platforms. Subscribe: Download Link: 21st Feb 2012 - Tech Slot</description></item><item><title>@ACR884 Tech Slot #003 – eReaders</title><link>/acr884-tech-slot-003/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/acr884-tech-slot-003/</guid><description>Our third slot on Athlone Community Radio. Aired the third Monday in January 2012 on ACR 88.4FM in Athlone, Co. Westmeath, Ireland.
Topics Covered: Kindle Sony eReader In this episode Patrick and Neil discuss the main players in the eBook market, as well as what eBooks are and the advanatages and disadvantages.
Subscribe: Your browser does not support the audio tag. Download Link: TechnologySlot16-01-12</description></item><item><title>@ACR884 Tech Slot #001 - Phones</title><link>/acr884-ep001/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/acr884-ep001/</guid><description>The very first slot on Athlone Community Radio. Aired November 2011 on ACR 88.4FM in Athlone, Co. Westmeath, Ireland.
Topics Covered:
iPhone 4S Samsung Galaxy S Discussion of Windows Phone 7 Hosts: Patrick Russell &amp;amp; Neil Grogan Subscribe: Your browser does not support the audio tag. Download Link: Episode 1 - ACR 88.4 Technology Show</description></item><item><title>@ACR884 Tech Slot #002 - Tablets</title><link>/acr884-tech-slot-002-tablets/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/acr884-tech-slot-002-tablets/</guid><description> iPad Motorola Xoom HP Slate Android tablet apps iOs tablet apps In this episode Patrick and Neil discuss the main players in the tablet market as well as Neils top Android and iOs tablet apps. Subscribe: Your browser does not support the audio tag. Download Link: Technology Slot Dec 19 11</description></item></channel></rss>