<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Business on Neil Grogan</title>
    <link>/tags/business/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Business on Neil Grogan</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/business/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Math can help you outsmart the MTA</title>
      <link>/math-mta/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/math-mta/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I heard a behavioural economist on the radio this morning, he was talking about&#xA;rising house prices in Dublin and the tricks the industry uses to get you to&#xA;overpay. Turns out you can mitigate these tricks with a bit of knowledge, as&#xA;this proves:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But now, with some simple math, you can fight back!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;First, let’s see how the MTA tricks you out of your money earlier than you&#xA;might want to release it to them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Grab the Popcorn!</title>
      <link>/grab-popcorn/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/grab-popcorn/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Fresh from the &amp;ldquo;interesting but pointless facts&amp;rdquo; desk comes this little kernel&#xA;(I apologise!) of truth:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In 2002, the British Film Institute depicted popcorn as &amp;ldquo;the most profitable&#xA;substance on the planet, more than heroin, more than plutonium&amp;rdquo;. Typically,&#xA;the popcorn we eat costs less to produce than the very container it comes&#xA;in. -&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.afoodieworld.com/en/features/all-features/articles/popcorn.html&#34;&gt;Foodie&#xA;World&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Further research indicates that isn&amp;rsquo;t quite true - antimatter is the most&#xA;expensive substance in the world. But for a common, everyday item, it&amp;rsquo;s very&#xA;expensive indeed. There&amp;rsquo;s a lot less risk in production then Heroin and a lot&#xA;bigger market the Plutonium, for instance.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mobile Carrier Charges</title>
      <link>/mobile-carrier-charges/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/mobile-carrier-charges/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is an old box which contained a Nokia phone from a now defunct Esat&#xA;Digifone. Irish Businessman &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Denis_O%27Brien&#34;&gt;Denis O&amp;rsquo;Brien&lt;/a&gt; started it and sold it to BT&#xA;and made a fortune (and after got &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Moriarty_Tribunal#Esat_Digifone&#34;&gt;embroiled in a tribunal on accusations of&#xA;impropriety&lt;/a&gt;). It is now called &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/O2_%28Ireland%29&#34;&gt;O2&lt;/a&gt;.I thought we got ripped&#xA;off now with call charges now, how nostalgia can prove one wrong:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5241/5269146304_9dc92e7f2e.jpg&#34; title=&#34;I thought mobile phone carriers are rip offs now #blastfromthepast&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../files/2011/05/esat.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Esat Digifone Box&#34;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Donating to Charity</title>
      <link>/donating-to-charity/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/donating-to-charity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been meaning to write this blog post for a while, probably since 2006.&#xA;(Almost) everyone that I know of donates to charity on a regular enough basis.&#xA;I&amp;rsquo;m a college student so I don&amp;rsquo;t donate as much as I should. But it really&#xA;annoys me how the &amp;ldquo;main&amp;rdquo; charities run a campaign of guilt and spend&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;millions&lt;/strong&gt; on it. I&amp;rsquo;ve donated money to all of these charities, the third&#xA;world aid charities. All of them spend far too much on paying people commission&#xA;and advertising. One that I can think of off hand is asking people who donated&#xA;more than €250 to sign a form and send it back.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Innovation Right Here - Dept. of Education is Wrong</title>
      <link>/innovation-right-here-dept-of-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/innovation-right-here-dept-of-education/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I usually get both of Ireland&amp;rsquo;s daily national papers to my email inbox every&#xA;morning. I think it&amp;rsquo;s very important to catch up on the latest news; as I think&#xA;you are more informed and have conversation pieces to talk to people (for those&#xA;awkward silences where &amp;ldquo;Ye the weather is terrible&amp;rdquo; just won&amp;rsquo;t do). So I was&#xA;highly informed when I read this piece:&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.independent.ie/education/latest-news/dcu-head-hits-out-at-outofdate-okeeffe-1532789.html?from=dailynews&#34;&gt;DCU head hits out at &amp;lsquo;out-of-date&amp;rsquo; O&amp;rsquo;Keeffe&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;ve decided - I&#39;m decidedly middle class</title>
      <link>/ive-decided-im-decidedly-middle-class/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/ive-decided-im-decidedly-middle-class/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I had a trip in to the faire capital city of Ireland today: Dublin. Okay I&amp;rsquo;ll&#xA;get this out of the way: I had a Frappacino in Starbucks and I&amp;rsquo;m a student; so&#xA;not too poor of a student ;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But I saw the inside of Brown Thomas for the first time. I don&amp;rsquo;t shop for&#xA;fashion at all: but what I found was the kind of vulgarity and fake-ness I&amp;rsquo;d&#xA;expect of London or New York; not Dublin. To paraphrase Bono: &amp;ldquo;In America if you&#xA;have your mansion on a hill people look up to you and think &amp;lsquo;I want to be like&#xA;him and afford a house like that one day&amp;rsquo;; if you have the same mansion in&#xA;Ireland people say &amp;rsquo;look at the fucken eejit on the hill with that house; thinks&#xA;he&amp;rsquo;s god or sumthen&amp;rsquo;&amp;rdquo; and that to me was always an endearing part of Irish&#xA;culture; people around you being the great leveller if you thought you were the&#xA;bomb. Inside BT (Brown Thomas) was all the names you&amp;rsquo;d expect; all the major&#xA;names more at home in Paris, London or New York. I confronted my friend who was&#xA;showing me round about my opinions (in my usual polite manner: just say it). To&#xA;my surprise he agreed 110%. Yes he said: for the people who buy this stuff can&#xA;tell who else is wearing it; and I think he meant that by this logic movers and&#xA;shakers also wore all the brands to look the part. Soon after he told me he was&#xA;also learning Golf because he knew it would be a great benefit for his future&#xA;career: &amp;ldquo;All important people also play golf&amp;rdquo; he assured me.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Will Google Buy Skype?</title>
      <link>/will-google-buy-skype/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/will-google-buy-skype/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been all over the tech news world lately; apparently&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.google.ie/&#34;&gt;Google&lt;/a&gt; is muling over taking Skype off of Ebay&amp;rsquo;s hands.&#xA;Ebay has already written down the value of&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Skype&#34;&gt;Skype&lt;/a&gt; as a large loss on their purchase&#xA;price of $2.6 billion in stock and cash. But&#xA;w&lt;a href=&#34;http://about.skype.com/online.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://about.skype.com/online.png&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;ould&#xA;Skype&amp;rsquo;s G-branded future be any better?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I think it would be. Skype is a strong international brand for voice calls,&#xA;instant messaging and video calls; but of course it competes directly with&#xA;Google Talk. Skype as a company has made a lot of mistakes; but they actually&#xA;produces some of the best technology for p2p VOIP out there in the marketplace.&#xA;Skype is particularly strong in redundancy, cost of network operation (since&#xA;it&amp;rsquo;s p2p every user carries&amp;rsquo; each others traffic; most people have no idea of&#xA;this fact) and routing around the most draconian network admins out their&#xA;through their routers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dell Sells Ubuntu 7.04</title>
      <link>/dell-sells-ubuntu-704/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 May 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/dell-sells-ubuntu-704/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dell Computers has started selling Ubuntu Linux 7.04 on consumer machines in the&#xA;United States. This can only be good news, as a supporter of Linux since late&#xA;2004/early 2005 I am fully behind this initiative to put Linux as a choice in&#xA;front of people who buy computers. They are testing the market at the moment&#xA;which explains why they are shipping stock drivers with the hardware, and no&#xA;multimedia codecs (which is unfortunate, but understandable that this deal was&#xA;done in 60 days). I think this is quite an achievement for Canonical and Mark&#xA;Shuttleworth (Ubuntu Founder), as they get to do the traditional Linux business&#xA;model: you pay for support, and if you don&amp;rsquo;t need it, you don&amp;rsquo;t buy it. This&#xA;could confuse some people in the shorter term, but long term its a winner: Dell&#xA;does what it does best (Hardware) and Software is left to Ubuntu&amp;rsquo;s parent&#xA;company Canonical. This is opposed to Microsoft getting Dell to provide support&#xA;for both hardware and software, sometimes a messy business in which the consumer&#xA;does not know which to turn to and can often be left out in the cold. I hope&#xA;Dell extends this to Europe and 6the rest of the world soon, and makes a decent&#xA;stab at promoting a free software desktop. Dell list advantages in one of their&#xA;videos:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Open Sourcing your CV</title>
      <link>/open-sourcing-your-cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/open-sourcing-your-cv/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just like software. it can be really useful to open source other things in life,&#xA;collaboration is nearly always a good thing. John Buckman, CEO of Magnatune&#xA;Records knows this principle all too well. He gave a speech at a Red Hat&#xA;conference a while back, and he talked about the importance of music artists&#xA;sharing the &amp;ldquo;source&amp;rdquo;, i.e. basically sharing the method of how the produced the&#xA;music in the first place. This allows easier mixing, and a higher chamnce your&#xA;work could be featured on TV or in a film, and you get paid&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BBC to host Multi-OS Debate and My First Web Auction</title>
      <link>/bbc-to-host-multi-os-debate-my-first/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/bbc-to-host-multi-os-debate-my-first/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://img111.imageshack.us/img111/7099/tuxcasefront7rw.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Tux, the Linux&#xA;Penguin&#34; title=&#34;Tux, the Linux Penguin&#34;&gt;BBC&#xA;are putting together a Mac, Windows and Linux user, to&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://news.bbc.co.uk/2/hi/technology/6288119.stm&#34; title=&#34;Mac Linux and Windows Debate&#34;&gt;debate the pros and cons of being a users for each operating system&lt;/a&gt;.&#xA;While this in itself is good news (more airtime for alternatives), most of the&#xA;comments are highly in favour of Linux, then Mac and lastly Windows. This is&#xA;part of the BBC&amp;rsquo;s coverage of Windows Vista. My hope for the future is that Mac&#xA;and Linux gain at least 10% each (20% total) over the next 5 years of the home&#xA;desktop market, as this will push innovation forward, like AMD and Intel&#xA;competition.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Irish Blog Awards</title>
      <link>/irish-blog-awards/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/irish-blog-awards/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well apparently I am a new kid on the block, according to the &lt;a href=&#34;http://awards.ie/blogawards/2006/11/27/new-blogs-on-the-block-november-27th-2006/&#34; title=&#34;Irish Blog Awards&#34;&gt;Irish Blog awards&#xA;blog&lt;/a&gt;). Irish Blog Awards from what I can gather is a new event, hoping to happen&#xA;in March 2007. They have an impressive list of backers, so I expect significant (although&#xA;maybe minor) coverage in the media. Unfortunately they called it Duey Fensters, but&#xA;I thank them for the link nonetheless! These are the categories that will be adjudicated&#xA;on:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mozilla&#39;s Millions</title>
      <link>/mozillas-millions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Mar 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/mozillas-millions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Only now is it truly becoming clear, their is [serious money in Open Source][]/&#xA;With &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mozilla.com/&#34; title=&#34;Mozilla Corp&#34;&gt;Mozilla&lt;/a&gt; reported to have made tens of millions of dollars. One blogger&#xA;reported 70m was made by the corporation, with a Mozilla insider confirming&#xA;thats a reasonable ballpark figure. Christopher Blizzard, board member of&#xA;Mozilla, had this to say on his blog:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Blizzard added that an earnings figure of $72m (£41m) quoted on some blogs was&#xA;incorrect. “I won’t comment on the dollar amount except to say that it’s&#xA;[$72m] not correct, though not off by an order of magnitude. I also won’t&#xA;comment on sources of that money, except to say that some of the assertions&#xA;that I’ve seen in the comments are pretty far off, both in terms of numbers&#xA;and sources,&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Million Dollars, Nice!</title>
      <link>/million-dollars-nice/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/million-dollars-nice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A student in England has almost reached his target of one million dollars, and&#xA;he is only 21! He came up with the idea after jotting down ideas before he went&#xA;to bed on how to become a millionaire before he went to university. Then he came&#xA;up with the million-dollar idea, sell pixels at USD $1 a piece on his homepage,&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.milliondollarhomepage.com&#34;&gt;MillionDollarHomepage.com&lt;/a&gt; . This man is Alex Tew, hailed as an&#xA;advertising genius by the many companies who are using his site to make Internet&#xA;history.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
