<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>internet on Neil Grogan</title><link>/tags/internet/</link><description>Recent content in internet on Neil Grogan</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/internet/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Research proves video games lack harm</title><link>/research-proves-video-games-lack-harm/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/research-proves-video-games-lack-harm/</guid><description>I am not a big gamer; I primarily love systems and how they work. I do own a PS3 (amazing hardware I might add) and I prefer FPS and generally devious natured video games (like the GTA franchise). Does that make me a bad person who wants to kill people? Of course not; nothing could be further from the truth. But some people stick their fingers in their ears and shout &amp;ldquo;LA LA LA Columbine LALALA Terrorists LALALA Violent Video Games!</description></item><item><title>Geek Thug - "I Had to Beat Up a Girl"</title><link>/geek-thug-i-had-to-beat-up-girl/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/geek-thug-i-had-to-beat-up-girl/</guid><description>I just read one of the most informative and insightful blog posts of my entire life. Half serious a guy takes a look back at when he had to beat up a Girl. Weird stuff!
Yes, you read that right, I had to beat up a girl … not a woman. She was asking for it and she deserved it.
I Had to Beat Up a Girl</description></item><item><title>Updates and New look</title><link>/updates-and-new-look/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/updates-and-new-look/</guid><description>Just a note on the new look, hope you like it. I am very fortunate to be running Wordpress, the world&amp;rsquo;s best blogging tool (and it is open source). I looked up the fabulous theme site to go with it, and I came across this one and liked it very much. The last design was my own, but I had awful trouble implementing to look the same in all browsers (especially Internet Explorer, even the latest one, argh).</description></item><item><title>My Plan to Digitise my past, for the future</title><link>/my-plan-to-digitise-my-past-for-future/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/my-plan-to-digitise-my-past-for-future/</guid><description>I am embarking on a journey I believe everyone should: digitise as much photo, video and documents you can. It serves as a record of your existance, a guide to people of what your life was like. Why? is the most obvious question you might ask. Well I will tell you what prompted me, which is the culmination of a lot of different things.
This brings me to the first reason: Television.</description></item><item><title>Home made server...</title><link>/home-made-server/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/home-made-server/</guid><description>I managed after ages of trying hard, to get my NAT transverse to work :-) !! This means the computer sitting in my house should be reachable worldwide at dueyfinster.com. It&amp;rsquo;s login screen is from Ampache music center, a php+mysql solution to a large music catalogue such as mine. It means (for those who can login :-) ) that my whole collection is streamable, downloadable, rateable and generally all round goodness and what you&amp;rsquo;d expect from a top class open source media+web application!</description></item><item><title>IEDR too stringent? Sorry about my email!</title><link>/iedr-too-stringent-sorry-about-my-email/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/iedr-too-stringent-sorry-about-my-email/</guid><description>We all want to stop spam and phishing domains, it hurts the Internet and confidence in it. Their is a lot of debate on this issue, even from the registrars. But I believe, as I know there are probably many out their like me, that the Irish Domain Registry have taken this one step too far. One only has to look to Slashdot to see what the rest of the world thinks about our backwards, censorship-driven domain registry.</description></item><item><title>Wiki, Awards and Wifi</title><link>/wiki-awards-and-wifi/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/wiki-awards-and-wifi/</guid><description>Well the last couple of weeks have been interesting! You will notice the website is now a wiki based on Wikipedias engine, metawiki. I had a load of problems with making the theme work with a wiki with loads of menus. I think I did well considering I only spent about 3 days doing it. The code still aint how I want it and some features were lost, such as rss and del.</description></item></channel></rss>