<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Internet on Neil Grogan</title>
    <link>/tags/internet/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Internet on Neil Grogan</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/internet/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Visit to CERN</title>
      <link>/cern/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/cern/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am currently in Switzerland on a business trip. In between work, I managed to&#xA;get some time over the Swiss national holiday to visit the&#xA;&lt;acronym title=&#34;European Nuclear Research Centre&#34;&gt;CERN&lt;/acronym&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;http://home.web.cern.ch/&#34;&gt;CERN&lt;/a&gt; is&#xA;world famous for the invention of &lt;acronym title=&#34;World Wide Web&#34;&gt;WWW&lt;/acronym&gt;&#xA;and of course most recently, the almost certainty that the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Higgs_boson&#34;&gt;Higgs Boson&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;(&lt;acronym title=&#34;also known as&#34;&gt;aka&lt;/acronym&gt;. &amp;ldquo;The God Particle&amp;rdquo;) - the&#xA;particle that gives energy mass - exists.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The CERN tour is completely free and highly recommended. I visited the &lt;a href=&#34;http://atlas.ch/&#34;&gt;Atlas&#xA;experiment&lt;/a&gt; with a colleague (who just so happened to have a Phd. in&#xA;Physics) and questions were encouraged at every turn. What impressed me the most&#xA;was the fact that there was no stupid questions. You can be a Phd weilding&#xA;Physicist or a child and each question was handled the same by the staff. The&#xA;guide (an active researcher at CERN) even expressed disappointment at the Higgs:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>All About Platforms</title>
      <link>/all-about-platforms/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/all-about-platforms/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If your passion is in technology, you often sigh with the marketing buzzwords&#xA;used in sales. &lt;em&gt;Cloud Computing&lt;/em&gt; doesn&amp;rsquo;t actually mean anything specific&#xA;(or could mean a lot of things). It&amp;rsquo;s that a lot of things to a lot of people&#xA;who makes it useful as a term, an  ideology, a way of explaining why&#xA;&lt;em&gt;you-oh-so-need-to-do-this-now&lt;/em&gt;. Cloud computing for me is a platform&#xA;description. I think of the myriad of hosting companies who offer a platform to&#xA;build your service atop.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Research proves video games lack harm</title>
      <link>/research-proves-video-games-lack-harm/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/research-proves-video-games-lack-harm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/a/a0/Gtalogowhite.svg/200px-Gtalogowhite.svg.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/a/a0/Gtalogowhite.svg/200px-Gtalogowhite.svg.png&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;I&#xA;am not a big gamer; I primarily love systems and how they work. I do own a&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/PlayStation_3&#34;&gt;PS3&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;(&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/PlayStation_3_hardware&#34;&gt;amazing hardware&lt;/a&gt; I might&#xA;add) and I prefer &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/First-person_shooter&#34;&gt;FPS&lt;/a&gt; and&#xA;generally devious natured video games (like the&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Grand_Theft_Auto_(series)&#34;&gt;GTA&lt;/a&gt; franchise). Does&#xA;that make me a bad person who wants to kill people? Of course not; nothing could&#xA;be further from the truth. But some people stick their fingers in their ears and&#xA;shout &amp;ldquo;LA LA LA&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Columbine_High_School_massacre&#34;&gt;Columbine&lt;/a&gt; LALALA&#xA;Terrorists LALALA Violent Video Games!&amp;rdquo;. They say it is destructive to childrens&#xA;young precious minds. The&#xA;&amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/For_The_Children_(politics)&#34;&gt;Think of The Children&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo;&#xA;argument always disgusted me; its like shouting Fire in a packed room when their&#xA;is no danger: it is false, just to garner attention and a sickening twisted&#xA;version of the facts. Are violent video games harmful to kids? &lt;em&gt;Probably&lt;/em&gt;; I&#xA;wouldn&amp;rsquo;t advocate giving them access since they; just like movies are&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pan_European_Game_Information&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;clearly rated for Adults&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. *&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Geek Thug - &#34;I Had to Beat Up a Girl&#34;</title>
      <link>/geek-thug-i-had-to-beat-up-girl/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/geek-thug-i-had-to-beat-up-girl/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I just read one of the most informative and insightful blog posts of my entire&#xA;life. Half serious a guy takes a look back at when he had to beat up a Girl.&#xA;Weird stuff!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yes, you read that right, I had to beat up a girl … not a woman. She was&#xA;asking for it and she deserved it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.geekthug.com/?p=18445&#34;&gt;I Had to Beat Up a Girl&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nokia N810 Tablet to hit the shops soon...</title>
      <link>/tablet-to-hit-shops-soon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Oct 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/tablet-to-hit-shops-soon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nokia have announced an upgrade to the N800 Internet tablet, called the N810. I&#xA;suspect its called that because it is more of an incremental upgrade than a&#xA;total visual refresh it was going from an Nokia 770 to N800. Here it is:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;../../img/07/n810gps.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../img/07/n810gps.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(Picture Courtesy:&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.internettablettalk.com/2007/10/17/the-nokia-n810-internet-tablet/&#34;&gt;Internet Tablet Talk&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It sports a nice new hardware keyboard; inbuilt GPS (For satellite mapping) and&#xA;OS 2008 (an upgrade to the operating system it runs). The N800 will also benefit&#xA;from OS 2008, which will include GoogleTalk, Skype, Mozilla browser, among the&#xA;usual such as its email client, media player, file manager, control panel,&#xA;assorted games and an image/PDF viewer. The one feature it will emit is an&#xA;inbuilt FM Radio, which was axed to make the N810 a smaller tablet. It still&#xA;retains the best screen size for web browsing, bluetooth connectivity, and of&#xA;course Wifi which is central to the tablets existance! No word on what easter&#xA;eggs are included if any; on the N800 it was a radio and the N770 it was the&#xA;microphone.&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.engadget.com/2007/10/17/nokia-n810-hands-on/&#34;&gt;Engadget has a great writeup on it&lt;/a&gt;,&#xA;choc-a-bloc full of high resolution photos with size comparisons to Apples&#xA;iPhone.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft settles with Eolas over Internet Explorer</title>
      <link>/microsoft-settles-with-eolas-over/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/microsoft-settles-with-eolas-over/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cbi.cnptia.embrapa.br/xmeeting/include/img/microsoft-logo.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.cbi.cnptia.embrapa.br/xmeeting/include/img/microsoft-logo.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.siliconrepublic.com/news/news.nv?storyid=single9119&#34;&gt;Microsoft has settled with Eolas&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;over a number of patents regarding browser plugins which chicago based Eolas&#xA;filed patents for in 1998. A jury in Chicago then found Microsoft guilty of&#xA;infringing on Eolas’ patents and was told to pay $521m US Dollars in &amp;lsquo;damages&amp;rsquo;.&#xA;That ruling was overturned and a fresh trial ordered which was due to start very&#xA;soon, but it seems Microsoft has decided to pay out:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Updates and New look</title>
      <link>/updates-and-new-look/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/updates-and-new-look/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://img164.imageshack.us/img164/9038/wordpresslogoxv7.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Wordpress&#xA;Logo&#34; title=&#34;Wordpress Logo&#34;&gt;Just&#xA;a note on the new look, hope you like it. I am very fortunate to be running&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://wordpress.org/&#34; title=&#34;Wordpress Blogging Software&#34;&gt;Wordpress&lt;/a&gt;, the world&amp;rsquo;s&#xA;best blogging tool (and it is open source). I looked up the fabulous theme site&#xA;to go with it, and I came across this one and liked it very much. The last&#xA;design was my own, but I had awful trouble implementing to look the same in all&#xA;browsers (especially Internet Explorer, even the latest one, argh). I know the&#xA;old one can be improved, so I am submitting to&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://themes.wordpress.net/&#34; title=&#34;Wordpress Themes&#34;&gt;WP Themes directory&lt;/a&gt;, which I&#xA;will update this post with the link. I love the new theme, it brings what I&#xA;couldn&amp;rsquo;t to the old one: choosable colours and sameness across browsers. I&amp;rsquo;d&#xA;like to thank Justin Winslow for that! Did I mention that the exact same colours&#xA;are used in this theme? It brings a total different look though, the power of&#xA;perception! So now you know these are the official DF&amp;rsquo;s colours!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Plan to Digitise my past, for the future</title>
      <link>/my-plan-to-digitise-my-past-for-future/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/my-plan-to-digitise-my-past-for-future/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am embarking on a journey I believe everyone should: digitise as much photo,&#xA;video and documents you can. It serves as a record of your existance, a guide to&#xA;people of what your life was like. Why? is the most obvious question you might&#xA;ask. Well I will tell you what prompted me, which is the culmination of a lot of&#xA;different things.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This brings me to the first reason: Television. I find shows fascinating where&#xA;people discover their ancestors were orphans, incredibly wealthy or died from&#xA;exhaustion in a mine. It really makes you think what makes you the person you&#xA;are, so to speak. David Attenborough says (although I have paraphrased) that if&#xA;people look back at his 100-150 hours of television, they will get a snapshot of&#xA;what the glaciers, mountains, desert and animals were like in the latter half of&#xA;the twentieth century, not a complete picture, but one nonetheless of what Earth&#xA;was like at that time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BBC to host Multi-OS Debate and My First Web Auction</title>
      <link>/bbc-to-host-multi-os-debate-my-first/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/bbc-to-host-multi-os-debate-my-first/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://img111.imageshack.us/img111/7099/tuxcasefront7rw.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Tux, the Linux&#xA;Penguin&#34; title=&#34;Tux, the Linux Penguin&#34;&gt;BBC&#xA;are putting together a Mac, Windows and Linux user, to&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://news.bbc.co.uk/2/hi/technology/6288119.stm&#34; title=&#34;Mac Linux and Windows Debate&#34;&gt;debate the pros and cons of being a users for each operating system&lt;/a&gt;.&#xA;While this in itself is good news (more airtime for alternatives), most of the&#xA;comments are highly in favour of Linux, then Mac and lastly Windows. This is&#xA;part of the BBC&amp;rsquo;s coverage of Windows Vista. My hope for the future is that Mac&#xA;and Linux gain at least 10% each (20% total) over the next 5 years of the home&#xA;desktop market, as this will push innovation forward, like AMD and Intel&#xA;competition.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Free Domain name off AOL, too good to be true?</title>
      <link>/free-domain-name-off-aol-too-good-to-be/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/free-domain-name-off-aol-too-good-to-be/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.aol.com/&#34; title=&#34;AOL&#34;&gt;AOL&lt;/a&gt;, the longtime dialup king, who esperate to keep customers at its&amp;rsquo; site&#xA;who have switched to broadband, is &lt;a href=&#34;https://domains.aol.com/personaldomain/app/domainHomeSearch&#34; title=&#34;AOL Free Domains&#34;&gt;offering free dot com and dot net&#xA;domains&lt;/a&gt;. There are a few caches however, one must be in possession of a US mobile&#xA;phone (cell) number. Luckily I have a cousin stateside willing to help out ;-) .&#xA;I got to register NeilGrogan.com (My actual name) which I hadn&amp;rsquo;t bothered with before.&#xA;AOL is the legal owner however, so has all the say legally to the name. At the minute&#xA;it provides 100 2GB email accounts with the free domain, and if you visit the address&#xA;online, it redirects to an AIM Pages profile of the owner (for all intents and purposes,&#xA;it&amp;rsquo;s another social networking site). Its a good way to drum up interest in its online&#xA;offerings, but they should be more flexible. If anyone is in any doubt, this is just&#xA;an &amp;lsquo;alright&amp;rsquo; kind of deal, AOL say they will give you the option to buy the name&#xA;back in the future, but I won&amp;rsquo;t hold my breath.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Home made server...</title>
      <link>/home-made-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/home-made-server/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I managed after ages of trying hard, to get my NAT transverse to work :-) !!&#xA;This means the computer sitting in my house should be reachable worldwide at&#xA;dueyfinster.com. It&amp;rsquo;s login screen is from Ampache music center, a php+mysql&#xA;solution to a large music catalogue such as mine. It means (for those who can&#xA;login :-) ) that my whole collection is streamable, downloadable, rateable and&#xA;generally all round goodness and what you&amp;rsquo;d expect from a top class open source&#xA;media+web application! I am excited about this, as I have already tried it from&#xA;a remote family members house. Unfortunately it does not work too well half way&#xA;across the world in the US (speed is *really* slow I have been gleefully&#xA;informed), but I am not too bothered, upgrades in speed will come with better&#xA;broadband (which may be years, this is Ireland). I am trying to restrict peoples&#xA;usage of it at the moment, as I really do not want a letter from my Internet&#xA;Service Provider!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IEDR too stringent? Sorry about my email!</title>
      <link>/iedr-too-stringent-sorry-about-my-email/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/iedr-too-stringent-sorry-about-my-email/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We all want to stop spam and phishing domains, it hurts the Internet and&#xA;confidence in it. Their is a lot of debate on this issue, even from the&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bobparsons.com/EULandrushFiasco.html&#34; title=&#34;Bob Parsons Blog&#34;&gt;registrars&lt;/a&gt;. But I believe, as I know there are probably many out their like&#xA;me, that the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.iedr.ie/&#34; title=&#34;Dot IE Domain Registry&#34;&gt;Irish Domain Registry&lt;/a&gt; have taken this one step too far. One&#xA;only has to look to &lt;a href=&#34;http://yro.slashdot.org/article.pl?sid=06/10/14/2142204&#34; title=&#34;Adult .IE Domain Names Banned As Immoral&#34;&gt;Slashdot&lt;/a&gt; to see what the rest of the world thinks about&#xA;our backwards, censorship-driven domain registry. My favourite rule they have&#xA;about domains is perhaps the one which requires the least amount of bureaucracy:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wiki, Awards and Wifi</title>
      <link>/wiki-awards-and-wifi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/wiki-awards-and-wifi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well the last couple of weeks have been interesting! You will notice the website&#xA;is now a wiki based on Wikipedias engine, metawiki. I had a load of problems&#xA;with making the theme work with a wiki with loads of menus. I think I did well&#xA;considering I only spent about 3 days doing it. The code still aint how I want&#xA;it and some features were lost, such as rss and del.icio.us bookmarks. But pages&#xA;are now easier than ever to navigate and comment on which brings more features.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
