<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Project on Neil Grogan</title>
    <link>/tags/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Project on Neil Grogan</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>CSThesis: Create Professional looking thesis</title>
      <link>/csthesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/csthesis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As part of my undergradute thesis, I found a template (for LyX) to ease the pain&#xA;of formatting a thesis in LaTeX. Making it look just right to me was very&#xA;important. If your are writing a thesis, perhaps you feel the same way? If so,&#xA;read on&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While doing my first undergraduate thesis in Computer Science, I found a&#xA;template used for a Computer Science thesis in NUI Maynooth (a university in&#xA;Ireland). What attracted me was simple: it was battle tested and easily&#xA;customisable. That was 2011 and since then I&amp;rsquo;d pretty much forgotten about it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GeoCampus</title>
      <link>/geocampus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/geocampus/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For my final year project, I have done a web application on the concept of&#xA;replacing traditional web applications. I picked an area I was deeply interested&#xA;in, smart phones. I am an avid iPhone user and I have bought Android phones&#xA;also, they are great devices I can&amp;rsquo;t imagine not having now that they are here.&#xA;As part of my thesis I touched on the old way to develop apps, using Symbian C++&#xA;or J2ME and we&amp;rsquo;ve come a long, long way since then.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;For those&#xA;interested, I will publish copy of my thesis after November 2011. I won&amp;rsquo;t&#xA;publish it here just yet, as the examiners have yet to pour over the contents&#xA;and grade it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Web Multimedia Project 1</title>
      <link>/web-multimedia-project-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/web-multimedia-project-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As part of Computer Science you do a couple of general modules which are general&#xA;in nature about computing; but I think that just reflects the broad use of IT in&#xA;every part of society today. As things go digital or are created digitally;&#xA;understanding of this concept is vital; that is where Web Multimedia comes in.&#xA;For my first project of this second year; I had to do a movie made of stills&#xA;with custom sound effects. Restrictions on sources of images and sounds (very&#xA;high percentage had to be self made). Here it is:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ultimate Games Disc</title>
      <link>/ultimate-games-disc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/ultimate-games-disc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I got inspiration over this past Easter holidays, being bored, I gave Linux&#xA;Gaming a shot. I am not much of a gamer myself and most websites aren&amp;rsquo;t very&#xA;helpful or have too small a focus (only shoot-em-ups, or only certain Linux&#xA;distros etc.). Inspired by the fine folks at OpenSourceMac.org and&#xA;OpenSourceWindows.org, I announce my own project: Ultimate Games Disc. UGD is a&#xA;project I think I can make very successful. My aims are as follows:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
