<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Homenet on Neil Grogan</title><link>/tags/homenet/</link><description>Recent content in Homenet on Neil Grogan</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/homenet/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Ubiquiti Unifi with Sonos on a separate VLAN</title><link>/ubnt-sonos/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/ubnt-sonos/</guid><description>Update 2023: these instructions are out-of-date for the latest Unifi controller software versions. It&amp;#39;s preserved here as written for those who still have older versions. This post uses a file called gateway.config.json and Unifi now say:
This article is not applicable to the UniFi Dream Machine models, because all configurations are already available in the UniFi Network user interface.
So I take that to mean use of this file is deprecated and it should be possible to do this via the administration webpage.</description></item><item><title>Ubuntu 20.04 Vagrant with Packer</title><link>/vagrant-ubuntu-fossa/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/vagrant-ubuntu-fossa/</guid><description>Ubuntu have recently released the new 20.04 LTS codenamed &amp;ldquo;Focal Fossa&amp;rdquo;. I&amp;rsquo;d also recently seen a tool that piqued my interest, Hashicorp Packer. Packer builds machine images that can be deployed to a cloud or as a virtual machine, or just even a plain disk image. You can even generate many images at once, really simplfying deployment. Very handy if you wanted to create virtual machines for a cluster for example, with a similar but slightly different configuration.</description></item><item><title>Ubiquiti Home Network</title><link>/ubnt/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/ubnt/</guid><description>Over the summer, I upgraded my home network to Ubiquiti gear. Ubiquiti do business Wifi, all the way up to covering stadiums. I first heard about them from Troy Hunt and then again from Marco Arment on Accidental Tech Podcast. Ubiquiti are popular in prosumer space - for people serious about good Wifi.
So far it&amp;rsquo;s been an excellent experience and I&amp;rsquo;d highly recommend it. After setting it up (there is a few moving pieces) it has been running without any intervention from me.</description></item></channel></rss>