<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Apple on Neil Grogan</title>
    <link>/tags/apple/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Apple on Neil Grogan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/apple/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>iPad Pro Review</title>
      <link>/ipadpro/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/ipadpro/</guid>
      <description>After some thought initially on a new laptop, I decided to spring for an iPad Pro 12.9&amp;quot;. So far I am really glad I did, the computer comes with me everywhere. I bring it to work, to visit family, on trips and everywhere in between.&#xA;It&amp;rsquo;s the ultimate work computer in many ways, always with you, light enough and comfortable enough for real work™. The keyboard shortcuts in iOS have improved massively from iOS 8 to iOS 9 to the point of actually being useful and the split screen view is actually rather nice to use (I never &amp;ldquo;got&amp;rdquo; it on a Mac).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Services I pay for</title>
      <link>/services/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/services/</guid>
      <description>In alphabetical order:&#xA;Amazon.com / Amazon.co.uk - usually buy electronics here! Apple&amp;rsquo;s App Store - I use iOS &amp;amp; Mac heavily, buy a lot of apps! Dropbox - sync files across computers Evernote - I store a lot of notes here. Fastmail - My email, contacts, calendars Hover - great place for domain names (like this one). Lastpass - excellent password manager Newsblur - Personalized RSS for news junkies Pinboard - stores all my bookmarks (also archives the sites) Trello - I&amp;rsquo;m planning a holiday via Trello Some of these are referral links, I stand to get extra credit on these services if you use it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Apple Watch Stand</title>
      <link>/watch-stand/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/watch-stand/</guid>
      <description>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-e1DiEegB_c&#xA;h/t; reddit&#xA;update: I tried this myself, but I&amp;rsquo;ve obviously no talent for these things:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mac Mini Server</title>
      <link>/macmini/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/macmini/</guid>
      <description>I recently purchased a Mac Mini Server, for this site to run on. It&amp;rsquo;s hosted on my home broadband connection, but it&amp;rsquo;s just really for small time side-projects like this site. Also it&amp;rsquo;s a way to play around with Docker, VirtualBox, Node.js and all those other fun technologies I don&amp;rsquo;t get time for.&#xA;I don&amp;rsquo;t really plan to post links, but maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll review things or cover things I&amp;rsquo;ve bought.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>iPhone 6 and Apple Watch</title>
      <link>/apple-annouces-iphone6-watch/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/apple-annouces-iphone6-watch/</guid>
      <description>Interesting announcements yesterday by Apple, finally releasing an iWatch. A lot of the talk on tech sites was reminiscent of the famous CMDR Taco (of Slashdot) line: &amp;ldquo;Less space then a nomad. Lame.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;I happened to own a Nomad shortly after that famous quote was made. So we can see, quoting Steve Jobs &amp;ldquo;[They] have no taste&amp;rdquo; is applicable to me! I just don&amp;rsquo;t get the watch yet. As a permanent contact wearer, I&amp;rsquo;m waiting for Google Glass in a contact lens!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s in your dock?</title>
      <link>/whats-in-your-dock/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/whats-in-your-dock/</guid>
      <description>I recently read an article that posed the question &amp;ldquo;Does your dock reflect your priorities?&amp;rdquo; - which is an interesting question. Further breaking that idea down leads to:&#xA;What apps do I need the most? What apps should be next (or be higher priority)? iPhone dock Phone app: pretty self explanatory Safari: Still the best mobile browser I think (though if Google ever gets going on a proper Chrome browser for Android that may change) Tweetbot: I like Twitter the most of the social networks and tweetbot is the Swiss army knife if twitter clients Music (aka.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Are Android Smartphones Bigger Than the iPhone?</title>
      <link>/why-are-android-smartphones-bigger-than-the-iphone/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/why-are-android-smartphones-bigger-than-the-iphone/</guid>
      <description>tl;dr It&amp;rsquo;s because LTE chipsets are very large and power hungry right now.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>@ACR884 Tech Slot #001 - Phones</title>
      <link>/acr884-ep001/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/acr884-ep001/</guid>
      <description>The very first slot on Athlone Community Radio. Aired November 2011 on ACR 88.4FM in Athlone, Co. Westmeath, Ireland.&#xA;Topics Covered:&#xA;iPhone 4S Samsung Galaxy S Discussion of Windows Phone 7 Hosts: Patrick Russell &amp;amp; Neil Grogan Subscribe: Your browser does not support the audio tag. Download Link: Episode 1 - ACR 88.4 Technology Show</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>@ACR884 Tech Slot #002 - Tablets</title>
      <link>/acr884-tech-slot-002-tablets/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/acr884-tech-slot-002-tablets/</guid>
      <description> iPad Motorola Xoom HP Slate Android tablet apps iOs tablet apps In this episode Patrick and Neil discuss the main players in the tablet market as well as Neils top Android and iOs tablet apps. Subscribe: Your browser does not support the audio tag. Download Link: Technology Slot Dec 19 11 </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>iPhone 4 Review</title>
      <link>/iphone4-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/iphone4-review/</guid>
      <description>I purchased the iPhone 4 shortly after its release in Summer 2010. I have obviously been so quick to review this device, the iPhone 5 is upon us! My philosophy for reviewing items is you have to live with them. Well boy have I lived with my iPhone 4! As I write this on it, I do marvel at how good the hardware is. I&amp;rsquo;ve dropped this extremely expensive device on occasions too numerous to count, so luckily it is designed well.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>iPad Evolution?</title>
      <link>/ipad-evolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/ipad-evolution/</guid>
      <description>Since Apple released an iPad there have been various competitors announced, so it got me thinking what would it take for me to buy one? I haven&amp;rsquo;t bought the first generation iPad because the lack of a camera on a device so obviously good for fullscreen video calls has baffled me. I guess they have to store up some ideas since they need a new hardware iteration every year, Apple&amp;rsquo;s revenue model depends on that vital hardware refresh cycle.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Haiku: Open Source BeOS clone</title>
      <link>/haiku-open-source-beos-clone/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/haiku-open-source-beos-clone/</guid>
      <description>I usually listen to podcasts on the excellent Twit.tv network and it goes without saying Floss Weekly is one of my favourites. A recent episode covered Haiku - an open source operating system based on the design of the old BeOS. What&amp;rsquo;s very interesting about BeOS is the design, an integrated all in one operating system - and the fact Apple almost purchased it. That&amp;rsquo;s amazing to me, literally in one fell swoop, if Apple had of offered the 200 million Be Systems wanted, there would be no NextStep into Apple and by extension - Steve Jobs.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is a Mac Pro overpriced?</title>
      <link>/is-mac-pro-overpriced/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/is-mac-pro-overpriced/</guid>
      <description>Gizmodo seem to think so:&#xA;The $2,500 Mac Pro, desperately in need of a refresh, gives you a 2.66GHz Quad-Core Xeon (essentially an i7), 3GB of RAM (triple channel, but seriously?), 640GB hard drive (again, seriously?) and a nominal graphics card. Spend $800 more and you&amp;rsquo;ll get a another processor and 3GB more RAM.&#xA;The $2200, 27-inch iMac obviously includes a screen, plus you get a 2.8GHz Quad-Core (i7), 1TB drive, 4GB of RAM and a nominal graphics card.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3G Coverage in Ireland</title>
      <link>/3g-coverage-in-ireland/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/3g-coverage-in-ireland/</guid>
      <description>I recently used Twitter to post about my journey on public transport from Kilkenny to Dublin. For people outside of Ireland the total Journey distance was about 90 miles.&#xA;I used only my iPhone on the O2 network and close to 50% of the time it seemed like I had 3G. This was on a train moving at speed, and YouTube played very well with little to no stutter. It did drop to Edge the other half of the time, with about 30% of time I still got speeds web browsing was acceptable on.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>iPhone 3G Review</title>
      <link>/iphone-3g-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/iphone-3g-review/</guid>
      <description>I recently got an iPhone 3G and away from all that Apple mania; I thought I would give an honest review. This is framed in the mindset of all the past Nokia devices (which I have posted about here also) which I have owned.&#xA;Okay so where to start? Well I think a good place would be what I could have bought instead. Strange place for a review; but its good to see what is out there and what I was looking at beforehand.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Apple Mac OS X: the most popular Desktop Unix?</title>
      <link>/apple-mac-os-x-most-popular-desktop/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Oct 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/apple-mac-os-x-most-popular-desktop/</guid>
      <description>Apple does it again: explosive growth in the computer market, no doubt in part to its Macbook/Macbook Pro line of laptops. As Ars Technica points out:&#xA;As predicted last quarter, however, Apple broke its tie for third place with Gateway by shipping 1.33 million units and growing by a whopping 37.2 percent (double that of any other US vendor) from third quarter 2006 to claim 8.1 percent of the US market for the quarter.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Apple - Play Nice....</title>
      <link>/apple-play-nice/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Sep 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/apple-play-nice/</guid>
      <description>Is the much beloved Apple the new Microsoft? First there was IBM, the big all crushing corporate machine that was humbled by the next big giant in the form of Microsoft, so it seems Apple&amp;rsquo;s turn is long overdue. The next few weeks are crucial to this crossroads in which Apple finds itself: It owes a HUGE amount to the BSD (an open source Unix clone) which is the foundation for not just OS X, but the iPhone and now the iPod Touch.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leopard - Worth the wait?</title>
      <link>/leopard-worth-wait/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jun 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/leopard-worth-wait/</guid>
      <description>If you haven&amp;rsquo;t heard of Apple&amp;rsquo;s latest Operating system, have a look at Wikipedia Article on Mac OS X Leopard. Here are some of the features:&#xA;Time Machine: an automated backup utility which allows the user to restore files that have been deleted or replaced by another version of a file. Front Row currently only available with the purchase of a new Mac, but will be included with Leopard. It has been reworked to closely resemble the interface used by the Apple TV.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Apple / EMI Deal - Thank the EU?</title>
      <link>/apple-emi-deal-thank-eu/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/apple-emi-deal-thank-eu/</guid>
      <description>I heard the news one hour before it was announced: Apple and EMI are going Digital Rights Management (DRM) free, albeit at a slightly higher cost and quality. One of my pet hates is people who bash the European Union, often citing I will admit its not glowing charachteristics. These same people never admit the things Europe does right, which may well be this hopefully landslide affect against destroying DRM. To quote The Register:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mac iPod Video Tutorial</title>
      <link>/mac-ipod-video-tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/mac-ipod-video-tutorial/</guid>
      <description>I recorded a tutorial, showing people how to extract YouTube (and other flash based sites videos&amp;rsquo;) and get them onto your iPod. It was recorded on my Mac, so unfortunately its Mac specific, but really only iSquint program is, so if anyone can suggest a replacement on Windows or Linux, I will add it to the details of the video. I use Garageband for audio, iMovieHD to edit the video and audio and Copernicus to record my screen.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Widget for our RSS feed!</title>
      <link>/new-widget-for-our-rss-feed/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/new-widget-for-our-rss-feed/</guid>
      <description>Thanks to Dashcode, the tool for making dashboard widgets, there is now an RSS one for this site! Currently it only works on Mac OS X, but KDE 4 should support dashboard widgets (they are really just bits of javascript, css and html).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Video iPod and Freespire</title>
      <link>/video-ipod-and-freespire/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/video-ipod-and-freespire/</guid>
      <description>Well I guess you can call me a hardcore Apple Computer fan, I have a Macbook, an iPod Nano (1st Gen 4GB) and now a 80GB iPod Video! I bought i for a couple of reasons, namely price and storage. I had been put off before since I thought they were too bulky ( I know a couple of people who have older generation iPod Videos) after being with the Nano for over a year (its still chugging along gleefully).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wiki goes live, downtime and Macbook Back!</title>
      <link>/wiki-goes-live-downtime-and-macbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/wiki-goes-live-downtime-and-macbook/</guid>
      <description>I have a Wiki for messing about! I haven&amp;rsquo;t found a purpose for it yet, but I&amp;rsquo;d like to have it all set up incase one day I turn out to need it (maybe for collaboration or something?). If you have any skill at themin&amp;rsquo; MediaWiki (the most popular wiki software, run but Wikipedia, no less) please, please get in touch! I would do it all myself, but my time is constrained at the moment, but I will eventually do it myself I suppose ;-)</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Broken Macbook Update Part II</title>
      <link>/broken-macbook-update-part-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/broken-macbook-update-part-ii/</guid>
      <description>Looks like Mactivate got it wrong, it wasn&amp;rsquo;t the heatsink, as referred to by my earlier post. Looks like I have seen good advice from the Web, never buy a first generation Apple product, until they work out the kinks! I guess Mactivate have been snowed under with heatsink problems, that they never bothered to check other parts of my Macbook, since it is such a common problem.They have ordered me a new &amp;ldquo;logic board&amp;rdquo; (I am guessing the PMU like I thought it was ;-) ).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Macbook Issue Identified</title>
      <link>/macbook-issue-identified/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/macbook-issue-identified/</guid>
      <description>Turns out my prediction wasn&amp;rsquo;t quite correct, it was not the Power Management Unit (PMU), it was the heatsink. Mactivate have informed me they have one on order from Apple, so it will take a bit longer than I anticipated to get my Macbook back. I found this strange as I had not experienced random shutdowns like the ones that have been widely reported across the web. it was like I described in my earlier post, something to do with the battery not being able to charge.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blog Updates, Calendar Updates, broken Macbook</title>
      <link>/blog-updates-calendar-updates-broken/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog-updates-calendar-updates-broken/</guid>
      <description>Well first of all, there has been some blog updates, inspired no less by my Grandfather! He&amp;rsquo;s at a fragile old age, so he can&amp;rsquo;t read the screen all too well. This is not a problem however, as he sets all fonts to 16 and higher in Firefox (which is out of beta and into version 2.0!). That got me thinking, as I really struggled to read this page being marginally away from the screen, as I am a [Keratoconus][] sufferer.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Macbook Update, Fonero Haven, Commercial Darknet and College!</title>
      <link>/macbook-update-fonero-haven-commercial/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/macbook-update-fonero-haven-commercial/</guid>
      <description>I have ordered and I am expecting delivery of my brand new Apple MacBook (or BlackBook as some call it)! It will be a Black, 2Ghz Core Duo, 1 GB RAM, 120 GB HDD (5400 RPM) MacBook, complete with a remote, Bluetooth 2 and Wifi functionality. Not mention cool applications such as iSight built in Camera, Front Row ( a media center) and Spotlight search technology. It cost me close to €2.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why I am getting an Apple MacBook</title>
      <link>/feel-i-need-to-confess-why-i-am-buying/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/feel-i-need-to-confess-why-i-am-buying/</guid>
      <description>I feel I need to confess why I am buying a MacBook, have I turned soft to my Open Source/Free Software ways? No, definately 100% NOT. I’ll explain why: I think Apple Computer has an incredible product in Mac OSx. For anyone who has not used it before, pop into a 3G store and ask to have a go. When someone releases a good a product as that, they deserve money, in my opinion.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ekiga&#39;s Vorbis</title>
      <link>/ekigas-vorbis/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/ekigas-vorbis/</guid>
      <description>I am all for open standards, but they face huge problems. Not least is lack of intergration between them. Take SIP used by VOIP providers, such as OpenWengo. While OpenWengo is open source, and it is SIP, they are not helpful in informing you how to use other clients, or dial other OpenWengo users from other networks.&#xA;What I am really talking about is the need for an all-in-one communications program, that is multi-platform.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
